<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Castle Clinton">

<photo  date_taken="2012-03-19 17:27:53" description="Best in large - geotagged - Image copyright" id="6973075246" latitude="40.703436" license="1" longitude="-74.016866" nbComments="126" rank="1" tags="newyork unitedstates batterypark castleclinton animal squirrel wild fun zoom color contyrast composition travel visit info information geotag geotagged eyes portrait light" title="New York wild squirrel begging - Castle Clinton in Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7124/6973075246_fb641a9d70_b.jpg" username="JanvanSchijndel" views="426" />
<photo  date_taken="1998-07-01 00:00:00" description="Manning &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt;'s 28 guns Order of September 18, 1814 -- &amp;quot;The force employed will be 2 gunners and 8 matrosses (artillerists) to each gun. To every section of chamber of 2 guns a non commissioned officer.&amp;quot;" id="163317657" latitude="40.703476" license="3" longitude="-74.016775" nbComments="0" rank="2" tags="nyc newyorkcity downtown fort harbor southwestbattery batterypark castleclinton cannon nationalmonument nps manhattan gothamist castle newyorkcitylandmarkspreservationcommission nyclpc landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument - Cannon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/49/163317657_3937276d3c_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1018" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:51:06" description="June 6, 2006 marked the opening of The Battery Conservancy’s first educational program displayed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton National Monument&lt;/a&gt;, Walls within Walls; an exhibit presenting the findings of the mid-18th century wall discovered in the Battery during excavation for the South Ferry Subway Tunnel. The exhibition, temporarily on display in the Castle, includes explanatory panels presenting the history of the wall, the archeological discovery, and an explanation of its modern significance. Accompanying the display is a reconstruction of a part of the first section of the wall to be excavated. Four sections of the colonial era wall were identified by archaeologists, with each of the four sections exhibiting unique features. They are all likely part of the same wall, constructed between 1730 and 1766. Differences among the sections may be due to successive periods of construction, which would account for the various building materials and construction techniques used. The wall was accompanied by a wooden log pier structure. It was documented in detailed drawings, and samples of the wood were taken for dating. Because of the archaeological analysis, the wall was determined eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places. Ongoing study of this important discovery will provide a more detailed history of the Battery than has ever been possible before." id="331723609" latitude="40.703476" license="3" longitude="-74.016775" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown castleclinton wallswithinwalls wall excavation colonial batterypark castleclintonnationalmonument fort southwestbattery nationalmonument nps castle newyorkcitylandmarkspreservationcommission nyclpc landmark ny newyork nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton -  Walls within Walls" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/150/331723609_72b62e6fca_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1063" />
<photo  date_taken="1998-07-01 00:00:00" description="Castle Clinton, along with more than a dozen other forts was built in anticipation of the War of 1812 to defend New York Harbor. The Southwest Battery was constructed on the rocks off the tip of Manhattan Island between 1808 and 1811. Although fully armed, the fort never had occasion to fire upon an enemy. In 1817, the fort was renamed Castle Clinton in honor of DeWitt Clinton, Mayor and later Governor of New York. The army vacated the fort in 1821 and the structure was deeded to New York City. In the summer of 1824, a new restaurant and entertainment center opened at the site, then called Castle Garden. A roof was added in the 1840s and Castle Garden served as an opera house and theater until 1854. Many new inventions were demonstrated there to amazed audiences including the telegraph, Colts revolving rifles, steam powdered fire engines and underwater electronic explosives. The &amp;quot;Swedish Nightengale&amp;quot; Jenny Lind made her American debut here in 1850, brought to America by no other then P.T. Barnum. By 1855, successive landfills had enlarged the Park to encompass Castle Garden and on August 3 the structure became America's first immigrant receiving center, welcoming 8.5 million people before it was closed in 1890 and succeeded by Ellis Island. The building was altered once again and reopened as the New York City Aquarium on December 10, 1896. It was one of the city's most popular attractions, and one of America's first public aquariums until it closed in 1941. Following its near-total demolition in 1941 and a major preservation battle, the original fort walls were declared a National Monument by an Act of Congress in 1946. Restored to its fortification appearance by the National Park Service in 1975, the Castle currently houses a small interpretive display and the ticket office for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island ferry. Castle Clinton was designated a landmarks by the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission in 1965. National Register #66000537" id="163317527" latitude="40.703476" license="3" longitude="-74.016775" nbComments="3" rank="4" tags="nyc newyorkcity aerial downtown fort harbor southwestbattery batterypark castleclinton nationalmonument nps manhattan neoclassical neoclassicalarchitecture americanrenaissance neoclassicism gothamist castle nyclpc johnmccomb johnmccombjr landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/57/163317527_16d7ad494e_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="4352" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-07 19:37:26" description="Terrence Blanchard at Castle Clinton" id="4008470632" latitude="40.703444" license="1" longitude="-74.016673" nbComments="2" rank="5" tags="terrenceblanchard nyc 2008 castleclinton trumpet saxophone" title="IMG_0646" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3062/4008470632_7325c1daa6_b.jpg" username="emkladil" views="36" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-11 15:46:12" description="Puesto de venta de figuritas en Battery Park, junto al Castle Clinton, NYC." id="3269588509" latitude="40.703834" license="1" longitude="-74.016598" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="metal models nyc newyork nuevayork castleclinton batterypark figuras" title="Figuritas metálicas" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1311/3269588509_fa81e1a555_b.jpg" username="multisanti" views="170" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:52:33" description="Castle Clinton, along with more than a dozen other forts was built in anticipation of the War of 1812 to defend New York Harbor. The Southwest Battery was constructed on the rocks off the tip of Manhattan Island between 1808 and 1811. Although fully armed, the fort never had occasion to fire upon an enemy. In 1817, the fort was renamed Castle Clinton in honor of DeWitt Clinton, Mayor and later Governor of New York. The army vacated the fort in 1821 and the structure was deeded to New York City. In the summer of 1824, a new restaurant and entertainment center opened at the site, then called Castle Garden. A roof was added in the 1840s and Castle Garden served as an opera house and theater until 1854. Many new inventions were demonstrated there to amazed audiences including the telegraph, Colts revolving rifles, steam powdered fire engines and underwater electronic explosives. The &amp;quot;Swedish Nightengale&amp;quot; Jenny Lind made her American debut here in 1850, brought to America by no other then P.T. Barnum. By 1855, successive landfills had enlarged the Park to encompass Castle Garden and on August 3 the structure became America's first immigrant receiving center, welcoming 8.5 million people before it was closed in 1890 and succeeded by Ellis Island. The building was altered once again and reopened as the New York City Aquarium on December 10, 1896. It was one of the city's most popular attractions, and one of America's first public aquariums until it closed in 1941. Following its near-total demolition in 1941 and a major preservation battle, the original fort walls were declared a National Monument by an Act of Congress in 1946. Restored to its fortification appearance by the National Park Service in 1975, the Castle currently houses a small interpretive display and the ticket office for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island ferry. Castle Clinton was designated a landmarks by the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission in 1965. National Register #66000537" id="332111962" latitude="40.703643" license="3" longitude="-74.016367" nbComments="0" rank="7" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark castleclinton park fort southwestbattery nationalmonument nps neoclassical neoclassicalarchitecture americanrenaissance neoclassicism castle nyclpc johnmccomb johnmccombjr landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/160/332111962_7acaa5db3f_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1619" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-09 18:10:47" description="Sculptor Luis Sanguino's &amp;quot;The Immigrants&amp;quot; celebrates the diversity of New York City and the struggle of immigrants in this heroic-sized bronze figural group. The sculpture depicts figures of various ethnic groups and eras, including an Eastern European Jew, a freed African slave, a priest, and a worker. STanding together, the members are connected through their pose. The rough surface of the bronze not only accentuates the extreme emotion, but generalizes the features allowing them to represent no individual in particular. The piece was donated by Samuel Rudin (18961975), who commissioned the sculpture in the early 1970s, intending it to be installed near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt; as a memorial to his parents, who, as it is noted on the plinth, emigrated to the United States in the late-19th century. Although sculpted in 1973, it was not placed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317761&quot;&gt;its initial home in front&lt;/a&gt; of the Castle until 1983. It has since been moved to the northeast of the Castle." id="541777590" latitude="40.703187" license="3" longitude="-74.01655" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark theimmigrants sculpture statue immigrants luissanguino ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: &quot;The Immigrants&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1214/541777590_f71b1c1a82_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="818" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:06:16" description="Sculptor Luis Sanguino's &amp;quot;The Immigrants&amp;quot; celebrates the diversity of New York City and the struggle of immigrants in this heroic-sized bronze figural group. The sculpture depicts figures of various ethnic groups and eras, including an Eastern European Jew, a freed African slave, a priest, and a worker. STanding together, the members are connected through their pose. The rough surface of the bronze not only accentuates the extreme emotion, but generalizes the features allowing them to represent no individual in particular. The piece was donated by Samuel Rudin (1896–1975), who commissioned the sculpture in the early 1970s, intending it to be installed near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt; as a memorial to his parents, who, as it is noted on the plinth, emigrated to the United States in the late-19th century. Although sculpted in 1973, it was not placed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317761&quot;&gt;its initial home in front&lt;/a&gt; of the Castle until 1983. It has since been moved to the northeast of the Castle." id="332139591" latitude="40.703187" license="3" longitude="-74.01655" nbComments="1" rank="9" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark theimmigrants sculpture statue immigrants luissanguino ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: &quot;The Immigrants&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/163/332139591_71d9908112_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1083" />
<photo  date_taken="1998-07-01 00:00:00" description="Sculptor Luis Sanguino's &amp;quot;The Immigrants&amp;quot; celebrates the diversity of New York City and the struggle of immigrants in this heroic-sized bronze figural group. The sculpture depicts figures of various ethnic groups and eras, including an Eastern European Jew, a freed African slave, a priest, and a worker. STanding together, the members are connected through their pose. The rough surface of the bronze not only accentuates the extreme emotion, but generalizes the features allowing them to represent no individual in particular. The piece was donated by Samuel Rudin (1896–1975), who commissioned the sculpture in the early 1970s, intending it to be installed near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt; as a memorial to his parents, who, as it is noted on the plinth, emigrated to the United States in the late-19th century. Although sculpted in 1973, it was not placed in its initial home in front of the Castle until 1983. It has since been moved to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/332137292/&quot;&gt;northeast of the Castle.&lt;/a&gt;" id="163317761" latitude="40.703761" license="3" longitude="-74.016206" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="nyc newyorkcity downtown batterypark theimmigrants sculpture castleclinton immigrants statue manhattan gothamist luissanguino park ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalmonument nps nationalparkservice" title="NYC - Battery Park: &quot;The Immigrants&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/55/163317761_72f0b2d2af_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1738" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:03:36" description="Netherlands Monument This monumental flagstaff commemorates the Dutch establishment of New Amsterdam and the seventeenth century European settlement which launched the modern metropolis of New York City. Designed by H.A.van den Eijnde (1869-1939), a sculptor from Haarlem in the Netherlands, the monument was dedicated in 1926 to mark the tercentenary of Dutch settlement, and the purchase of the island of Manhattan from Native Americans. In 1609, the Dutch East India Company ship De Halve Maen (The Half Moon) entered the harbor. The river still carries the name of the ship’s commander, an Englishman named Henry Hudson. Subsequent trading missions led to the formation in 1614 of the New Netherland Company which stretched from Delaware to Connecticut. In 1621, the States General of the Netherlands established the Dutch West India Company. Around this time, Dutch and Walloon families formed a small community at the southern end of the island, though the precise date and circumstances of New Amsterdam’s creation remain the subject of debate. Also in question is the location of the almost mythical purchase of the land now known as Manhattan by Dutch provincial Director General Peter Minuit from the Lenape people, an event depicted on the south-west façade of the monument. New Amsterdam grew in size and prosperity over the ensuing decades, and became its own municipality in 1653—the same year that a fortification wall was built between the Hudson and East Rivers at what is now Wall Street. This wall was built to defend against an invasion from New England during the First Anglo-Dutch war. Opposite today’s monument site, and the present-day location of the National Museum of the American Indian (formerly the Old Custom House), stood Fort Amsterdam. The waters of the harbor lapped at a shoreline, which has been extended repeatedly over the past three centuries. New Amsterdam was surrendered to the British in 1664 and renamed New York. Though comprising about three tenths of one percent of the citizenry in the year 2000, the Dutch have had far-reaching influence on local culture. Two boroughs—the Bronx and Brooklyn (Breuckelen)—numerous streets, and the New York Knickerbockers professional basketball team derive their names from the Dutch. Old Dutch-style Houses such as the Dyckman Farmhouse (circa 1785) in northern Manhattan and the Wyckoff House (circa 1652) in Flatbush, Brooklyn survive a bygone era. Monuments to the Dutch legacy dot the landscape, and include Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney’s statue of Dutch director general Peter Stuyvesant, commissioned for the 1939 New York World’s Fair, which has stood on the western side of Stuyvesant Square Park since 1941. Above all, New York City’s preeminence in commerce is a direct outgrowth of its origins as a Dutch mercantile trading outpost. On Saint Nicholas Day, December 6, 1926 the Netherlands Monument, a gift of the people of Holland, was formally accepted by Mayor James J. Walker and Parks Commissioner Francis D. Gallatin. At that time it stood south of Castle Clinton, then the site of the New York Aquarium. In 1939 the monument underwent restoration and the inscriptions were recut. Subsequently, a fire caused damage to the monument. When the park was closed from 1940 to 1952 for renovations and to build the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel, the monument was relocated to its present site at the northeast entrance. In 2000 the monument was conserved by the City Parks Foundation Monuments Conservation Program, with the financial support of individual and corporate donors under the auspices of the Netherlands Memorial Foundation and the Netherlands Consulate General. The stone was cleaned and poulticed. Bronze emblems were cleaned, repainted, and coated. The map of New Amsterdam was polished, and the Dutch and English inscriptions were repaired and regilded. A new flagstaff will be installed by the City of New York. The monument was rededicated by the Honorable Pieter van Vollenhoven, Parks Commissioner Stern, and other dignitaries in a ceremony held on November 16, 2000. The date marks Dutch-American Heritage Day, which commemorates the Dutch people’s first salute in 1776 of the United States flag on the Caribbean island of St. Eustatius. The restored monument remains a symbol of the longstanding Dutch presence in American life." id="3929807277" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2542/3929807277_84517543d6_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="248" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:04:05" description="Netherlands Monument This monumental flagstaff commemorates the Dutch establishment of New Amsterdam and the seventeenth century European settlement which launched the modern metropolis of New York City. Designed by H.A.van den Eijnde (1869-1939), a sculptor from Haarlem in the Netherlands, the monument was dedicated in 1926 to mark the tercentenary of Dutch settlement, and the purchase of the island of Manhattan from Native Americans. In 1609, the Dutch East India Company ship De Halve Maen (The Half Moon) entered the harbor. The river still carries the name of the ship’s commander, an Englishman named Henry Hudson. Subsequent trading missions led to the formation in 1614 of the New Netherland Company which stretched from Delaware to Connecticut. In 1621, the States General of the Netherlands established the Dutch West India Company. Around this time, Dutch and Walloon families formed a small community at the southern end of the island, though the precise date and circumstances of New Amsterdam’s creation remain the subject of debate. Also in question is the location of the almost mythical purchase of the land now known as Manhattan by Dutch provincial Director General Peter Minuit from the Lenape people, an event depicted on the south-west façade of the monument. New Amsterdam grew in size and prosperity over the ensuing decades, and became its own municipality in 1653—the same year that a fortification wall was built between the Hudson and East Rivers at what is now Wall Street. This wall was built to defend against an invasion from New England during the First Anglo-Dutch war. Opposite today’s monument site, and the present-day location of the National Museum of the American Indian (formerly the Old Custom House), stood Fort Amsterdam. The waters of the harbor lapped at a shoreline, which has been extended repeatedly over the past three centuries. New Amsterdam was surrendered to the British in 1664 and renamed New York. Though comprising about three tenths of one percent of the citizenry in the year 2000, the Dutch have had far-reaching influence on local culture. Two boroughs—the Bronx and Brooklyn (Breuckelen)—numerous streets, and the New York Knickerbockers professional basketball team derive their names from the Dutch. Old Dutch-style Houses such as the Dyckman Farmhouse (circa 1785) in northern Manhattan and the Wyckoff House (circa 1652) in Flatbush, Brooklyn survive a bygone era. Monuments to the Dutch legacy dot the landscape, and include Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney’s statue of Dutch director general Peter Stuyvesant, commissioned for the 1939 New York World’s Fair, which has stood on the western side of Stuyvesant Square Park since 1941. Above all, New York City’s preeminence in commerce is a direct outgrowth of its origins as a Dutch mercantile trading outpost. On Saint Nicholas Day, December 6, 1926 the Netherlands Monument, a gift of the people of Holland, was formally accepted by Mayor James J. Walker and Parks Commissioner Francis D. Gallatin. At that time it stood south of Castle Clinton, then the site of the New York Aquarium. In 1939 the monument underwent restoration and the inscriptions were recut. Subsequently, a fire caused damage to the monument. When the park was closed from 1940 to 1952 for renovations and to build the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel, the monument was relocated to its present site at the northeast entrance. In 2000 the monument was conserved by the City Parks Foundation Monuments Conservation Program, with the financial support of individual and corporate donors under the auspices of the Netherlands Memorial Foundation and the Netherlands Consulate General. The stone was cleaned and poulticed. Bronze emblems were cleaned, repainted, and coated. The map of New Amsterdam was polished, and the Dutch and English inscriptions were repaired and regilded. A new flagstaff will be installed by the City of New York. The monument was rededicated by the Honorable Pieter van Vollenhoven, Parks Commissioner Stern, and other dignitaries in a ceremony held on November 16, 2000. The date marks Dutch-American Heritage Day, which commemorates the Dutch people’s first salute in 1776 of the United States flag on the Caribbean island of St. Eustatius. The restored monument remains a symbol of the longstanding Dutch presence in American life." id="3930594478" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2489/3930594478_a362259968_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="180" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:03:51" description="Netherlands Monument This monumental flagstaff commemorates the Dutch establishment of New Amsterdam and the seventeenth century European settlement which launched the modern metropolis of New York City. Designed by H.A.van den Eijnde (1869-1939), a sculptor from Haarlem in the Netherlands, the monument was dedicated in 1926 to mark the tercentenary of Dutch settlement, and the purchase of the island of Manhattan from Native Americans. In 1609, the Dutch East India Company ship De Halve Maen (The Half Moon) entered the harbor. The river still carries the name of the ship’s commander, an Englishman named Henry Hudson. Subsequent trading missions led to the formation in 1614 of the New Netherland Company which stretched from Delaware to Connecticut. In 1621, the States General of the Netherlands established the Dutch West India Company. Around this time, Dutch and Walloon families formed a small community at the southern end of the island, though the precise date and circumstances of New Amsterdam’s creation remain the subject of debate. Also in question is the location of the almost mythical purchase of the land now known as Manhattan by Dutch provincial Director General Peter Minuit from the Lenape people, an event depicted on the south-west façade of the monument. New Amsterdam grew in size and prosperity over the ensuing decades, and became its own municipality in 1653—the same year that a fortification wall was built between the Hudson and East Rivers at what is now Wall Street. This wall was built to defend against an invasion from New England during the First Anglo-Dutch war. Opposite today’s monument site, and the present-day location of the National Museum of the American Indian (formerly the Old Custom House), stood Fort Amsterdam. The waters of the harbor lapped at a shoreline, which has been extended repeatedly over the past three centuries. New Amsterdam was surrendered to the British in 1664 and renamed New York. Though comprising about three tenths of one percent of the citizenry in the year 2000, the Dutch have had far-reaching influence on local culture. Two boroughs—the Bronx and Brooklyn (Breuckelen)—numerous streets, and the New York Knickerbockers professional basketball team derive their names from the Dutch. Old Dutch-style Houses such as the Dyckman Farmhouse (circa 1785) in northern Manhattan and the Wyckoff House (circa 1652) in Flatbush, Brooklyn survive a bygone era. Monuments to the Dutch legacy dot the landscape, and include Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney’s statue of Dutch director general Peter Stuyvesant, commissioned for the 1939 New York World’s Fair, which has stood on the western side of Stuyvesant Square Park since 1941. Above all, New York City’s preeminence in commerce is a direct outgrowth of its origins as a Dutch mercantile trading outpost. On Saint Nicholas Day, December 6, 1926 the Netherlands Monument, a gift of the people of Holland, was formally accepted by Mayor James J. Walker and Parks Commissioner Francis D. Gallatin. At that time it stood south of Castle Clinton, then the site of the New York Aquarium. In 1939 the monument underwent restoration and the inscriptions were recut. Subsequently, a fire caused damage to the monument. When the park was closed from 1940 to 1952 for renovations and to build the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel, the monument was relocated to its present site at the northeast entrance. In 2000 the monument was conserved by the City Parks Foundation Monuments Conservation Program, with the financial support of individual and corporate donors under the auspices of the Netherlands Memorial Foundation and the Netherlands Consulate General. The stone was cleaned and poulticed. Bronze emblems were cleaned, repainted, and coated. The map of New Amsterdam was polished, and the Dutch and English inscriptions were repaired and regilded. A new flagstaff will be installed by the City of New York. The monument was rededicated by the Honorable Pieter van Vollenhoven, Parks Commissioner Stern, and other dignitaries in a ceremony held on November 16, 2000. The date marks Dutch-American Heritage Day, which commemorates the Dutch people’s first salute in 1776 of the United States flag on the Caribbean island of St. Eustatius. The restored monument remains a symbol of the longstanding Dutch presence in American life." id="3929810253" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2668/3929810253_bd9337de18_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="346" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:10:04" description="New York Korean War Veterans Memorial This monument in Battery Park, north of Castle Clinton, honors military personnel who served in the Korean Conflict (1950–1953). The memorial, dedicated in 1991, was designed by Welsh-born artist Mac Adams (b. 1943) and is notable as one of the first Korean War memorials erected in the United States. The Korean War began on June 25, 1950, when North Korean forces crossed the 38th parallel, the dividing line between North and South Korea, and invaded South Korea. Within one month, the North Koreans had pushed the South Korean army and supporting U.S. forces to the southernmost tip of the Korean peninsula. In response, the United Nations authorized an army, under the command of U.S. General Douglas MacArthur (1880–1964), to repulse the North Koreans and re-establish the boundary between the North and South at the 38th parallel. In mid-September, MacArthur staged a daring amphibious landing at the Inchon Peninsula and attacked the North Koreans from behind. The U.N. troops soon pushed the North Korean army back across the 38th parallel, and advanced along the Yalu River, the border between North Korea and China. Fearing invasion, Chinese forces became involved in the conflict. In November, the Chinese attacked the U.N. forces near the Yalu River, and drove them back into South Korea. The U.N. forces counterattacked and managed to re-establish a battle line near the 38th parallel. In April 1951, President Harry S. Truman (1884–1972) relieved General MacArthur of his command, rejecting MacArthur’s aggressive policies which Truman believed would instigate a major war with China and the Soviet Union. Fighting would continue in Korea for the next two years, although little ground was gained by either side. Finally, on July 27, 1953, both sides signed an armistice, which ended hostilities and restored the 38th parallel as the dividing line between North and South Korea. In 1987 the Korean War Veterans Memorial Committee was formed to raise money to build a monument to commemorate the soldiers of the “forgotten war.” Mac Adams’ winning design, selected from a group of over 100 entries, features a 15-foot-high black granite stele with the shape of a Korean War soldier cut out of the center. Also known as “The Universal Soldier,” the figure forms a silhouette that allows viewers to see through the monument to the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island. Adams also designed the piece to function as a sundial. Every July 27 at 10 a.m., the anniversary of the exact moment in New York when hostilities ceased in Korea, the sun shines through the soldier’s head and illuminates the commemorative plaque installed in the ground at the foot of the statue. One of the three tiers in the base of the monument is decorated with a mosaic of flags of the countries that participated in the U.N.-sponsored mission. The plaza’s paving blocks are inscribed with the number of dead, wounded, and missing in action from each of the 22 countries that participated in the war. Korean War veterans are also commemorated in New York with the Korean War Veterans Plaza at Cadman Plaza in Brooklyn, and the Korean War Veterans Parkway in Staten Island, previously known as the Richmond Parkway until it was renamed in April 1997 by the New York State Legislature." id="3930617286" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2653/3930617286_201b45c5d7_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="100" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:21:41" description="This monumental flagstaff commemorates the Dutch establishment of New Amsterdam and the seventeenth century European settlement which launched the modern metropolis of New York City. Designed by H.A.van den Eijnde (1869-1939), a sculptor from Haarlem in the Netherlands, it was dedicated on St. Nicholas Day, December 6, 1926 to mark the tercentenary of Dutch settlement, and the purchase of the island of Manhattan from Native Americans. At that time it stood south of Castle Clinton, then the site of the New York Aquarium. In 1939 the monument underwent restoration and the inscriptions were recut. Subsequently, a fire caused damage to the monument. When the park was closed from 1940 to 1952 for renovations and to build the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel, the monument was relocated to its present site at the northeast entrance. In 1609, the Dutch East India Company ship De Halve Maen (The Half Moon) entered the harbor. The river still carries the name of the ship’s commander, an Englishman named Henry Hudson. Subsequent trading missions led to the formation in 1614 of the New Netherland Company which stretched from Delaware to Connecticut. In 1621, the States General of the Netherlands established the Dutch West India Company. Around this time, Dutch and Walloon families formed a small community at the southern end of the island, though the precise date and circumstances of New Amsterdam’s creation remain the subject of debate. Also in question is the location of the almost mythical purchase of the land now known as Manhattan by Dutch provincial Director General Peter Minuit from the Lenape people, an event depicted on the south-west façade of the monument. New Amsterdam grew in size and prosperity over the ensuing decades, and became its own municipality in 1653—the same year that a fortification wall was built between the Hudson and East Rivers at what is now Wall Street. This wall was built to defend against an invasion from New England during the First Anglo-Dutch war. Opposite today’s monument site, and the present-day location of the National Museum of the American Indian (formerly the Old Custom House), stood Fort Amsterdam. The waters of the harbor lapped at a shoreline, which has been extended repeatedly over the past three centuries. New Amsterdam was surrendered to the British in 1664 and renamed New York. Though comprising about .003% of the citizenry, the Dutch have had far-reaching influence on local culture. Two boroughs—the Bronx and Brooklyn (Breuckelen)—numerous streets, and the New York Knickerbockers professional basketball team derive their names from the Dutch. Old Dutch-style Houses such as the Dyckman Farmhouse (circa 1785) in northern Manhattan and the Wyckoff House (circa 1652) in Flatbush, Brooklyn survive a bygone era. Monuments to the Dutch legacy dot the landscape, and include Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney’s statue of Dutch director general &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/508706529/&quot;&gt;Peter Stuyvesant&lt;/a&gt;, commissioned for the 1939 New York World’s Fair, which has stood on the western side of Stuyvesant Square Park since 1941. Above all, New York City’s preeminence in commerce is a direct outgrowth of its origins as a Dutch mercantile trading outpost." id="332157206" latitude="40.704359" license="3" longitude="-74.014833" nbComments="1" rank="15" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark park flagpole netherlandsmemorial netherlands newamsterdam flagstaff dutch ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: Netherlands Memorial Flagstaff" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/142/332157206_487fb30c43_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="2339" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:21:50" description="This monumental flagstaff commemorates the Dutch establishment of New Amsterdam and the seventeenth century European settlement which launched the modern metropolis of New York City. Designed by H.A.van den Eijnde (1869-1939), a sculptor from Haarlem in the Netherlands, it was dedicated on St. Nicholas Day, December 6, 1926 to mark the tercentenary of Dutch settlement, and the purchase of the island of Manhattan from Native Americans. At that time it stood south of Castle Clinton, then the site of the New York Aquarium. In 1939 the monument underwent restoration and the inscriptions were recut. Subsequently, a fire caused damage to the monument. When the park was closed from 1940 to 1952 for renovations and to build the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel, the monument was relocated to its present site at the northeast entrance. In 1609, the Dutch East India Company ship De Halve Maen (The Half Moon) entered the harbor. The river still carries the name of the ship’s commander, an Englishman named Henry Hudson. Subsequent trading missions led to the formation in 1614 of the New Netherland Company which stretched from Delaware to Connecticut. In 1621, the States General of the Netherlands established the Dutch West India Company. Around this time, Dutch and Walloon families formed a small community at the southern end of the island, though the precise date and circumstances of New Amsterdam’s creation remain the subject of debate. Also in question is the location of the almost mythical purchase of the land now known as Manhattan by Dutch provincial Director General Peter Minuit from the Lenape people, an event depicted on the south-west façade of the monument. New Amsterdam grew in size and prosperity over the ensuing decades, and became its own municipality in 1653—the same year that a fortification wall was built between the Hudson and East Rivers at what is now Wall Street. This wall was built to defend against an invasion from New England during the First Anglo-Dutch war. Opposite today’s monument site, and the present-day location of the National Museum of the American Indian (formerly the Old Custom House), stood Fort Amsterdam. The waters of the harbor lapped at a shoreline, which has been extended repeatedly over the past three centuries. New Amsterdam was surrendered to the British in 1664 and renamed New York. Though comprising about .003% of the citizenry, the Dutch have had far-reaching influence on local culture. Two boroughs—the Bronx and Brooklyn (Breuckelen)—numerous streets, and the New York Knickerbockers professional basketball team derive their names from the Dutch. Old Dutch-style Houses such as the Dyckman Farmhouse (circa 1785) in northern Manhattan and the Wyckoff House (circa 1652) in Flatbush, Brooklyn survive a bygone era. Monuments to the Dutch legacy dot the landscape, and include Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney’s statue of Dutch director general &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/508706529/&quot;&gt;Peter Stuyvesant&lt;/a&gt; commissioned for the 1939 New York World’s Fair, which has stood on the western side of Stuyvesant Square Park since 1941. Above all, New York City’s preeminence in commerce is a direct outgrowth of its origins as a Dutch mercantile trading outpost." id="332155554" latitude="40.704359" license="3" longitude="-74.014833" nbComments="1" rank="16" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark park flagpole netherlandsmemorial netherlands newamsterdam flagstaff dutch ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: Netherlands Memorial Flagstaff" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/134/332155554_a46c4ff73f_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1746" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-22 11:30:53" description="Castle Clinton" id="4379076578" latitude="40.70363" license="1" longitude="-74.016892" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="newyork newyorkcity étatsunis usa" title="Tickets" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4018/4379076578_a6da983c83_b.jpg" username="xave" views="125" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-07-14 18:50:53" description="seen from Castle Clinton" id="189759406" latitude="40.703513" license="3" longitude="-74.016877" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="newyork" title="Lower Manhattan" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/70/189759406_21fdf23427_b.jpg" username="renaatje" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-28 14:01:27" description="" id="337019577" latitude="40.703529" license="3" longitude="-74.016818" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="us manhattan lowermanhattan batterypark park castleclinton newyork" title="DSC07253" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/124/337019577_47e76bb9ba_b.jpg" username="Kramchang" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-21 11:52:27" description="" id="2788182436" latitude="40.703529" license="3" longitude="-74.016818" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="us newyork castleclinton manhattan lowermanhattan batterypark park" title="DSC00020.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3092/2788182436_6bb5ae1cb4_b.jpg" username="Kramchang" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-05-12 17:38:42" description="" id="1011670638" latitude="40.703773" license="1" longitude="-74.01699" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="batterypark lowermanhattan manhattan newyorkcity nyc castleclinton" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1337/1011670638_1d383f8519_b.jpg" username="joshbousel" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-05 11:34:06" description="" id="4408346439" latitude="40.703492" license="3" longitude="-74.016813" nbComments="1" rank="22" tags="nikonfm2n kodakportra800 batterypark castleclinton snow snowstorm" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4029/4408346439_4d1e5be223_b.jpg" username="Kilgub" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-11-01 13:12:09" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:4139961503&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See this and neighboring photos on Google Maps.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="4139961503" latitude="40.703472" license="1" longitude="-74.016814" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="nyc newyorkcity newyork ny geo:lat=40703472 geo:lon=74016814 geotagged" title="Castle Clinton #8504" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2633/4139961503_199bfab480_b.jpg" username="Nemo's great uncle" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:50:49" description="Manning &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton National Monument&lt;/a&gt;'s 28 guns Order of September 18, 1814 -- &amp;quot;The force employed will be 2 gunners and 8 matrosses (artillerists) to each gun. To every section of chamber of 2 guns a non commissioned officer.&amp;quot;" id="332113593" latitude="40.703476" license="3" longitude="-74.016775" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark castleclinton park cannon gun fort harbor southwestbattery nationalmonument nps americanrenaissance castle newyorkcitylandmarkspreservationcommission nyclpc landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument - Cannon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/155/332113593_1eae9a77d8_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="747" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-07-10 13:11:36" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. Today, Castle Clinton stands approximately two blocks west of where Fort Amsterdam stood almost 400 years ago, when New York City was still known by the Dutch name New Amsterdam." id="5986061981" latitude="40.7034" license="1" longitude="-74.016864" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="2011 castleclinton castlegarden fortclinton fujifilmfinepix laurel manhattan matt ny nyc newyork newyorkcity x100" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6131/5986061981_44544d972e_b.jpg" username="jonathanpercy" views="155" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-10 09:22:07" description="" id="7113540881" latitude="40.703358" license="3" longitude="-74.016892" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="newyork unitedstates" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7139/7113540881_798e6e0a33_b.jpg" username="dtpancio" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:43:43" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237092384" latitude="40.703899" license="5" longitude="-74.016855" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="" title="Castle Clinton National Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7236/7237092384_b8e46492a5_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-10 09:24:19" description="" id="7113542397" latitude="40.70333" license="3" longitude="-74.016823" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="newyork unitedstates" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7262/7113542397_b3d1d6b951_b.jpg" username="dtpancio" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:01:56" description="This monument honors the valiant sailors of the Norwegian merchant marines and navy who lost their lives in the cause of the Allies during World War II. Many of the thousands of seamen who served and paid the supreme sacrifice considered New York to be their principal port of call, and during the War used it as a home port. The monument was conceived by officers of the Royal Norwegian Navy and Merchant Marine. It was dedicated in a ceremony held on October 21, 1982, and attended by King Olav V of Norway and Mayor Ed Koch. It consists of a large natural granite slab on which rests a boulder with an image of an anchor inscribed on it. Additional inscriptions are etched on the base as well as on a pink granite marker installed in 1995. In the spring of 2001 was relocated to a newly landscaped setting northwest of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton National Monument&lt;/a&gt;." id="331724459" latitude="40.703863" license="3" longitude="-74.017193" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown norwegianmaritimemonument norwegianbattery parkmonumentmemorialwar memorialparknorwegian veterans monument worldwarii wwii worldwar2 norwegianveteransmonument warmemorial ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: Norwegian Maritime Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/132/331724459_a57a81cc85_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="945" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:50:23" description="Castle Clinton, along with more than a dozen other forts was built in anticipation of the War of 1812 to defend New York Harbor. The Southwest Battery was constructed on the rocks off the tip of Manhattan Island between 1808 and 1811. Although fully armed, the fort never had occasion to fire upon an enemy. In 1817, the fort was renamed Castle Clinton in honor of DeWitt Clinton, Mayor and later Governor of New York. The army vacated the fort in 1821 and the structure was deeded to New York City. In the summer of 1824, a new restaurant and entertainment center opened at the site, then called Castle Garden. A roof was added in the 1840s and Castle Garden served as an opera house and theater until 1854. Many new inventions were demonstrated there to amazed audiences including the telegraph, Colts revolving rifles, steam powdered fire engines and underwater electronic explosives. The &amp;quot;Swedish Nightengale&amp;quot; Jenny Lind made her American debut here in 1850, brought to America by no other then P.T. Barnum. By 1855, successive landfills had enlarged the Park to encompass Castle Garden and on August 3 the structure became America's first immigrant receiving center, welcoming 8.5 million people before it was closed in 1890 and succeeded by Ellis Island. The building was altered once again and reopened as the New York City Aquarium on December 10, 1896. It was one of the city's most popular attractions, and one of America's first public aquariums until it closed in 1941. Following its near-total demolition in 1941 and a major preservation battle, the original fort walls were declared a National Monument by an Act of Congress in 1946. Restored to its fortification appearance by the National Park Service in 1975, the Castle currently houses a small interpretive display and the ticket office for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island ferry. Castle Clinton was designated a landmark by the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission in 1965. National Register #66000537" id="332115973" latitude="40.703326" license="3" longitude="-74.017161" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark castleclinton park sign fort southwestbattery nationalmonument nps neoclassical neoclassicalarchitecture americanrenaissance neoclassicism castle newyorkcitylandmarkspreservationcommission nyclpc johnmccomb johnmccombjr landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/161/332115973_54e7e7b31f_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1058" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-03 11:41:29" description="" id="2747207435" latitude="40.703777" license="1" longitude="-74.016594" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="nyc manhattan batterypark" title="Castle Clinton in Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3002/2747207435_348409857e_b.jpg" username="Kwong Yee Cheng" views="38" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-11-15 11:55:26" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Battery Park&lt;/a&gt; Lower Manhattan, New York City, New York, USA" id="6660950881" latitude="40.703605" license="1" longitude="-74.016548" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="america amerika bw batterypark canon castleclinton eos550d eosrebelt2i lowermanhattan manhattan mauer ny nyc nationalhistoricmonument newyork newyorkcity schild sigma18250f3563dcos sign us usa unitedstates unitedstatesofamerica vereinigtestaaten vereinigtestaatenvonamerika vignettierung vignetting wall blackwhite blackandwhite schwarzweis" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7029/6660950881_14e32f090e_b.jpg" username="Nataraj Metz" views="73" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:45:11" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237098556" latitude="40.703407" license="5" longitude="-74.017295" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="" title="Castle Clinton National Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5341/7237098556_9f9b64ca02_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:45:32" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237100010" latitude="40.703407" license="5" longitude="-74.017295" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="" title="Castle Clinton National Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8160/7237100010_9b7e1de141_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:45:01" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237097294" latitude="40.703407" license="5" longitude="-74.017295" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="" title="Castle Clinton National Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7239/7237097294_42f61047b0_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:44:47" description="Castle Clinton or Fort Clinton, once known as Castle Garden, is a circular sandstone fort now located in Battery Park at the southern tip of Manhattan Island, New York City, in the United States. It is perhaps best remembered as America's first immigration station (predating Ellis Island), where more than 8 million people arrived in the U.S. from 1855 to 1890. Over its active life, it has also functioned as a beer garden, exhibition hall, theater, public aquarium, and finally today as a national monument. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237096028" latitude="40.703407" license="5" longitude="-74.017295" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="" title="Castle Clinton National Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8148/7237096028_4e2f01ef8d_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-30 15:16:15" description="Castle Clinton, Battery Park." id="5003680199" latitude="40.703623" license="3" longitude="-74.016512" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="757 holiday usa newyork castle batterypark" title="IMG_3430" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4145/5003680199_d6a2bb2182_b.jpg" username="Andrew Batram" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-30 15:16:35" description="Sign on Castle Clinton, Battery Park." id="5003682741" latitude="40.703623" license="3" longitude="-74.016512" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="757 holiday usa newyork castle sign batterypark" title="IMG_3431" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4113/5003682741_6289a67c91_b.jpg" username="Andrew Batram" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-24 12:11:24" description="" id="231998957" latitude="40.703484" license="2" longitude="-74.017376" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="newyork usa" title="clinton castle" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/81/231998957_aadec39c66_b.jpg" username="Patrick Rasenberg" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2002-01-19 01:38:08" description="Castle Clinton, Deus Ex !" id="2299055973" latitude="40.703635" license="4" longitude="-74.016469" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="newyork couchsurfingnewyork" title="New York 26/28" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3106/2299055973_dc6e28cc7a_b.jpg" username="Francis Bourgouin" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-21 11:55:31" description="" id="2788189008" latitude="40.703619" license="3" longitude="-74.01641" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="us newyork ticket castleclinton manhattan lowermanhattan batterypark park ferry thestatueofliberty ellisisland 自由女神 移民島" title="DSC00021.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3070/2788189008_01443ef26d_b.jpg" username="Kramchang" views="90" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-28 12:34:40" description="" id="337019290" latitude="40.703619" license="3" longitude="-74.01641" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="us manhattan lowermanhattan batterypark park castleclinton newyork" title="DSC07251" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/134/337019290_f1e6a1ce46_b.jpg" username="Kramchang" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:51:41" description="Castle Clinton, along with more than a dozen other forts was built in anticipation of the War of 1812 to defend New York Harbor. The Southwest Battery was constructed on the rocks off the tip of Manhattan Island between 1808 and 1811. Although fully armed, the fort never had occasion to fire upon an enemy. In 1817, the fort was renamed Castle Clinton in honor of DeWitt Clinton, Mayor and later Governor of New York. The army vacated the fort in 1821 and the structure was deeded to New York City. In the summer of 1824, a new restaurant and entertainment center opened at the site, then called Castle Garden. A roof was added in the 1840s and Castle Garden served as an opera house and theater until 1854. Many new inventions were demonstrated there to amazed audiences including the telegraph, Colts revolving rifles, steam powdered fire engines and underwater electronic explosives. The &amp;quot;Swedish Nightengale&amp;quot; Jenny Lind made her American debut here in 1850, brought to America by no other then P.T. Barnum. By 1855, successive landfills had enlarged the Park to encompass Castle Garden and on August 3 the structure became America's first immigrant receiving center, welcoming 8.5 million people before it was closed in 1890 and succeeded by Ellis Island. The building was altered once again and reopened as the New York City Aquarium on December 10, 1896. It was one of the city's most popular attractions, and one of America's first public aquariums until it closed in 1941. Following its near-total demolition in 1941 and a major preservation battle, the original fort walls were declared a National Monument by an Act of Congress in 1946. Restored to its fortification appearance by the National Park Service in 1975, the Castle currently houses a small interpretive display and the ticket office for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island ferry. Castle Clinton was designated a landmark by the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission in 1965. National Register #66000537" id="332114572" latitude="40.703643" license="3" longitude="-74.016367" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark castleclinton park plaque nps fort southwestbattery nationalmonument castle newyorkcitylandmarkspreservationcommission nyclpc johnmccomb johnmccombjr landmark ny newyork castleclintonnationalmonument nationalparkservice nationalregisterofhistoricplaces nrhp usnationalregisterofhistoricplaces" title="NYC - Battery Park: Castle Clinton National Monument - NPS plaque" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/141/332114572_2e0e10c585_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1007" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:18:57" description="Sculptor Luis Sanguino's &amp;quot;The Immigrants&amp;quot; celebrates the diversity of New York City and the struggle of immigrants in this heroic-sized bronze figural group. The sculpture depicts figures of various ethnic groups and eras, including an Eastern European Jew, a freed African slave, a priest, and a worker. STanding together, the members are connected through their pose. The rough surface of the bronze not only accentuates the extreme emotion, but generalizes the features allowing them to represent no individual in particular. The piece was donated by Samuel Rudin (1896–1975), who commissioned the sculpture in the early 1970s, intending it to be installed near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt; as a memorial to his parents, who, as it is noted on the plinth, emigrated to the United States in the late-19th century. Although sculpted in 1973, it was not placed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317761&quot;&gt;its initial home in front&lt;/a&gt; of the Castle until 1983. It has since been moved to the northeast of the Castle." id="332137292" latitude="40.703187" license="3" longitude="-74.01655" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark theimmigrants sculpture statue immigrants luissanguino ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: &quot;The Immigrants&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/164/332137292_a5e5585f82_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="848" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 17:06:08" description="Sculptor Luis Sanguino's &amp;quot;The Immigrants&amp;quot; celebrates the diversity of New York City and the struggle of immigrants in this heroic-sized bronze figural group. The sculpture depicts figures of various ethnic groups and eras, including an Eastern European Jew, a freed African slave, a priest, and a worker. STanding together, the members are connected through their pose. The rough surface of the bronze not only accentuates the extreme emotion, but generalizes the features allowing them to represent no individual in particular. The piece was donated by Samuel Rudin (1896–1975), who commissioned the sculpture in the early 1970s, intending it to be installed near &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt; as a memorial to his parents, who, as it is noted on the plinth, emigrated to the United States in the late-19th century. Although sculpted in 1973, it was not placed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317761&quot;&gt;its initial home in front&lt;/a&gt; of the Castle until 1983. It has since been moved to the northeast of the Castle. Pictured in the background is the impressive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/332089709&quot;&gt;Whitehall Building&lt;/a&gt;." id="332138410" latitude="40.703187" license="3" longitude="-74.01655" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark theimmigrants sculpture statue immigrants luissanguino ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: &quot;The Immigrants&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/147/332138410_567e24a2c1_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="928" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-06-10 12:39:28" description="A plaque at the entrance of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt;." id="5915308974" latitude="40.703561" license="5" longitude="-74.016331" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="" title="P6102570" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6014/5915308974_3ff87873b3_b.jpg" username="calestyo" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:40:27" description="Battery Park is a 25-acre (10 hectare) public park located at the Battery, the southern tip of Manhattan Island in New York City, facing New York Harbor. The Battery is named for artillery batteries that were positioned there in the city's early years in order to protect the settlement behind them. At the north end of the park is Castle Clinton, the often re-purposed last remnant of the defensive works that inspired the name of the park; Pier A, formerly a fireboat station; and Hope Garden, a memorial to AIDS victims. At the other end is Battery Gardens restaurant, next to the United States Coast Guard Battery Building. Along the waterfront, ferries depart for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island, and there is also a New York Water Taxi stop. The park is also the site of the East Coast Memorial which commemorates U.S. servicemen who died in coastal waters of the western Atlantic Ocean during World War II, and several other memorials. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237083170" latitude="40.703765" license="5" longitude="-74.016319" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="" title="Battery Park with Sphere and Manhattan Financial District in Background" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7075/7237083170_07a282ea9f_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-30 15:13:53" description="Castle Clinton, Battery Park." id="5003675473" latitude="40.703179" license="3" longitude="-74.016383" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="757 holiday usa newyork park castle batterypark" title="IMG_3428" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4131/5003675473_cf679b9bdd_b.jpg" username="Andrew Batram" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-10 09:19:11" description="" id="6967462786" latitude="40.703669" license="3" longitude="-74.016237" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="newyork unitedstates" title="Castle Clinton" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7275/6967462786_c217e2fc71_b.jpg" username="dtpancio" views="43" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-03 11:38:50" description="" id="3884354469" latitude="40.703736" license="1" longitude="-74.016244" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="panorama newyork" title="Clinton Castle" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3462/3884354469_2911c9dd84_b.jpg" username="czechian" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-23 16:53:38" description="This nearly ten-foot-tall granite stele at the northwest corner of Battery Park by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/163317527/&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton National Monument&lt;/a&gt; was designed by noted architect Henry Bacon. The monument and its gilded inscription commemorates the Walloon Settlers, a group of 32 Belgian Huguenot families who joined the Dutch in 1624 on the ship Nieu Nederland (“New Netherland”) to colonize New Amsterdam. Bacon also designed Washington's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/136354036/&quot;&gt;Lincoln Memorial&lt;/a&gt; and Williamsburg's Metropolitan Pool. The Walloons were natives of the County of Hainaut in Belgium who had fled to nearby Holland to escape religious persecution. Made to feel unwelcome in Holland, the Walloons, led by Jesse de Forest, first appealed to the British in 1621 for permission to settle in Virginia. When was denied, they petitioned the Dutch West India Company to allow them to settle in the Dutch-controlled colony of New Amsterdam. Their application was granted and the Walloons left Holland in March 1624, landing in New York on May 20, 1624. The piece was dedicated May 20, 1924, the 300th anniversary of the Walloon settlers’ arrival in New York. The monument was a gift of the Conseil Provincial du Hainaut and is made of Hainaut granite, a Belgian stone. That year Governor Alfred E. Smith and the New York State Senate issued an official proclamation recognizing the Walloons’ place in New York history and the Federal Government issued three commemorative stamps and a silver 50-cent coin to mark the anniversary. The monument was relocated from the northeast part of the park to its current location as a result of the construction of the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel during the late 1940s and early 50s." id="331724758" latitude="40.70418" license="3" longitude="-74.016517" nbComments="1" rank="51" tags="newyorkcity nyc manhattan gothamist downtown batterypark walloonsettlersmemorial walloon belgian park ny newyork" title="NYC - Battery Park: Walloon Settlers Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/153/331724758_419f6e0cd5_b.jpg" username="wallyg" views="1492" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-25 15:51:18" description="我喜歡枯樹" id="402865798" latitude="40.703236" license="5" longitude="-74.01633" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="tree winter castle clinton" title="樹" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/160/402865798_e02a7d6769_b.jpg" username="tommy.lan" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-06-10 12:39:16" description="The entrance to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Clinton&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Castle Clinton&lt;/a&gt;." id="5914749011" latitude="40.703558" license="5" longitude="-74.016225" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="" title="P6102569" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6041/5914749011_01cf74e80b_b.jpg" username="calestyo" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-20 10:44:22" description="The line for the ferry to the Statue of Liberty ran along the water edge, City Pier A and the edge of the park back to Castle Clinton." id="4966515409" latitude="40.704125" license="3" longitude="-74.016412" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="park usa newyork newyorkcity manhattan" title="imgp1642.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4087/4966515409_cebe896e20_b.jpg" username="Mr. Pi" views="72" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:46:58" description="17 State Street is a 42-story building in the Financial District of Manhattan. It was designed by Emery Roth and Sons, and it is most noted for its distinct curved facade. The bottom floors of the skyscraper are home to New York Unearthed, an urban archaeology museum with approximately two million artifacts from local excavation sites. The museum was originally included as a concession to the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission, who had been unable to perform an archaeological survey of the site before construction began. They believed that the lot had contained artifacts from the early 18th century, although a lawyer for the construction firm claimed to be &amp;quot;absolutely certain that no archeological material was lost. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/17_State_Street&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/17_State_Street&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237103016" latitude="40.703822" license="5" longitude="-74.017692" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="" title="Castle Clinton with 17 State Street in Background" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7091/7237103016_f32a309034_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-30 12:40:32" description="@ Castle Clinton National Monument &lt;a href=&quot;http://4sq.com/l5f9EC&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4sq.com/l5f9EC&lt;/a&gt; (posted via FlickSquare)" id="5777314340" latitude="40.703643" license="2" longitude="-74.016051" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="uploaded:by=flicksquare foursquare:venue=4ad0ec5df964a52023db20e3 geo:lat=407036434049721 geo:lon=740160512924194" title="Grandpa enjoying the show at Battery Park. http://picplz.com/xH2m" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5223/5777314340_419d9df2ae_b.jpg" username="mjpeacecorps" views="35" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:42:04" description="Battery Park is a 25-acre (10 hectare) public park located at the Battery, the southern tip of Manhattan Island in New York City, facing New York Harbor. The Battery is named for artillery batteries that were positioned there in the city's early years in order to protect the settlement behind them. At the north end of the park is Castle Clinton, the often re-purposed last remnant of the defensive works that inspired the name of the park; Pier A, formerly a fireboat station; and Hope Garden, a memorial to AIDS victims. At the other end is Battery Gardens restaurant, next to the United States Coast Guard Battery Building. Along the waterfront, ferries depart for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island, and there is also a New York Water Taxi stop. The park is also the site of the East Coast Memorial which commemorates U.S. servicemen who died in coastal waters of the western Atlantic Ocean during World War II, and several other memorials. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237085088" latitude="40.704302" license="5" longitude="-74.01633" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="" title="Walloon Monument, Battery Park, Manhattan, New York" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7215/7237085088_d74d6fe101_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:07:51" description="Walloon Settlers Monument This nearly ten-foot-tall granite stele at the northwest corner of Battery Park by Castle Clinton was designed by noted architect Henry Bacon (1866–1924). The monument and its gilded inscription commemorates the Walloon Settlers, a group of 32 Belgian Huguenot families who joined the Dutch in 1624 on the ship Nieu Nederland (“New Netherland”) to colonize New Amsterdam, in what is now called the island of Manhattan. Architect Bacon also designed Washington, D.C.’s Lincoln Memorial (1911-22) and Brooklyn’s Metropolitan Pool (1922). The Walloons were natives of the County of Hainaut in Belgium who had fled to nearby Holland to escape religious persecution. Made to feel unwelcome in Holland, the Walloons, led by Jesse de Forest, first appealed to the British in 1621 for permission to settle in the British-controlled Virginia colony. When their request to the British was denied, they petitioned the Dutch West India Company to allow them to settle in the Dutch-controlled colony of New Amsterdam. Their application was granted and the Walloons left Holland in March 1624, landing in New York on May 20, 1624. The piece was dedicated May 20, 1924, the 300th anniversary of the Walloon settlers’ arrival in New York. The monument was a gift of the Conseil Provincial du Hainaut and is made of Hainaut granite, a Belgian stone. That year Governor Alfred E. Smith (1873-1944) and the New York State Senate issued an official proclamation recognizing the Walloons’ place in New York history and the Federal Government issued three commemorative stamps and a silver 50-cent coin to mark the anniversary. The monument was relocated from the northeast part of the park to its current location as a result of the construction of the Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel during the late 1940s and early 50s." id="3929822275" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2531/3929822275_f243a06ebf_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="140" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:09:09" description="Norwegian Veterans Monument This monument honors the valiant sailors of the Norwegian merchant marines and navy who lost their lives in the cause of the Allies during World War II. Many of the thousands of seamen who served and paid the supreme sacrifice considered New York to be their principal port of call, and during the War used it as a home port. The monument was conceived by officers of the Royal Norwegian Navy and Merchant Marine. It was dedicated in a ceremony held on October 21, 1982, and attended by King Olav V of Norway and Mayor Edward I. Koch. It consists of a large natural granite slab on which rests a boulder with an image of an anchor inscribed on it. Additional inscriptions are etched on the base as well as on a pink granite marker installed in 1995. In the spring of 2001, as part of the overall improvements to the park’s Upper Promenade designed by Saratoga Associates and implemented by the City and the Conservancy for Historic Battery Park, the monument was relocated to a newly landscaped setting northwest of Castle Clinton." id="3929832467" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2551/3929832467_a304547dcf_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="63" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:09:04" description="Norwegian Veterans Monument This monument honors the valiant sailors of the Norwegian merchant marines and navy who lost their lives in the cause of the Allies during World War II. Many of the thousands of seamen who served and paid the supreme sacrifice considered New York to be their principal port of call, and during the War used it as a home port. The monument was conceived by officers of the Royal Norwegian Navy and Merchant Marine. It was dedicated in a ceremony held on October 21, 1982, and attended by King Olav V of Norway and Mayor Edward I. Koch. It consists of a large natural granite slab on which rests a boulder with an image of an anchor inscribed on it. Additional inscriptions are etched on the base as well as on a pink granite marker installed in 1995. In the spring of 2001, as part of the overall improvements to the park’s Upper Promenade designed by Saratoga Associates and implemented by the City and the Conservancy for Historic Battery Park, the monument was relocated to a newly landscaped setting northwest of Castle Clinton." id="3930610528" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2428/3930610528_ff1f064e9d_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="79" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-06 14:09:01" description="Norwegian Veterans Monument This monument honors the valiant sailors of the Norwegian merchant marines and navy who lost their lives in the cause of the Allies during World War II. Many of the thousands of seamen who served and paid the supreme sacrifice considered New York to be their principal port of call, and during the War used it as a home port. The monument was conceived by officers of the Royal Norwegian Navy and Merchant Marine. It was dedicated in a ceremony held on October 21, 1982, and attended by King Olav V of Norway and Mayor Edward I. Koch. It consists of a large natural granite slab on which rests a boulder with an image of an anchor inscribed on it. Additional inscriptions are etched on the base as well as on a pink granite marker installed in 1995. In the spring of 2001, as part of the overall improvements to the park’s Upper Promenade designed by Saratoga Associates and implemented by the City and the Conservancy for Historic Battery Park, the monument was relocated to a newly landscaped setting northwest of Castle Clinton." id="3930607294" latitude="40.703545" license="2" longitude="-74.015986" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="newyork newyorkcity nyc" title="Battery Park" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2438/3930607294_de11d8de4d_b.jpg" username="peterjr1961" views="76" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-25 15:55:03" description="Castle Clinton 這跟前任總統沒關係" id="402866555" latitude="40.703407" license="5" longitude="-74.015997" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="battery park mahattan" title="克林頓堡" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/124/402866555_42b81493f1_b.jpg" username="tommy.lan" views="58" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-16 18:39:35" description="In Battery Park, Castle Clinton in the background. Spent a few lovely afternoons here." id="189936791" latitude="40.70261" license="3" longitude="-74.016673" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="newyork batterypark" title="Fountain" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/59/189936791_14ae64dbe1_b.jpg" username="renaatje" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-05 10:40:02" description="We got to the South Ferry around 10 am. We walked around until we found the ticket booth in Castle Clinton. There were no &amp;quot;crown&amp;quot; tickets available, so there was to be no access to the monument itself. I understand that these are now being booked four months in advance! We were told the line up for security was around two hours - this was taken at 10:40, soon after we joined line." id="4539434164" latitude="40.702984" license="3" longitude="-74.015772" nbComments="2" rank="64" tags="batterypark lineup" title="The line up" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2690/4539434164_30d9279b4c_b.jpg" username="Stephen Rees" views="78" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-01-13 16:38:29" description="This monument, one of the first Korean War monuments erected in the USA (1991), is located north of Castle Clinton at NYC's Battery Park. Information on the monument is available here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycgovparks.org/about/history/historical-signs/listings?id=12355&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.nycgovparks.org/about/history/historical-signs/listin...&lt;/a&gt;" id="6691646177" latitude="40.704521" license="3" longitude="-74.015192" nbComments="1" rank="65" tags="new york city ny usa united states battery park korean war veterans memorial" title="New York Korean War Veterans Memorial - Battery Park, New York City, NY, USA" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7028/6691646177_8a2abf5559_b.jpg" username="Juan_Carlos_Cruz" views="290" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-17 05:38:52" description="Battery Park is a 25-acre (10 hectare) public park located at the Battery, the southern tip of Manhattan Island in New York City, facing New York Harbor. The Battery is named for artillery batteries that were positioned there in the city's early years in order to protect the settlement behind them. At the north end of the park is Castle Clinton, the often re-purposed last remnant of the defensive works that inspired the name of the park; Pier A, formerly a fireboat station; and Hope Garden, a memorial to AIDS victims. At the other end is Battery Gardens restaurant, next to the United States Coast Guard Battery Building. Along the waterfront, ferries depart for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island, and there is also a New York Water Taxi stop. The park is also the site of the East Coast Memorial which commemorates U.S. servicemen who died in coastal waters of the western Atlantic Ocean during World War II, and several other memorials. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battery_Park&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_...&lt;/a&gt;" id="7237076246" latitude="40.704298" license="5" longitude="-74.014849" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="" title="Monument to the Establishment of Fort Amsterdam, Battery Park, Manhattan" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7229/7237076246_8ecd064aa6_b.jpg" username="Ken Lund" views="14" />
</photos>
