<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Liberty Memorial">

<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:16:12" description="The Marines lining up before the start of the rededication ceremony at Kansas City, Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312491129" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="marines soldiers flags rededication kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Marines In A Row" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/122/312491129_37b56e3567_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="2323" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:07:45" description="American soldiers during World War I were referred to as Doughboys, but why? No one really knows the answer, but here are some of the theories. From Wikipedia: &amp;quot;The origin of the term is unclear. The most commonly held explanation is that it came into use in the Civil War in reference to the dumpling-shaped buttons on the Union soldiers' jackets. Others claim that it goes back to the Mexican-American War of 1846-48, or originated from an early form of the doughnut, called the doughboy. Another explanation of the term stems from the time of the Punitive Expedition against Pancho Villa in 1916, in which the infantry were constantly covered with dust from marching through the dry terrain of northern Mexico, giving them the appearance of unbaked dough. Other explanations point to the use of pipe clay, which looks like dough, to clean infantrymen’s white belts; another is that it is a corruption of &amp;quot;adobe boy&amp;quot; from the adobe bricks used to house infantrymen in the pre-Civil War Southwest; and yet another that it refers to the &amp;quot;soft&amp;quot; condition of the young soldiers, applied by British and French forces in World War I who had already fought nearly four years. None of these theories is definite.&amp;quot; Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312491271" latitude="39.079924" license="3" longitude="-94.586357" nbComments="1" rank="2" tags="doughboy soldier american rifle helmet kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Doughboy InThe Elements" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/115/312491271_3b6db8da79_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="1418" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:11:39" description="This wall shows the different insignias worn by the soldiers. Each symbol designates a different military division. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312485583" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="2" rank="3" tags="insignias patches uniform division infantry rainbow kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Insignias" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/312485583_ffd96019af_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="572" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:48:30" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. The museum has a large recreation of trench warfare. To see the trench, there are small &amp;quot;head holes&amp;quot; that you stick you head through to see into their world and hear the sounds of war. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312487138" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="3" rank="4" tags="trench sandbags barbedwire soldiers recreation exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="The Trench" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/120/312487138_7b6a68c071_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="970" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:34:45" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Inside the museum, but not in the exhibits, these small interactive windows show photographs of soldiers who served during the war. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312484530" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="soldiers photographs history interactive kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Those Who Served" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/111/312484530_d3d8e9615b_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="185" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:11:10" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. A display showcasing jackets and symbols of the war. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312485834" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="jacket uniform exhibit flag symbols kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Jackets" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/121/312485834_793aa53648_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="221" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:52:50" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. The museum has a large recreation of trench warfare. To see the trench, there are small &amp;quot;head holes&amp;quot; that you stick you head through to see into their world and hear the sounds of war. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312486869" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="3" rank="7" tags="trench soldiers recreation exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="TheTrench 2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/121/312486869_418ea90e87_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="370" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:11:58" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. A wall of showing photos of soldiers. The pictures are kind of small so the wall has built-in magifying glasses that slide up and down as well as left and right. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312485410" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="soldiers old photos magnify glass magnifyingglass wall kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Magnify" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/111/312485410_c87e7e1431_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="168" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:44:03" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. The official logo for the museum right near the front entrance. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312488758" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="logo official soldier entrance kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Museum Entrance" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/101/312488758_40f31c13fa_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="271" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-10 10:36:49" description="One of the four figures that appear near the top of the WWI Liberty Memorial in Kansas City, Missouri. This one is called &amp;quot;Sacrifice&amp;quot;. The other three are Courage, Honor and Patriotism. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="242708832" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="0" rank="10" tags="sacrifice stone figure libertymemorial memorial world war one wwi kansascity missouri" title="Sacrifice" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/80/242708832_cf19b421cb_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="204" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-22 10:59:16" description="Liberty Memorial in Kansas City. The official national monument to commemorate World War I. Apparently it is also the only national monument created in the Art Deco Style. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="45672465" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="0" rank="11" tags="kansascity libertymemorial liberty memorial war worldwari missouri monument national sky landscape artdeco" title="The Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/32/45672465_56306dfd43_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="688" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:00:11" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Just after the release of doves, the curtain is parted, and the museum offically opens to the public. At the podium is Kansas City Mayor Kay Barnes. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312489136" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="12" tags="curtains parting mayor barnes ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="The Curtains Open" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/114/312489136_62a4319db3_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="122" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 12:38:36" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. During the rededication ceremony, retired Brigadier General Stephen R. Berkheiser, USMC spoke about the museum. He is the Executive Director of the National WWI Museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312489730" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="brigadier general berkheiser marine director ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="General Berkheiser" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/118/312489730_cbc1e9dee8_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="181" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:26:58" description="At Kansas City's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum, these bricks are part of a program that allows people to buy a brick to honor a living or deceased soldier who served in war. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312490753" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="walkofhonor bricks honor fundraising kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Walk Of Honor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/108/312490753_55d8a575f9_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="232" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 12:46:03" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. During the rededication ceremony, Brigadier General Dany Van de Ven, from the Defense, Military, Naval and Air Attache, Embassy of Belgium, spoke about the museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312489550" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="15" tags="brigadier general vandeven belgium military ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="General Van de Ven" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/106/312489550_3b63e3ef17_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="179" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:40:51" description="People waiting for the start of the rededication ceremony for Kansas City's Liberty Memorial World War I Musuem. Many veterans and former soldiers were in attendance. According to Wikipedia, 13 American WWI soldiers are still alive, but I don't think any of them were in attendance. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312490010" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="veterans public flag ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Veteran" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/109/312490010_c167e713f3_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="114" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:05:22" description="Dressed in World War I era uniforms, the Color guard carries the flag. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312491802" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="flag american doughboy soldiers kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Doughboy Color Guard" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/99/312491802_abc86f17ed_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="264" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:30:27" description="Four Marines wait in the cold weather for the rededication ceremony to start. This ceremony reopened Kansas City's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312490279" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="18" tags="marines soldiers uniforms skyline snow kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Soldiers Waiting" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/100/312490279_cbabb5094f_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="313" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:03:50" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. The crowd descends down the steps and around the fountain into the new museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312488938" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="fountain ceremony public curtains kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Museum Is Open" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/103/312488938_b9ad99b723_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="119" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:22:01" description="Marines attending the rededication ceremony of Kansas City, Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312490940" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="1" rank="20" tags="marines soldiers uniforms rededication tower gloves kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Soldiers And Honor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/100/312490940_831dd7ec35_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="509" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 12:52:41" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. During the rededication ceremony, Kansas Governor Kathleen Sebelius spoke about the museum. I thought it was interesting that the governor of Kansas attended this event, even though the museum is in Missouri. Also, Governor Matt Blunt was listed in the program, but did not attend. He was also not mentioned during the ceremony. If he had missed the ceremony due to inclement weather (highly possible) wouldn't he have sent a message to be read in his absence? Interesting... Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312489357" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="governor sebelius kansas ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Governor Sebelius" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/111/312489357_e3b1cab120_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="141" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:05:43" description="This photo was taken just about an hour before the opening of the renovated Liberty Memorial Museum. A giant black curtain was placed over the new entrance for the ceremony. The eyes on the curtain symbolize the purpose of the museum - to allow the visitor to see the war through the soldiers' eyes. Also, the flags of the allied forces were flown (left to right: Great Britian, Belgium, U.S., Italy and France) Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312491557" latitude="39.080248" license="3" longitude="-94.586217" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="curtain flags greatbritian belgium italy france tower fountain kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="The Eyes Of War" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/312491557_9e43accc4e_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="207" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:48" description="" id="281759034" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010023.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/106/281759034_8a95505a41_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="28" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:22" description="" id="281758041" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="view courtyard lawn tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010013.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/91/281758041_886511483b_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="15" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:09" description="" id="281757354" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="cp carrie ml micah me tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010005.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/281757354_46f819314d_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:32" description="" id="281758850" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="elevator tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010021.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/87/281758850_b556a19b0f_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:04" description="" id="281758519" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="cp carrie tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri view" title="P1010018.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/118/281758519_df6c6aefb0_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:23:43" description="" id="281757091" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri museum" title="P1010002.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/94/281757091_4066291b52_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:38" description="" id="281757624" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="interior museum libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="National World War One Museum interior" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/89/281757624_466a452fb1_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="27" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:39" description="" id="281758217" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010015.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/79/281758217_14cb3a5ff0_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:19" description="" id="281757443" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri museum" title="P1010006.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/104/281757443_3f9df8accb_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="27" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:56" description="" id="281757799" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010010.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/99/281757799_102899759a_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:22" description="" id="281758738" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="elevator gate tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010020.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/106/281758738_a56f1ec444_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:13" description="" id="281758649" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri view usps unitedstatespostoffice postoffice aerial" title="P1010019.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/86/281758649_01a0f6391b_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="83" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:01" description="" id="281757275" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="cp carrie libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri downtown" title="P1010004.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/122/281757275_bf982dfa49_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:23:34" description="" id="281756986" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="tower lawn libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010001.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/117/281756986_53a622e30a_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:26:40" description="" id="281758938" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="warning letter blurry libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010022.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/106/281758938_096cfe25aa_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:29" description="" id="281757534" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="urn libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010007.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/114/281757534_6650d0d798_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:31" description="" id="281758118" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010014.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/112/281758118_800a4fd03a_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:47" description="" id="281758319" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="view downtown unionstation tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010016.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/79/281758319_d080d59390_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:23:52" description="" id="281757175" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="sphinx libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010003.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/104/281757175_07541b3dc7_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:56" description="" id="281758432" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="view downtown unionstation tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010017.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/87/281758432_1dc92a980a_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:24:46" description="" id="281757700" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010009.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/119/281757700_23ae21cbf1_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:04" description="" id="281757871" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010011.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/110/281757871_58f730de0a_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-10-28 17:25:13" description="" id="281757960" latitude="39.080115" license="1" longitude="-94.586271" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="cp carrie skyline view downtown tower libertymemorial nationalworldwaronemuseum artdeco kansascity mo missouri" title="P1010012.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/117/281757960_e0c2f222e1_b.jpg" username="mlaaker" views="55" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:03:56" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. PENTAX *istDs, f4.5, 35mm, 1/8s, ISO1600." id="92378470" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="5" rank="46" tags="kia museum wwi war kansas liberty" title="KIA" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/30/92378470_ac726e1ae9_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="131" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:11:38" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. PENTAX *istDs, 33mm, f5.6, 1/1500s, ISO200." id="96126133" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="2" rank="47" tags="memorial museum kansascity war wwi" title="IMGP6664" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/39/96126133_48c9cafea1_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="99" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:10:56" description="Liberty Memorial Tower, Kansas City. This is the tower dedicated in 1921 after the World War I. Many people and generals gathered around here for the peace after the first massacre swept all around the world. As you all know, peace hadn't last that long after this dedication. PENTAX *istDs, f5.6, 55mm, 1/1500s, ISO200." id="92791464" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="4" rank="48" tags="wwi war memorial museum kansascity" title="For the Peace of All Mankind" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/32/92791464_17f5b478f8_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="172" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:17:42" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. PENTAX *istDs, f4.0, 26mm, 1/250s, ISO1600." id="93760658" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="4" rank="49" tags="wwi war museum kansas liberty" title="Do you know him?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/25/93760658_d8fe1f939b_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="100" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 10:42:17" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. A watch had been on a soldier's wrist in the moments of life and death. PENTAX *istDs, f4.5, 40mm, 1/20s, ISO1600." id="91257585" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="watch wwi memory war museum kansas" title="Remained..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/17/91257585_b50a481c1e_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="150" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:28:16" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. Canister that was used for pigeon messengers during the World War I. Just imagine how many soldiers had been saved through this small packet...and what can I do to save someone else? PENTAX *istDs, 26mm, f4.0, 1/125s, ISO1600." id="98033929" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="2" rank="51" tags="dof pigeon messenger wwi war memorial kansas museum" title="Messenger" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/31/98033929_a671363720_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="195" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:24:19" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. Enemy or friend.... what makes the difference in our world? This broken helmet reminds me of the movie 'Saints and Soldiers'. PENTAX *istDs, 23mm, f4.0, 1/45s, ISO1600." id="94432407" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="war memorial museum kansascity helmet german wwi" title="Enemy..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/38/94432407_67a78d4654_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="241" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:16:17" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. One of the slides used to train soldiers during the World War I. I don't know how the past war made influence on our education system, but it's sad enough that many of our modern technology have been developed for military use at first. PENTAX *istDs, f4.0, 24mm, 1/90s, ISO1600." id="93393345" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="slide war education museum kansascity" title="Education" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/27/93393345_d94df08a96_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="218" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 10:45:04" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, Kansas City. PENTAX *istDs, f4.5, 35mm, 1/6s, ISO1600." id="91634609" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="ironcross wwi war museum" title="Iron Cross...." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/26/91634609_79d54d41ea_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="116" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-12 11:43:02" description="Liberty Memorial Museum, kansas City. Shadow of the Liberty Memorial Tower and the Stars and Stripes....May peace stay here forever. PENTAX *istDs, 55mm, f9.5, 1/250s, ISO200." id="95531071" latitude="39.080074" license="3" longitude="-94.586341" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="starsandstripes memory memorial museum liberty kansascity" title="Shadow" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/32/95531071_f891885df9_b.jpg" username="Mountainbread" views="118" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-31 14:45:27" description="Kansas City, Liberty memorial" id="5305060575" latitude="39.080602" license="3" longitude="-94.586094" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="rebelforces rebelalliance theempire terrorist terrorism notbenhoy giabo" title="L1070888.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5082/5305060575_4859475a8c_b.jpg" username="sam~x" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-17 15:16:28" description="@ National World War I Museum at Liberty Memorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://4sq.com/MkdJXT&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4sq.com/MkdJXT&lt;/a&gt; (posted via FlickSquare)" id="7388866916" latitude="39.080637" license="1" longitude="-94.586089" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="uploaded:by=flicksquare foursquare:venue=4f9c0ba5e4b04dd7353a754d geo:lat=3908063728597938 geo:lon=9458608987731417" title="got right off the plane and onto my bike, it's gorgeous in KC today!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7214/7388866916_c53983ac35_b.jpg" username="ramseymohsen" views="1" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-10 15:15:22" description="" id="7358961414" latitude="39.079874" license="1" longitude="-94.586148" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="instagramapp square squareformat iphoneography uploaded:by=instagram hudson foursquare:venue=4ac910adf964a52063be20e3" title="downtown Kansas City (off the top of Liberty Memorial)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7096/7358961414_bacd7f7e07_b.jpg" username="ramseymohsen" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-11 19:30:34" description="@ Liberty Memorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://4sq.com/LJvJBK&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4sq.com/LJvJBK&lt;/a&gt; (posted via FlickSquare)" id="7553025732" latitude="39.079874" license="1" longitude="-94.586148" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="uploaded:by=flicksquare foursquare:venue=4ac910adf964a52063be20e3 geo:lat=39079874203988716 geo:lon=9458614826202393" title="At Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8148/7553025732_b868f0b776_b.jpg" username="ramseymohsen" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-10 10:19:42" description="@ Liberty Memorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://4sq.com/LHXtng&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4sq.com/LHXtng&lt;/a&gt; (posted via FlickSquare)" id="7357927570" latitude="39.079874" license="1" longitude="-94.586148" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="uploaded:by=flicksquare foursquare:venue=4ac910adf964a52063be20e3 geo:lat=39079874203988716 geo:lon=9458614826202393" title="Stop #3, we made it to the top!" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7079/7357927570_b3f456f5e1_b.jpg" username="ramseymohsen" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-02 13:40:33" description="@ Liberty Memorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://4sq.com/L8KN4v&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4sq.com/L8KN4v&lt;/a&gt; (posted via FlickSquare)" id="7321984936" latitude="39.079874" license="1" longitude="-94.586148" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="uploaded:by=flicksquare foursquare:venue=4ac910adf964a52063be20e3 geo:lat=39079874203988716 geo:lon=9458614826202393" title="#ilovekansascity" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8167/7321984936_10656b4f42_b.jpg" username="ramseymohsen" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-16 19:34:22" description="I recently went to the Liberty Memorial here in Kansas City. This is the only monument in the United States dedicated to the memorial of World War 1. I would highly recommend visiting it if you come to Kansas City. Its a beautiful monument and museum. The memorial is currently undergoing some renovations which somewhat limited the shots I could take. This turned out to be kind of nice in this case. The memorial is so large and there are so many angles you can shoot it from sticking to a limited area aloud me to not worry about other possible shots and focus on just this area. I will probably return to the memorial several more times in the future to try some different compositions. This is one of the first shots I took this evening. I was really waiting for the sun to get lower and for the sky to change a little more before starting to shoot but I just loved how the blue and orange/yellow colors compliment each other. The clouds really worked well for this shot as well. I really like how the memorial looks out over the Kansas City sky line." id="7433704756" latitude="39.080682" license="3" longitude="-94.58604" nbComments="2" rank="62" tags="libertymemorial worldwar1 kansascity monuments worldwarmemorial kansas hdr" title="Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7269/7433704756_f88cc68fdf_b.jpg" username="ZTW1" views="126" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 11:25:37" description="The weather during the Liberty Memorial rededication was COLD. Symbolic of their assistance during the war, the American Red Cross gave out free coffee, hot chocolate and mini cinnamon rolls. Thank you, Red Cross! Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312491403" latitude="39.079924" license="3" longitude="-94.586357" nbComments="1" rank="63" tags="american redcross free coffee hotchocolate kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="It's FREE" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/115/312491403_418864159c_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="136" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:50:08" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. As a graphic designer, I wanted to add this photo to show how the museum used type to convey information. It's very legible and well spaced. The way it should be. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312486524" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="type lettering graphics exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="French Trench Type" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/112/312486524_66046489b8_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="205" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:26:46" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. A display of a cot, table and stretcher used by the medical personnel during the war. This display is covered in a light fabric. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312484938" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="cot table stretcher medical exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Taking Care of the Wounded" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/114/312484938_3ff42a9c58_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="156" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:56:48" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. This photo might look like just a light table, but it's not. It's much more. It's actually a bunch of interactive monitors that you can interact with using laser wands. A must see! Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312486313" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="interactive table light digital laser animated kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Interactive Table" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/114/312486313_bffb83004c_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="622" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 12:08:40" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. A Biplane flies near the Liberty Memorial Tower during the rededication ceremony. During the ceremony, the plane dropped rose petals on the crowd. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312489845" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="67" tags="biplane airplane tower ceremony kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Biplane" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/102/312489845_1564166521_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="123" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:46:11" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. This photo is of a display of artifacts (like gas masks, shell casings, etc.) that are placed under the floor along with type and covered with glass so you can walk over the top of it. This blurry photo doesn't do it justice. Very cool. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312487331" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="68" tags="glass gasmask type lettering shells bullets kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Glass Floor Case" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/117/312487331_9995d3988a_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="241" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:14:47" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Another one of the museums &amp;quot;environments&amp;quot; is this recreation of a bomb crater. The visitor steps into the middle of a giant hole showing the enormity of the destruction. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312485176" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="crater hole damage mud destruction exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Crater" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/112/312485176_218c7a5625_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="199" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:30:22" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. From the entrance of the museum, you can see through the glass roof up towards the Liberty Tower. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312484676" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="2" rank="70" tags="tower glass ceiling entrance kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Looking Up At The Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/122/312484676_28a220b179_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="195" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:12:52" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Just inside the museum is a large field of poppies, symbolizing the poppies that grew on the battlefields of Belgium and France throughout the war regardless of the conditions. It is also a reference to the famous poem &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arlingtoncemetery.net/flanders.htm&quot;&gt;In Flanders Field. &lt;/a&gt; A large glass bridge spans the poppies and leads you into the exhibits. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312488601" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="1" rank="71" tags="poppies bridge glass entrance kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum skylight visitors" title="Field Of Poppies" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/312488601_dae7d67e41_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="405" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:44:45" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. A couple of large cannons inside the new museum. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312487603" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="cannons displays kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Cannons" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/108/312487603_2913c8fe40_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="251" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:29:36" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Once inside the museum, this large room sets the stage for the visitor by showing the conditions in Europe before the war, and the reasons the war happened. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312487982" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="3" rank="73" tags="giant murals beginning introduction kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Beginning of the Museum, Beginning of the War" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/120/312487982_371fe36b6d_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="308" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:21:55" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. One of the displays on the museum's interactive tables shows posters, photos and artwork of Kansas City during the World War I era. I thought it was cool there was a reference to KC's old Electric Park. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312486177" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="interactive table photos art electricpark kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="KC During The War" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/109/312486177_1d4a2e5150_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="156" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:41:09" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. War era propaganda posters. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312487819" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="75" tags="posters propaganda art design kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="European War Posters" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/118/312487819_2551e2f41a_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="450" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:24:16" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. The opening wall just inside the museum. This museum was designed by famous museum designer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raany.com/html/RalphAppelbaum.html&quot;&gt;Ralph Appelbaum. &lt;/a&gt; He is responsible for the design of the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum and for the American Museum of Natural History. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312488131" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="76" tags="exhibit kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="The World War" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/107/312488131_8aebc949c4_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="460" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:06:08" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. One of the signature items of this museum is a giant IMAX-like screen that is about 100 feet wide and helps the visitor experience the war. Just below the screen is a recreation of soldiers slogging through the mud and rubble. This is another example of how my blurry photo does not do this exhibit justice. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312486044" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="77" tags="screen horizontheater movie exhibit soldiers mud kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Horizon Theater" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/117/312486044_25cd5f5e89_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="288" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 14:16:46" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. Looking very similar to the exhibit room at the beginning of the museum, this room looks back at the lessons of the war, and towards the consequences for the future - namely World War II. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312484828" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="78" tags="war exhibit end skyscrapers kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="The End Of War" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/115/312484828_138318ce9d_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="205" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-12-02 13:13:19" description="Kansas City Missouri's Liberty Memorial World War I Museum. This is looking throught the glass bridge inside the museum down on to the field of poppies. The bridge is very sturdy, but I felt a little uncomfortable at first walking over this transparent bridge! Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="312488338" latitude="39.080711" license="3" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="0" rank="79" tags="bridge glass poppies entrance kansascity missouri libertymemorial nationalworldwarimuseum wwi grandreopening museum" title="Glass Bridge" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/111/312488338_1302696e82_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="512" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 16:04:29" description="Taken from the main floor of the Liberty Memorial. This was a very interesting room at the top was glass as well as the floor." id="294871313" latitude="39.080727" license="6" longitude="-94.586132" nbComments="2" rank="80" tags="" title="Looking Up" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/119/294871313_c1fc8c8f7e_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="24" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-31 14:38:43" description="Kansas City, Liberty memorial" id="5305655604" latitude="39.080665" license="3" longitude="-94.585858" nbComments="0" rank="81" tags="rebelforces rebelalliance theempire terrorist terrorism notbenhoy giabo" title="L1070872.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5161/5305655604_0edf63df9c_b.jpg" username="sam~x" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 15:54:57" description="" id="294861967" latitude="39.080781" license="6" longitude="-94.586057" nbComments="1" rank="82" tags="" title="Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/99/294861967_0e2234adef_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 16:08:04" description="Look up from the base of Liberty Memorial" id="294786099" latitude="39.080781" license="6" longitude="-94.586057" nbComments="0" rank="83" tags="" title="Looking Up" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/101/294786099_3add3a9ad3_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 15:57:36" description="Walking on a glass floor at Liberty Memorial." id="294868714" latitude="39.080781" license="6" longitude="-94.586057" nbComments="0" rank="84" tags="" title="IMG_4455" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/103/294868714_844ee39ef6_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 16:12:20" description="From the top of Liberty Memorial" id="294783820" latitude="39.080781" license="6" longitude="-94.586057" nbComments="0" rank="85" tags="kansascity libertymemorial" title="217 Feet High" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/110/294783820_1bf04a6c29_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="25" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-11 15:55:26" description="Looking to the West at Liberty Memorial" id="294865549" latitude="39.080781" license="6" longitude="-94.586057" nbComments="6" rank="86" tags="abigfave" title="Down The Road" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/101/294865549_8b6282a3d6_b.jpg" username="steve9567" views="73" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-10-24 14:37:55" description="A World War I memorial in downtown Kansas City, MO. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libertymemorialmuseum.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.libertymemorialmuseum.org/&lt;/a&gt;" id="188534619" latitude="39.0808" license="3" longitude="-94.586" nbComments="0" rank="87" tags="mo missouri kansascity unionstation libertymemorial monuments geotagged geo:lat=390808 geo:lon=945860" title="Liberty Memorial Monument" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1/188534619_ebc20d2e54_b.jpg" username="m t miller" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-05-25 20:45:29" description="" id="153410169" latitude="39.080827" license="1" longitude="-94.586212" nbComments="0" rank="88" tags="libertymemorial unionstation kansascity blue" title="Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/63/153410169_c451e80cd0_b.jpg" username="Jose Mario Santamaria" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-28 17:59:48" description="how many times can i use 'memorial'?  i recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libertymemorialmuseum.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;museum&lt;/a&gt; highly." id="372658210" latitude="39.080852" license="3" longitude="-94.586121" nbComments="0" rank="89" tags="thingsididntmake libertymemorial kansascity" title="memorial from the memorial-making software at the liberty memorial museum" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/128/372658210_5597f1df23_b.jpg" username="sparrowsfall" views="94" />
<photo  date_taken="2002-05-27 11:55:53" description="how &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; they keep people from jumping off?  because it would be pretty simple. to leap, that is. the last one to do so, i believe, was just before they closed it a number of years ago for repairs and such.  it's insanely high: it made me ill to look over the edge. but people do such things." id="336620487" latitude="39.080852" license="3" longitude="-94.586121" nbComments="2" rank="90" tags="kansascity libertymemorial" title="all the talk about the liberty memorial really makes you think..." url_b="http://static.flickr.com/130/336620487_5978dfe549_b.jpg" username="sparrowsfall" views="64" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-02-18 15:24:53" description="Kansas City, Missouri" id="6903923643" latitude="39.080861" license="2" longitude="-94.586191" nbComments="0" rank="91" tags="" title="Strolling the Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7057/6903923643_32fb3dc985_b.jpg" username="mrtickles" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-03 18:53:24" description="Kansas City, Liberty memorial" id="5305063377" latitude="39.080862" license="3" longitude="-94.585864" nbComments="0" rank="92" tags="rebelforces rebelalliance theempire terrorist terrorism notbenhoy giabo" title="L1080552.JPG" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5243/5305063377_2b534d9fef_b.jpg" username="sam~x" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-11 14:03:31" description="" id="418007926" latitude="39.079994" license="3" longitude="-94.586684" nbComments="0" rank="93" tags="kansascity libertymemorial" title="Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/167/418007926_f0388eda5e_b.jpg" username="jonathan_moreau" views="768" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-22 12:08:37" description="" id="4822063473" latitude="39.080919" license="2" longitude="-94.586191" nbComments="0" rank="94" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial worldwarimuseum" title="Memory Sphinx at Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4098/4822063473_85292606f1_b.jpg" username="gmeador" views="40" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-22 16:02:30" description="Two of the Four Symbolic &amp;quot;guardsmen&amp;quot; of Liberty Memorial, named Patriotism and Courage (the other two are Sacrifice and Honor). Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="45672624" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="1" rank="95" tags="liberty memorial libertymemorial kansascity missouri worldwari war statue artdeco patriotism courage sword" title="Patriotism &amp; Courage" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/24/45672624_7ec275e8d3_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="289" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-22 12:02:27" description="Downtown Kansas City as seen from the top of Liberty Memorial. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="45672586" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="0" rank="96" tags="kansascity kansas city downtown skyscrapers buildings skyline missouri" title="Downtown Kansas City" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/26/45672586_6fc9325816_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="1720" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-10 10:16:44" description="Looking up the hill towards the WWI Liberty Memorial in Kansas City, Missouri. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="242708799" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="0" rank="97" tags="worldwari world war one memorial tower grass lawn sky kansascity missouri" title="Liberty Memorial" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/81/242708799_2696a3d919_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="147" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-09-22 11:04:50" description="Base of The Liberty Memorial tower with downtown Kansas City in the background. Visit my website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrism70.com&quot;&gt; ChrisM70.com. &lt;/a&gt;" id="45672483" latitude="39.08094" license="3" longitude="-94.586078" nbComments="0" rank="98" tags="kansascity libertymemorial liberty memorial war worldwari missouri" title="&quot;In Honor Of Those Who Served&quot;" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/29/45672483_56b24fbf20_b.jpg" username="ChrisM70" views="164" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-04-07 10:04:02" description="This photo was submitted un-crazified but somehow flickr decided to switch the blues and reds during the upload. It looks cool so it shall stay. Explore: ?" id="518480353" latitude="39.080956" license="4" longitude="-94.586094" nbComments="4" rank="99" tags="kansascity libertymemorial worldwari missiouri kcmo war soldier" title="Flickr Mistake Madness" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/246/518480353_e668c2273e_b.jpg" username="Brian ⚓ Hillegas" views="124" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:19:58" description="" id="209830030" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="100" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3852.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/74/209830030_aecc01a292_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:54:01" description="" id="209854077" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="101" tags="kansascity missouri westernauto libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3894.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/90/209854077_53e9b0655f_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:12:15" description="Hmm... a bit crooked. oh well!" id="209825550" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="102" tags="kansascity missouri sky tall libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3841.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/61/209825550_335669d8b6_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:03:54" description="Just look at that Liberty Memorial pop!" id="209861001" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="103" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3904-ps3.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/82/209861001_e01b13ce91_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:40:16" description="There's nothing like an artsy fartsy angle!" id="209842182" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="104" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial artsy fartsy inabeanpod" title="DSC_3874.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/67/209842182_46aba08847_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:57:02" description="My friend was waiting to take a totally sweet shot of Union Station but there was this bus in the way... So I took a quick shot thinking that might get the bus to move. It didn't work. The bus moved forward to the next set of windows and sat for a while longer." id="209855169" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="2" rank="105" tags="kansascity missouri unionstation libertymemorial downtown inabeanpod" title="DSC_3898.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/71/209855169_de798cffb2_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="78" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:17:36" description="Standing tall in black and white." id="209828477" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="106" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial long shadow inabeanpod" title="DSC_3851-bw.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/72/209828477_646ed5ab73_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:58:26" description="" id="209856006" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="107" tags="kansascity missouri fountain libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3899.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/90/209856006_7978fda126_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:03:54" description="A friend of my suggested this shot. I think it turned out pretty well because I forgot my tripod and hand held this shot." id="209861458" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="108" tags="kansascity missouri amazinghandheldshot libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3904.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/84/209861458_2e82045fa8_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:44:57" description="" id="209849813" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="109" tags="kansascity missouri moon tree libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3884.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/91/209849813_505e201198_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:15:49" description="" id="209827870" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="110" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3850.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/95/209827870_6f48d0c5d4_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:21:02" description="" id="209834980" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="111" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3859.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/89/209834980_0ecf094c56_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:20:58" description="" id="209834273" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="112" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3858.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/70/209834273_f3cafd3e41_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:44:57" description="" id="209848943" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="113" tags="kansascity missouri bw blackandwhtie moon tree libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3884-bw.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/77/209848943_606da65b68_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:03:54" description="Not so glowy any more" id="209860556" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="114" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial orange gray black inabeanpod" title="DSC_3904-ps2.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/68/209860556_100580e8fc_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:12:21" description="" id="209826247" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="115" tags="kansascity missouri sky tall libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3842.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/63/209826247_2d8abf9b15_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:56:47" description="" id="209854607" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="116" tags="kansascity missouri downtown libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3897.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/95/209854607_15e3d6d38d_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:11:14" description="" id="209824920" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="117" tags="kansascity missouri sky tall libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3840.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/62/209824920_5e85640b53_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:20:44" description="The top and a bit of the middle." id="209831436" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="118" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3854.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/72/209831436_5dd573183f_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:15:36" description="I was trying to shoot the train... but blew out the sky and just about everything else!" id="209827305" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="119" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3849.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/58/209827305_23d6cb37d3_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:27:56" description="" id="209863131" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="120" tags="kansascity missouri alllitup libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3916.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/72/209863131_02ddca1d76_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="22" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:52:50" description="" id="209852182" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="121" tags="kansascity missouri downtown libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3889.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/87/209852182_f95bf6a847_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:29:17" description="Now that's a sweet reflection! Half water half marble = 100% Cool!! You can buy this shot @ &lt;a href=&quot;http://inabeanpod.imagekind.com&quot;&gt;http://inabeanpod.imagekind.com&lt;/a&gt;!!" id="209837142" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="122" tags="kansascity missouri reflection libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3863.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/87/209837142_5817af9f4b_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:32:45" description="" id="209839005" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="123" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3869.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/78/209839005_ec4f77d040_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:23:07" description="Saw a couple of girls trying to take photos of themselves under that tree." id="209836214" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="124" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3860.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/97/209836214_9fde65b145_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:41:33" description="Capturing the perfict shot." id="209844623" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="125" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3878.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/83/209844623_9844396ed4_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:42:14" description="" id="209845576" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="126" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3879.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/82/209845576_0effaff321_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:03:54" description="Still glowing!" id="209860027" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="127" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial glow orange gray black inabeanpod" title="DSC_3904-ps1.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/85/209860027_8aa6fcc712_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:20:48" description="The middle." id="209832181" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="128" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3855.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/68/209832181_79a7a55328_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:32:52" description="" id="209839773" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="129" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3870.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/83/209839773_7558c94f2b_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:42:59" description="" id="209846216" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="130" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3880.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/60/209846216_480f7d777e_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:44:16" description="" id="209847371" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="131" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3882.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/62/209847371_483a09f9e0_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:02:54" description="A friend of my suggested this shot. I think it turned out pretty well because I forgot my tripod and hand held this shot." id="209858328" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="132" tags="kansascity missouri amazinghandheldshot libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3902.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/62/209858328_99e00576e9_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:47:09" description="" id="209850203" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="133" tags="kansascity missouri sunset libertymemorial inabeanpod outdoors tagged" title="DSC_3885.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/64/209850203_d334751f09_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 04:03:23" description="A friend of my suggested this shot. I think it turned out pretty well because I forgot my tripod and hand held this shot. You can buy this shot @ &lt;a href=&quot;http://inabeanpod.imagekind.com&quot;&gt;http://inabeanpod.imagekind.com&lt;/a&gt;!!" id="209858918" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="134" tags="kansascity missouri amazinghandheldshot libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3903.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/71/209858918_7785b6285a_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:53:54" description="" id="209853571" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="135" tags="kansascity missouri westernauto libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3893.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/78/209853571_127bacc0ed_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:53:00" description="" id="209852675" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="136" tags="kansascity missouri downtown libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3890.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/75/209852675_c96cb38042_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:20:51" description="More of the middle... and it looks like I'm falling over! LOL" id="209832894" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="137" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3856.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/91/209832894_147e804188_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:51:51" description="" id="209851179" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="138" tags="kansascity missouri friends libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3887.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/75/209851179_8eac07403e_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:44:42" description="" id="209848375" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="139" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial vineyardchurchhat inabeanpod" title="DSC_3883.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/81/209848375_9791941489_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:41:22" description="Stalking the perfict shot." id="209843871" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="140" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3877.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/73/209843871_9cc9dc81a0_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:36:03" description="" id="209840946" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="1" rank="141" tags="kansascity missouri stickbug selectivecolor libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3872-sc.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/98/209840946_d4b7391577_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:20:40" description="The top!" id="209830614" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="142" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3853.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/57/209830614_570766ea3b_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:52:18" description="" id="209851689" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="143" tags="kansascity missouri downtown libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3888.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/73/209851689_19db06610f_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:59:04" description="" id="209857011" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="144" tags="kansascity missouri strangers libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3900.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/92/209857011_430987765a_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:10:56" description="I set the back of the camera on the ground with the bottom of the camera right next to the mermorial and fired the shot... and took off the top of my head in the process! LOL" id="209823974" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="145" tags="kansascity missouri sky myhead libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3839.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/86/209823974_d4699ef39f_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:14:29" description="" id="209826943" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="146" tags="kansascity missouri westernauto libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3848.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/76/209826943_2949f42a40_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:36:03" description="" id="209841572" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="147" tags="kansascity missouri stickbug libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3872.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/85/209841572_9891e60db8_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:30:05" description="A photographer capturing the moment." id="209838117" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="148" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial reflection inabeanpod" title="DSC_3864.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/69/209838117_b0875d797d_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:53:19" description="" id="209853090" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="149" tags="kansascity missouri downtown libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3891.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/71/209853090_67b4211d7b_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="19" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-01-15 03:41:20" description="Stalking the perfict shot." id="209843096" latitude="39.080956" license="3" longitude="-94.586073" nbComments="0" rank="150" tags="kansascity missouri libertymemorial inabeanpod" title="DSC_3876.jpg" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/71/209843096_26aee30c1d_b.jpg" username="inabeanpod" views="3" />
</photos>
