<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Luxor Obelisk">

<photo  date_taken="2008-10-03 11:13:56" description="Amazingly, the removal of this obelisk (part of a pair) from the entrance of the Temple of Luxor in the 19th Century is depicted on its base, Paris; October 2008 Canon 30D" id="3508358129" latitude="48.865498" license="3" longitude="2.321119" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="obelisk base pedestal temple luxor egypt place dela concorde assemblée nationale national assembly egyptian paris 巴黎 パリ parigi france 法国 frankreich 5photosaday" title="In Paris,  from Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3408/3508358129_9498f65785_b.jpg" username="█ Slices of Light █▀ ▀ ▀" views="109" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-17 16:34:32" description="Obélisque et grande roue, Place de la Concorde, peu de temps avant la pluie... L'obélisque égyptien de Louxor, vieux de 3 300 ans (XIIIe siècle av. J.‑C.), fut transporté en France en 1836, offert par l'Égypte en reconnaissance du rôle du Français Champollion qui a été le premier à traduire les hiéroglyphes. Le roi Louis-Philippe le fit placer au centre de la place lors son l'aménagement par l'architecte Hittorff. Haut de 22,86 mètres, le monolithe, en granite rose de Syène, pèse 227 tonnes. Il est érigé sur un socle de 9 mètres et est coiffé d'un pyramidion doré de plus de trois mètres et demi. Les hiéroglyphes qui le recouvrent célèbrent la gloire du pharaon Ramsès II. Le sommet de cet obélisque est surmonté d'un pyramidion de plus de 3,50 m, ajouté en mai 1998, aussi pointu qu'étincelant, fait de bronze et de feuilles d'or. Il est censé remplacer un précédent ornement sommital, emporté lors d'invasions en Égypte au VIe siècle. L'obélisque se situe sur la ligne de l'axe historique de Paris qui va de l'Arc de triomphe du Carrousel à l'Arche de la Défense en passant par le jardin des Tuileries et l'avenue des Champs-Élysées. L'obélisque est aussi un cadran solaire, grâce à des lignes tracées au sol. &lt;i&gt;The center of the Place is occupied by a giant Egyptian obelisk decorated with hieroglyphics exalting the reign of the pharaoh Ramses II. It is one of two the Egyptian government gave to the French in the nineteenth century. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology at that time. In the 1990s, President François Mitterrand gave the second obelisk back to the Egyptians. The obelisk once marked the entrance to the Luxor Temple. The Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered the 3,300-year-old Luxor Obelisk to France in 1829. It arrived in Paris on 21 December 1833. Three years later, on 25 October 1836, King Louis Philippe had it placed in the center of Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the Revolution. The obelisk, a red granite column, rises 23 metres (75 ft) high, including the base, and weighs over 250 metric tons (280 short tons). Given the technical limitations of the day, transporting it was no easy feat — on the pedestal are drawn diagrams explaining the machinery that was used for the transportation. The obelisk is flanked on both sides by fountains constructed at the time of its erection on the Place. Early morning on 1 December 1993, the French AIDS fighting society Act Up Paris carried out a fast and unwarned commando-style operation. A giant pink condom was unrolled over the whole monument.[3] Missing its original cap, believed stolen in the 6th century BC, the government of France added a gold-leafed pyramid cap to the top of the obelisk in 1998.&lt;/i&gt; Source, Wikipedia" id="6544144337" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321087" nbComments="4" rank="2" tags="olibac obélisque paris concorde obelisk canoneos500d mmxi absolutearchitecture redmatrix" title="Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7020/6544144337_cfb43f5864_b.jpg" username="OliBac" views="177" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:17:54" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution - in Paris, France (from the coach) The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="3769624411" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="0" rank="3" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3594/3769624411_e5dc8f8888_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="256" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:17:28" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. Building behind is the Hôtel de Crillon. The Hôtel de Crillon in Paris is one of the oldest luxury hotels in the world. It is located at the foot of the Champs-Élysées on the north side of Place de la Concorde. The five-star Crillon, with 103 guest rooms and 44 suites, occupies one of two identical stone buildings, divided by the rue Royale, constructed in 1758 under the auspices of architect Louis François Trouard as a result of a commission from King Louis XV. Initially, both structures were built as government offices, and the eastern one continues to this day as Headquarters of the Royale, the French Navy. In 1788, François-Félix-Dorothee Berton des Balbes, the Count of Crillon, acquired the hotel, only to have it confiscated shortly thereafter by the government of the French Revolution. It was eventually returned to the Count of Crillon's family who ran it until 1907, at which time it underwent a two-year-long refurbishing by the Société du Louvre under the supervision of architect Gabriel-Hippolyte Destailleur. Today, through the Concorde Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts, the Crillon is still part of the Société du Louvre whose shares are listed on the Paris Stock Exchange and is controlled by the Taittinger family holding company." id="3769621837" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="0" rank="4" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach hôteldecrillon champselysees rueroyale louisfrancoistroucard kinglouisxv headquartersoftheroyalethefrenchnavy francoisfelixdorotheebertondesbalbes countofcrillon societedulouvre gabrielhippolytedestailleur concordehotelsresorts taittinger" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3440/3769621837_5a7bc15693_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="294" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 11:49:26" description="A view of the Luxor Obelisk from the Seine. During preparations for Bastille Day (which was three days later). A zoom in on the Luxor Obelisk, probably from the river boat cruise down the Seine. The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="4910717443" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="0" rank="5" tags="paris riverseine france iledefrance bateauxmouches boat boattrip rivercruise placedelaconcorde kinglouisxv louisxv kinglouisxvi louisxvi queenmarieantoinette marieantoinette beheaded placedelalouisxv placedelarevolution guillotine reignofterror obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap trees" title="Luxor Obelisk from the River Seine" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4137/4910717443_da72a85df4_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="69" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 10:23:28" description="The Luxor Obelisk as seen from the coach while we were on Quai d'Orsay. We wer about to pass the Palais Bourbon - National Assembly of France. Was my first glimpse of it from the coach. Trees in the way. One of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations. The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="4871078511" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="0" rank="6" tags="paris france iledefrance coach riverseine quaidorsay palaisbourbon nationalassemblyoffrance placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap trees" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France - from Quai d'Orsay" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4118/4871078511_6079f551c1_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:16:19" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. The building behind is the Hôtel de la Marine. The Hotel de la Marine (also known hotel in the Garde-Meuble) is located in Paris, Place de la Concorde. It was built between 1757 and 1774. The facade was designed by Jacques-Ange Gabriel, prime architect of the King, author of the plans of the Place Louis XV (now the Place de la Concorde). The hotel itself was built to plans by Gabriel edited by Jacques-Germain Soufflot. Since 1789 it housed the Ministry of Naval Affairs. Nowadays the command office of the marine is located in this building. Bullet holes still visible from the final battle for Paris on 26 August 1944." id="3769615621" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="2" rank="7" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach hôteldelamarine placelouisxv jacquesangegabriel jacquesgermainsoufflot ministryofnavalaffairs commandofficeofthemarine flag flags frenchflag hotelinthegardemeuble" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2502/3769615621_2346f91775_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="343" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-19 15:23:36" description="Place de la Concorde, Paris" id="3349726438" latitude="48.865448" license="2" longitude="2.321215" nbComments="1" rank="8" tags="paris place de la concorde backlight sun needle obelisk luxor egypt monument" title="Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3451/3349726438_43344efef5_b.jpg" username="peirz" views="71" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 11:49:01" description="A view of the Luxor Obelisk from the Seine. Two signs to the left of it. A zoom in on the Luxor Obelisk, probably from the river boat cruise down the Seine. The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="3763467868" latitude="48.865529" license="4" longitude="2.320963" nbComments="0" rank="9" tags="paris riverseine france obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle placedelaconcorde ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance rivercruise boattrip bateauxmouches" title="Luxor Obelisk from the River Seine" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3441/3763467868_7fd9eefbfb_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="69" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-03 20:35:38" description="Stereographic projection of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gadl/414906232/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; equirectangular panorama. Part of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gadl/sets/72157594279945875/&quot;&gt;Wee planets&lt;/a&gt; set." id="414906241" latitude="48.865516" license="5" longitude="2.320953" nbComments="12" rank="10" tags="paris 75008 france placedelaconcorde place concorde fontaine fountain obélisque champsélysées champs élysées madeleine assemblénationale toureiffel nuit night longexposure panorama hugin enblend 360° stereographicprojection stereographic projection planet planète polar hôteldecrillon eiffel tour tower eiffeltower obelisk" title="Obélisque de Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/159/414906241_78decdb738_b.jpg" username="gadl" views="7249" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-26 16:33:46" description="Several decades after its construction, this square was to serve as a focal point for the bloodiest political upheaval in the history of France: the French Revolution. When the hordes of revolutionaries seized power, they renamed the square Place de la Révolution, tore down the statue of Louis XV and replaced it with a guillotine. Between 1793 and 1795, more than 1300 people were beheaded in public executions, including Louis XVI, Marie Antoinette, Danton and Robespierre. It is said that the scent of blood was so strong here that a herd of cattle once refused to cross the grounds. Supplanting the guillotine is the powerful Obelisk of Luxor, a pink granite monolith that was given to the French in 1829 by the viceroy of Egypt, Mehemet Ali. The edifice, which once marked the entrance to the Amon temple at Luxor, is more than 3,300 years old and is decorated with hieroglyphics portraying the reigns of the pharaohs Ramses II and Ramses III. Gilded images on the pedestal portray the monumental task of transporting the monolith to Paris and erecting it at the square. Installed in 1833, the Obelisk — weighing 230 tons and standing 22.83 meters (75 ft) high in the center of the Place — is flanked on both sides by two fountains constructed during the same period. Having survived more than 33 centuries, the Obelisk has suffered the greatest damage during the past half-century by air pollution from industry and motor vehicles. -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.discoverfrance.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.discoverfrance.net&lt;/a&gt;" id="7411336108" latitude="48.865364" license="1" longitude="2.321156" nbComments="1" rank="11" tags="eiffeltower paris luxorobelisk obélisquedelouxor placedelaconcorde luxor egypt" title="Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/5234/7411336108_f89818a168_b.jpg" username="Jason OX4" views="56" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-03 11:24:56" description="The Egyptian Obelisk at the Place de la Concorde with the Palais Bourbon (across the Seine) in the background), Paris; October 2008 Canon 30D" id="3509169810" latitude="48.865709" license="3" longitude="2.321537" nbComments="3" rank="12" tags="place dela concorde assemblée nationale national assembly obelisk egyptian luxor egypt hieroglyphs paris 巴黎 パリ parigi france 法国 frankreich 5photosaday 5halloffame" title="Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3304/3509169810_930a5c3d24_b.jpg" username="█ Slices of Light █▀ ▀ ▀" views="122" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:15:48" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. The building on the right side of the square is the Hôtel de la Marine. The Hotel de la Marine (also known hotel in the Garde-Meuble) is located in Paris, Place de la Concorde. It was built between 1757 and 1774. The facade was designed by Jacques-Ange Gabriel, prime architect of the King, author of the plans of the Place Louis XV (now the Place de la Concorde). The hotel itself was built to plans by Gabriel edited by Jacques-Germain Soufflot. Since 1789 it housed the Ministry of Naval Affairs. Nowadays the command office of the marine is located in this building. Bullet holes still visible from the final battle for Paris on 26 August 1944." id="3770413168" latitude="48.865237" license="4" longitude="2.320754" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach lantern lamppost hôteldelamarine placelouisxv jacquesangegabriel jacquesgermainsoufflot ministryofnavalaffairs commandofficeofthemarine hotelinthegardemeuble" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3580/3770413168_1fab8f43b4_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="300" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:16:40" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations. The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. Building behind the obelisk is the Hôtel de la Marine. The Hotel de la Marine (also known hotel in the Garde-Meuble) is located in Paris, Place de la Concorde. It was built between 1757 and 1774. The facade was designed by Jacques-Ange Gabriel, prime architect of the King, author of the plans of the Place Louis XV (now the Place de la Concorde). The hotel itself was built to plans by Gabriel edited by Jacques-Germain Soufflot. Since 1789 it housed the Ministry of Naval Affairs. Nowadays the command office of the marine is located in this building. Bullet holes still visible from the final battle for Paris on 26 August 1944. You can see the dome of the Eglise de l'Assomption (Polski kościół). Vestige of the former (ancient)convent of the Girls of the Assumption, this church was built in the XVIIth century according to Charles Errard's drawings, architect of King Louis XIV. Since the middle of the XIXth century, it has been considered as the church of the Parisians of Polish origin." id="3770418280" latitude="48.865237" license="4" longitude="2.320754" nbComments="4" rank="14" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach hôteldelamarine placelouisxv jacquesangegabriel jacquesgermainsoufflot ministryofnavalaffairs commandofficeofthemarine hotelinthegardemeuble dome eglisedelassomptionpolskikościół vestigeoftheformerancientconventofthegirlsoftheassumption charleserrard kinglouisxivchurchoftheparisiansofpolishorigin" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3474/3770418280_de3840640e_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="252" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:15:56" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. On the left is one of Jacque Ignace Hittorff's statues - this one is the Statue de la ville de Bordeaux, one of eight that is at each corner of the Place creating an octogan. In the background is the Hotel Crillon. A fountain is on the right." id="3769614447" latitude="48.865237" license="4" longitude="2.320754" nbComments="2" rank="15" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap jacquesignacehittorff statue octagon corner hotelcrillon hoteldecrillon fountain iledefrance coach lantern lamppost statuedelavilledebordeaux" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3465/3769614447_ac4601fbe5_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="346" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:16:36" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. At the back of the square is on the left Hôtel de Crillon and on the right is the Hôtel de la Marine. The Hôtel de Crillon in Paris is one of the oldest luxury hotels in the world. It is located at the foot of the Champs-Élysées on the north side of Place de la Concorde. The five-star Crillon, with 103 guest rooms and 44 suites, occupies one of two identical stone buildings, divided by the rue Royale, constructed in 1758 under the auspices of architect Louis François Trouard as a result of a commission from King Louis XV. Initially, both structures were built as government offices, and the eastern one continues to this day as Headquarters of the Royale, the French Navy. In 1788, François-Félix-Dorothee Berton des Balbes, the Count of Crillon, acquired the hotel, only to have it confiscated shortly thereafter by the government of the French Revolution. It was eventually returned to the Count of Crillon's family who ran it until 1907, at which time it underwent a two-year-long refurbishing by the Société du Louvre under the supervision of architect Gabriel-Hippolyte Destailleur. Today, through the Concorde Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts, the Crillon is still part of the Société du Louvre whose shares are listed on the Paris Stock Exchange and is controlled by the Taittinger family holding company. The Hotel de la Marine (also known hotel in the Garde-Meuble) is located in Paris, Place de la Concorde. It was built between 1757 and 1774. The facade was designed by Jacques-Ange Gabriel, prime architect of the King, author of the plans of the Place Louis XV (now the Place de la Concorde). The hotel itself was built to plans by Gabriel edited by Jacques-Germain Soufflot. Since 1789 it housed the Ministry of Naval Affairs. Nowadays the command office of the marine is located in this building. Bullet holes still visible from the final battle for Paris on 26 August 1944." id="3770417124" latitude="48.865237" license="4" longitude="2.320754" nbComments="3" rank="16" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach lamppost lantern hôteldecrillon champselysees rueroyale louisfrancoistroucard kinglouisxv headquartersoftheroyalethefrenchnavy francoisfelixdorotheebertondesbalbes countofcrillon societedulouvre gabrielhippolytedestailleur concordehotelsresorts taittinger hôteldelamarine placelouisxv jacquesangegabriel jacquesgermainsoufflot ministryofnavalaffairs commandofficeofthemarine hotelinthegardemeuble" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2582/3770417124_58f4e14fb4_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="319" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:17:08" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations A fountain in the Place de la Concorde, created by Jacques Ignace Hittorff in 1836. Hittorfff was entrusted with redesigning the Place de la Concorde in 1833. The fountain is the Fontaine des Mers. One of the two Fontaines de la Concorde. The Maritime Fountain, to the south, closer to the River Seine, represents the maritime spirit of France. Large semi-nude figures supporting the vasque represent the Mediterranean Sea and the Atlantic Ocean. Other figures beneath the vasque represent the industries of the sea; Coral, Fish, Shells and Pearls. [4] The figures are seated in the prow of a ship, the symbol of the City of Paris, and they are surrounded by dolphins spraying water through their nostrils. Above the vasque, supporting the mushroom-shaped cap, are figures representing the spirits of Maritime Navigation, Astronomy and Commerce. Next to them are swans which spout water into the basin below. In the basin, tritons and nereids hold fish which spout water upwards to the rim of the vasque. The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. On the left is the Hôtel de Crillon. The Hôtel de Crillon in Paris is one of the oldest luxury hotels in the world. It is located at the foot of the Champs-Élysées on the north side of Place de la Concorde. The five-star Crillon, with 103 guest rooms and 44 suites, occupies one of two identical stone buildings, divided by the rue Royale, constructed in 1758 under the auspices of architect Louis François Trouard as a result of a commission from King Louis XV. Initially, both structures were built as government offices, and the eastern one continues to this day as Headquarters of the Royale, the French Navy. In 1788, François-Félix-Dorothee Berton des Balbes, the Count of Crillon, acquired the hotel, only to have it confiscated shortly thereafter by the government of the French Revolution. It was eventually returned to the Count of Crillon's family who ran it until 1907, at which time it underwent a two-year-long refurbishing by the Société du Louvre under the supervision of architect Gabriel-Hippolyte Destailleur. Today, through the Concorde Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts, the Crillon is still part of the Société du Louvre whose shares are listed on the Paris Stock Exchange and is controlled by the Taittinger family holding company." id="4942487468" latitude="48.864926" license="4" longitude="2.320615" nbComments="0" rank="17" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday fountain jacquesignacehittorff iledefrance coach obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap fontainedesmers fontainesdelaconcorde hôteldecrillon champselysees rueroyale louisfrancoistroucard kinglouisxv headquartersoftheroyalethefrenchnavy francoisfelixdorotheebertondesbalbes countofcrillon societedulouvre gabrielhippolytedestailleur concordehotelsresorts taittinger themaritimefountain coral fish shells pearls" title="Fontaine des Mers and Luxor Obelisk - Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4073/4942487468_453a3fd939_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="465" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-12 13:25:43" description="&lt;b&gt;Paris, France&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;Place de La Concorde&lt;/i&gt; Enquanto o &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n3to&quot;&gt;neto&lt;/a&gt; enchia o meu saco ontem, dei um trato nessa aí... Place de la Concorde, Paris, onde a Maria Antonieta perdeu a cabeça :) While &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/n3to&quot;&gt;neto&lt;/a&gt; was annoying me yesterday, I made this one... Place de la Concorde, Paris, where Marie Antoinette lost her head :)" id="418998990" latitude="48.865215" license="3" longitude="2.32202" nbComments="26" rank="18" tags="paris place concorde france europe guillotine obelisk luxor danorbit geotagged blood trip vacation fun lovely flickr" title="Where's the guillotine?" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/185/418998990_3cbfc70fdd_b.jpg" username="danorbit." views="1095" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-12-08 11:52:16" description="Paris" id="8349588302" latitude="48.866333" license="1" longitude="2.322333" nbComments="0" rank="19" tags="bigwheel bus capital cars champselysees chocolate elf expensive ferriswheel france globalcity gnome hat hats îledefrance lavillelumière me mercedes northfrance obelisk obeliskofluxor paname paris placedelaconcorde publicsquare reflection selfportrait shop silvia square tourist wheel" title="Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8468/8349588302_3129fd1462_b.jpg" username="DG Jones" views="26" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 11:49:34" description="Views of Place de la Concorde from the Seine. Can't see much as was on the boat on the river. It was three days before Bastille Day, and they were preparing the square for the celebrations. Built by King Louis XV in the 18th century is one of Paris's most famous squares, This is also the spot were King Louis XVI and Queen Marie Antoinette were beheaded in 1793. The square used to be called Place de la Louis XV but was renamed during the revolution. The Place was designed by Ange-Jacques Gabriel in 1755 as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées to the west and the Tuileries Gardens to the east. Filled with statues and fountains, the area was named Place Louis XV to honor the king at that time. The square showcased an equestrian statue of the king, which had been commissioned in 1748 by the city of Paris, sculpted mostly by Edmé Bouchardon, and completed by Jean-Baptiste Pigalle after the death of Bouchardon. At the north end, two magnificent identical stone buildings were constructed. Separated by the rue Royale, these structures remain among the best examples of Louis XV style architecture. Initially, the eastern building served as the French Naval Ministry. Shortly after its construction, the western building became the opulent home of the Duc d'Aumont. It was later purchased by the Comte de Crillon, whose family resided there until 1907. The famous luxury hôtel which currently occupies the building took its name from its previous owners. The Hôtel de Crillon served as the headquarters of the occupying German army during World War II. During the French Revolution the statue of Louis XV of France was torn down and the area renamed &amp;quot;Place de la Révolution&amp;quot;. The new revolutionary government erected the guillotine in the square, and it was here that King Louis XVI was executed on January 21, 1793. Other important figures guillotined on the site, often in front of cheering crowds, were Queen Marie Antoinette, Princess Élisabeth of France, Charlotte Corday, Madame du Barry, Georges Danton, Camille Desmoulins, Antoine Lavoisier, Maximilien Robespierre, Louis de Saint-Just and Olympe de Gouge. The guillotine was most active during the &amp;quot;Reign of Terror&amp;quot;, in the summer of 1794, when in a single month more than 1,300 people were executed. A year later, when the revolution was taking a more moderate course, the guillotine was removed from the square. The Fountain of River Commerce and Navigation, one of the two Fontaines de la Concorde (1840) on the Place de la Concorde. Behind: the Hôtel de Crillon; to the left: the embassy of the United States of America. Execution of Louis XVI in the then Place de la Révolution. The empty pedestal in front of him had supported a statue of his grandfather, Louis XV, torn down during one of the many revolutionary riots. The square was then renamed Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795–1799) as a symbolic gesture of reconciliation after the turmoil of the French Revolution. It underwent a series of name changes in the nineteenth century, but the city eventually settled on Place de la Concorde. Several boats below the square on the Seine. Can see the Luxor Obelisk from here. The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="4911322640" latitude="48.86404" license="4" longitude="2.319509" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="paris riverseine france iledefrance bateauxmouches boat boattrip rivercruise placedelaconcorde kinglouisxv louisxv kinglouisxvi louisxvi queenmarieantoinette marieantoinette beheaded placedelalouisxv placedelarevolution guillotine reignofterror trees boats obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap" title="Place de la Concorde from the Seine- boats" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4080/4911322640_9d81190deb_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="613" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 11:49:41" description="Views of Place de la Concorde from the Seine. Can't see much as was on the boat on the river. It was three days before Bastille Day, and they were preparing the square for the celebrations. Built by King Louis XV in the 18th century is one of Paris's most famous squares, This is also the spot were King Louis XVI and Queen Marie Antoinette were beheaded in 1793. The square used to be called Place de la Louis XV but was renamed during the revolution. The Place was designed by Ange-Jacques Gabriel in 1755 as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées to the west and the Tuileries Gardens to the east. Filled with statues and fountains, the area was named Place Louis XV to honor the king at that time. The square showcased an equestrian statue of the king, which had been commissioned in 1748 by the city of Paris, sculpted mostly by Edmé Bouchardon, and completed by Jean-Baptiste Pigalle after the death of Bouchardon. At the north end, two magnificent identical stone buildings were constructed. Separated by the rue Royale, these structures remain among the best examples of Louis XV style architecture. Initially, the eastern building served as the French Naval Ministry. Shortly after its construction, the western building became the opulent home of the Duc d'Aumont. It was later purchased by the Comte de Crillon, whose family resided there until 1907. The famous luxury hôtel which currently occupies the building took its name from its previous owners. The Hôtel de Crillon served as the headquarters of the occupying German army during World War II. During the French Revolution the statue of Louis XV of France was torn down and the area renamed &amp;quot;Place de la Révolution&amp;quot;. The new revolutionary government erected the guillotine in the square, and it was here that King Louis XVI was executed on January 21, 1793. Other important figures guillotined on the site, often in front of cheering crowds, were Queen Marie Antoinette, Princess Élisabeth of France, Charlotte Corday, Madame du Barry, Georges Danton, Camille Desmoulins, Antoine Lavoisier, Maximilien Robespierre, Louis de Saint-Just and Olympe de Gouge. The guillotine was most active during the &amp;quot;Reign of Terror&amp;quot;, in the summer of 1794, when in a single month more than 1,300 people were executed. A year later, when the revolution was taking a more moderate course, the guillotine was removed from the square. The Fountain of River Commerce and Navigation, one of the two Fontaines de la Concorde (1840) on the Place de la Concorde. Behind: the Hôtel de Crillon; to the left: the embassy of the United States of America. Execution of Louis XVI in the then Place de la Révolution. The empty pedestal in front of him had supported a statue of his grandfather, Louis XV, torn down during one of the many revolutionary riots. The square was then renamed Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795–1799) as a symbolic gesture of reconciliation after the turmoil of the French Revolution. It underwent a series of name changes in the nineteenth century, but the city eventually settled on Place de la Concorde. Several boats below the square on the Seine." id="4910721979" latitude="48.86404" license="4" longitude="2.319509" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="paris riverseine france iledefrance bateauxmouches boat boattrip rivercruise placedelaconcorde kinglouisxv louisxv kinglouisxvi louisxvi queenmarieantoinette marieantoinette beheaded placedelalouisxv placedelarevolution guillotine reignofterror trees boats obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap" title="Place de la Concorde from the Seine - boats" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4121/4910721979_b383c19eee_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="233" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 11:48:53" description="Views of Place de la Concorde from the Seine. Can't see much as was on the boat on the river. It was three days before Bastille Day, and they were preparing the square for the celebrations. Built by King Louis XV in the 18th century is one of Paris's most famous squares, This is also the spot were King Louis XVI and Queen Marie Antoinette were beheaded in 1793. The square used to be called Place de la Louis XV but was renamed during the revolution. The Place was designed by Ange-Jacques Gabriel in 1755 as a moat-skirted octagon between the Champs-Élysées to the west and the Tuileries Gardens to the east. Filled with statues and fountains, the area was named Place Louis XV to honor the king at that time. The square showcased an equestrian statue of the king, which had been commissioned in 1748 by the city of Paris, sculpted mostly by Edmé Bouchardon, and completed by Jean-Baptiste Pigalle after the death of Bouchardon. At the north end, two magnificent identical stone buildings were constructed. Separated by the rue Royale, these structures remain among the best examples of Louis XV style architecture. Initially, the eastern building served as the French Naval Ministry. Shortly after its construction, the western building became the opulent home of the Duc d'Aumont. It was later purchased by the Comte de Crillon, whose family resided there until 1907. The famous luxury hôtel which currently occupies the building took its name from its previous owners. The Hôtel de Crillon served as the headquarters of the occupying German army during World War II. During the French Revolution the statue of Louis XV of France was torn down and the area renamed &amp;quot;Place de la Révolution&amp;quot;. The new revolutionary government erected the guillotine in the square, and it was here that King Louis XVI was executed on January 21, 1793. Other important figures guillotined on the site, often in front of cheering crowds, were Queen Marie Antoinette, Princess Élisabeth of France, Charlotte Corday, Madame du Barry, Georges Danton, Camille Desmoulins, Antoine Lavoisier, Maximilien Robespierre, Louis de Saint-Just and Olympe de Gouge. The guillotine was most active during the &amp;quot;Reign of Terror&amp;quot;, in the summer of 1794, when in a single month more than 1,300 people were executed. A year later, when the revolution was taking a more moderate course, the guillotine was removed from the square. The Fountain of River Commerce and Navigation, one of the two Fontaines de la Concorde (1840) on the Place de la Concorde. Behind: the Hôtel de Crillon; to the left: the embassy of the United States of America. Execution of Louis XVI in the then Place de la Révolution. The empty pedestal in front of him had supported a statue of his grandfather, Louis XV, torn down during one of the many revolutionary riots. The square was then renamed Place de la Concorde under the Directory (1795–1799) as a symbolic gesture of reconciliation after the turmoil of the French Revolution. It underwent a series of name changes in the nineteenth century, but the city eventually settled on Place de la Concorde. Several boats below the square on the Seine. Can see the Luxor Obelisk. The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998." id="4911318360" latitude="48.86404" license="4" longitude="2.319509" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="paris riverseine france iledefrance bateauxmouches boat boattrip rivercruise placedelaconcorde kinglouisxv louisxv kinglouisxvi louisxvi queenmarieantoinette marieantoinette beheaded placedelalouisxv placedelarevolution guillotine reignofterror trees boats obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap" title="Place de la Concorde from the Seine" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4118/4911318360_5f783a63e1_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="310" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-26 15:20:09" description="View down the Champs Elysee with the Place de la Concorde (and 3,300 year old Luxor Obelisk) in the foreground. The Arc de Triomphe is in the background. Taken from Tuileries Park, outside the front of the Louvre. Paris, France." id="958869385" latitude="48.862371" license="3" longitude="2.330904" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde concorde champselysee champs elysee arcdetriomphe arc triomphe tuileries" title="Champs Elysee" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1246/958869385_f8a6296306_b.jpg" username="davidagalvan" views="1339" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-07-03 13:37:09" description="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France. Photographed on 3 July 2010." id="4866852557" latitude="48.8655" license="1" longitude="2.3211" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="luxorobelisk placedelaconcorde paris france geocode:accuracy=200meters geocode:method=googleearth geo:country=france" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4102/4866852557_ac2384c875_b.jpg" username="Arthur Chapman" views="57" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-10-03 11:26:36" description="The hieroglyphics on the obelisk relate to the reign of the Ramses II, Paris; October 2008 Canon 30D" id="3509169400" latitude="48.865498" license="3" longitude="2.321119" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="obelisk hieroglyphs hieroglyphics luxor egypt ramses ii rameses place dela concorde assemblée nationale national assembly egyptian paris 巴黎 パリ parigi france 法国 frankreich 5photosaday" title="Hieroglyphs" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3398/3509169400_1eda76e800_b.jpg" username="█ Slices of Light █▀ ▀ ▀" views="401" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-08-14 22:16:47" description="Place de la Concorde Paris" id="5038781962" latitude="48.865519" license="1" longitude="2.321065" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="frankreich france paris obelisk luxor place concorde night nacht dunkel" title="Obélisque de Louxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4129/5038781962_7dcaf17a46_b.jpg" username="Morku" views="95" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-10 13:54:50" description="Paris anaglyph red/cyan Place de Concorde Obelisk from Luxor" id="7970684004" latitude="48.865491" license="3" longitude="2.32113" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="obelisk placedelaconcorde paris parijs 3d stereo anaglyph luxor" title="Obelisk Paris 3D" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8460/7970684004_3942500d6e_b.jpg" username="wim hoppenbrouwers" views="170" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-06 20:34:59" description="" id="2511526227" latitude="48.865491" license="3" longitude="2.321087" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="paris france obelisk placedelaconcorde needle cleopatras egyptian" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2004/2511526227_85c8a900f0_b.jpg" username="Drumaboy" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-05-06 20:35:52" description="I like the phosphorescent glow of the tip the camera captured here. It was a very beautiful, hot day as the blue sky suggests." id="2511525915" latitude="48.865491" license="3" longitude="2.321087" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="paris france obelisk placedelaconcorde egyptian needle glint gold" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3018/2511525915_e32f318b10_b.jpg" username="Drumaboy" views="46" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-03 09:38:24" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&lt;/a&gt; Photo used with permission here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gogobot.com/place_de_la_concorde_la-paris-attraction&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.gogobot.com/place_de_la_concorde_la-paris-attraction&lt;/a&gt;" id="167788403" latitude="48.865487" license="5" longitude="2.321119" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="swflsceuropeantour06 travel traveling tour southwestfloridasymphonychorus 2006 europe tourism placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor paris france june2006 swflsc 606 europeantour2006 touris summer june" title="The Obelisk of Luxor in Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/46/167788403_7912f3ef35_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="36" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-05-08 12:24:20" description="Egyptian obelisk decorated with hieroglyphics exalting the reign of the pharaoh Ramesses II. It once marked the entrance to the Luxor Temple. The viceroy of Egypt, Mehemet Ali, presented the 3,300-year-old Luxor Obelisk to France in 1829. King Louis-Philippe had it placed in the centre of Place de la Concorde in 1833. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/sebastiagiralt/506156256/&quot;&gt;Do you want to see the original place?&lt;/a&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&lt;/a&gt;" id="506153239" latitude="48.865473" license="1" longitude="2.32113" nbComments="1" rank="31" tags="paris obelisc obelisco obelisk ramses ramesses luxor concorde plaça plaza square" title="Obelisc, Place de la Concorde, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/219/506153239_80e7bb6993_b.jpg" username="Sebastià Giralt" views="247" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-11 14:17:42" description="one of the major public areas in Paris. Here they were preparing for the Bastille Day celebrations The Luxor Obelisk is in the middle of Place de la Concorde, standing where the guillotine used to be in the French Revolution The Luxor Obelisk is a 23 metres high Egyptian obelisk standing at the centre of the Place de la Concorde in Paris, France. It was originally located at the entrance to the Luxor Temple, in Egypt. In 1829 the Ottoman viceroy of Egypt, Mehmet Ali, offered two obelisks to France from the entrance of the Luxor Temple. The obelisk now in Paris arrived in 1833, and three years later in 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed at the centre of the Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the revolution. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology of the period. The French President (Francois Mitterrand) of the early 1990s gave the second obelisk back to Egypt. The obelisk is made of red granite. It is decorated with hieroglyphics of the reign of the Pharaoh Ramses II. Missing it's cap (possibly stolen in the 6th century BC), the French Government added a gold-leafed pyramid to the top of the obelisk in 1998. Building behind is the Hôtel de Crillon. The Hôtel de Crillon in Paris is one of the oldest luxury hotels in the world. It is located at the foot of the Champs-Élysées on the north side of Place de la Concorde. The five-star Crillon, with 103 guest rooms and 44 suites, occupies one of two identical stone buildings, divided by the rue Royale, constructed in 1758 under the auspices of architect Louis François Trouard as a result of a commission from King Louis XV. Initially, both structures were built as government offices, and the eastern one continues to this day as Headquarters of the Royale, the French Navy. In 1788, François-Félix-Dorothee Berton des Balbes, the Count of Crillon, acquired the hotel, only to have it confiscated shortly thereafter by the government of the French Revolution. It was eventually returned to the Count of Crillon's family who ran it until 1907, at which time it underwent a two-year-long refurbishing by the Société du Louvre under the supervision of architect Gabriel-Hippolyte Destailleur. Today, through the Concorde Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts, the Crillon is still part of the Société du Louvre whose shares are listed on the Paris Stock Exchange and is controlled by the Taittinger family holding company." id="3769623099" latitude="48.865498" license="4" longitude="2.321033" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde bastilleday obelisk parisneedle cleopatrasneedle ramassesii luxorobelisk egypt egyptianobelisk luxortemple ottomanempire ottomanviceroyofegypt mehmetali kinglouisphilippe guillotine revolution frenchrevolution presidentfrancoismitterand redgranitecolumn hieroglyphics ramsesii pharaohramsesii cap goldleafedpyramidcap iledefrance coach hôteldecrillon champselysees rueroyale louisfrancoistroucard kinglouisxv headquartersoftheroyalethefrenchnavy francoisfelixdorotheebertondesbalbes countofcrillon societedulouvre gabrielhippolytedestailleur concordehotelsresorts taittinger" title="Luxor Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2634/3769623099_8b8ba3cf8b_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="280" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-23 16:07:00" description="See detail of authentic egyptian lettering." id="383381806" latitude="48.865477" license="2" longitude="2.321038" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="egypt obelisk luxor france europe concorde paris french monument ancient egyptian tall" title="Obelisk in Place de Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/136/383381806_170b884811_b.jpg" username="The Adventures of Kristin &amp; Adam" views="76" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-06-14 15:35:27" description="" id="4769638437" latitude="48.865463" license="1" longitude="2.321166" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="paris07palaisbourbon îledefrance france fr canoneos7d canon70200mmf28l paris" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4134/4769638437_459724ca4e_b.jpg" username="nathangibbs" views="30" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-10-03 16:08:39" description="Obelisk of Luxor in the Place de la Concorde" id="71410426" latitude="48.865497" license="3" longitude="2.321005" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="paris placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor france europe placeduconcorde obelisk panorama" title="Panorama - Paris 2" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/34/71410426_2a41976fca_b.jpg" username="zemistor" views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-01-23 09:59:18" description="This obelisk was one of three that &amp;quot;protected&amp;quot; the pyramid of Luxor in Egypt. The first one (the one you are looking at) was given to France, second given to England, and third given to the U.S. (in Central Park). While in transport the tip broke off, so they replaced it with a gold." id="372422452" latitude="48.865434" license="2" longitude="2.321087" nbComments="1" rank="36" tags="obelisk luxor eiffel eiffeltower placedelaconcorde concorde paris france monument gold antiquities egypt pillar longer taller" title="Obelisk and Eiffel Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/132/372422452_cb4bb4df48_b.jpg" username="The Adventures of Kristin &amp; Adam" views="302" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-05-26 16:33:46" description="someday remind me how i've come to believe this tale Just playing with Nik's solarization tweak. And listening to Film School." id="7411335824" latitude="48.865431" license="1" longitude="2.321092" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="eiffeltower paris luxorobelisk obélisquedelouxor solarized placedelaconcorde solarization luxor egypt" title="Breet" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7120/7411335824_384e7cc4f9_b.jpg" username="Jason OX4" views="65" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-06-16 15:55:39" description="this was originally located at the entrance of the Luxor Temple in Egypt, and now stands at the center of the Place de la Concorde in Paris. Its 3,300 years old...impressive" id="4732510440" latitude="48.865434" license="1" longitude="2.321151" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="europe france paris travel travelling obélisquedelouxor luxorobelisk" title="Obélisque de Louxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1397/4732510440_cb1750c222_b.jpg" username="1yen" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-04-23 02:29:45" description="" id="289747929" latitude="48.865434" license="3" longitude="2.321167" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="europe travel paris obelisk placedelaconcorde" title="Luxor Obelisk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/101/289747929_529272ee2b_b.jpg" username="IceNineJon" views="107" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-11-20 11:03:45" description="" id="5200534851" latitude="48.865438" license="4" longitude="2.321183" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="france geography culture" title="Luxor Obelisk in the Place de la Concorde, Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4083/5200534851_992c667a91_b.jpg" username="geographyalltheway.com" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-04-26 11:59:06" description="The center of Place de la Concorde is occupied by a giant Egyptian obelisk decorated with hieroglyphics exalting the reign of the pharaoh Ramses II. It is one of two the Egyptian government gave to the French in the nineteenth century. The other one stayed in Egypt, too difficult and heavy to move to France with the technology at that time. The obelisk once marked the entrance to the Luxor Temple. The viceroy of Egypt, Mehemet Ali, offered the 3,300-year-old Luxor Obelisk to France in 1831. The obelisk arrived in Paris on December 21, 1833. Three years later, on October 25, 1836, King Louis-Philippe had it placed in the centre of Place de la Concorde, where a guillotine used to stand during the Revolution." id="2841419760" latitude="48.865695" license="6" longitude="2.321092" nbComments="0" rank="41" tags="parisfranceapril2008 paris eu europe european travel museum" title="Obelisk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3140/2841419760_99c99000c0_b.jpg" username="OliverN5" views="129" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-03-03 20:35:38" description="Equirectangular panorama built from 32 pictures (EXIF data from first the one). See also its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gadl/414906241/&quot;&gt;stereographic projection&lt;/a&gt;. More about this place on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&quot;&gt;wikipiedia&lt;/a&gt;" id="414906232" latitude="48.865516" license="5" longitude="2.320953" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="paris 75008 france placedelaconcorde place concorde fontaine fountain obélisque champsélysées champs élysées madeleine assemblénationale toureiffel nuit night longexposure panorama hugin enblend 360° 360°x180° equirectangular 21 geotagged geo:tool=gmif geo:lat=48865516 geo:lon=2320953 eiffel tour tower eiffeltower obelisk hôteldecrillon" title="Obélisque de Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/145/414906232_830d6537ff_b.jpg" username="gadl" views="2216" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-08-11 14:01:47" description="" id="2783286769" latitude="48.865448" license="1" longitude="2.321237" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="paris parís francia france obélisque obelisco louxor luxor obelisk" title="L'Obélisque de Louxor, place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3109/2783286769_3ae46a4767_b.jpg" username="SamwiseGamgee69" views="207" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:39:30" description="" id="3971607594" latitude="48.865555" license="4" longitude="2.321305" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="DSCN1026" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3459/3971607594_2b9819f43a_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:40:14" description="" id="3970839875" latitude="48.865416" license="4" longitude="2.321249" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="IMG_8739" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2618/3970839875_3d80fdfd38_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:39:33" description="" id="3970838899" latitude="48.865611" license="4" longitude="2.321333" nbComments="0" rank="46" tags="parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="IMG_8738" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3520/3970838899_8163a1cd9d_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="6" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-06-03 09:40:43" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Place_de_la_Concorde&lt;/a&gt; Photo used with permission here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gogobot.com/place_de_la_concorde_la-paris-attraction&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.gogobot.com/place_de_la_concorde_la-paris-attraction&lt;/a&gt;" id="167788849" latitude="48.865462" license="5" longitude="2.321355" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="swflsceuropeantour06 travel traveling tour southwestfloridasymphonychorus 2006 europe tourism placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor paris france june2006 swflsc 606 europeantour2006 touris summer june" title="The Obelisk of Luxor in Place de la Concorde, Paris, France" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/71/167788849_df8243db79_b.jpg" username="nikoretro" views="32" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-08-09 10:22:03" description="Place de la Concorde Paris" id="6298494825" latitude="48.8653" license="6" longitude="2.321017" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="" title="The Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6216/6298494825_8ceb7b3f94_b.jpg" username="alex hanoko" views="59" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-22 16:09:03" description="" id="1595150484" latitude="48.865776" license="1" longitude="2.321317" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="paris france placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor" title="Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2203/1595150484_6b9c31773d_b.jpg" username="Steve and Sara" views="42" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-26 03:16:34" description="" id="4609700056" latitude="48.865794" license="5" longitude="2.321398" nbComments="0" rank="50" tags="phototour placedelaconcorde eiffeltower luxorobelisk paris afsvrzoomnikkor70200mmf28gifed" title="Paris 2010 Day 2 - 94" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1293/4609700056_b9c5047c01_b.jpg" username="evocateur" views="54" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:39:18" description="" id="3971605776" latitude="48.865638" license="4" longitude="2.321583" nbComments="0" rank="51" tags="parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="IMG_8737" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3461/3971605776_15f0c349cb_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-09-20 18:09:54" description="in the Place de la Concorde" id="293995181" latitude="48.865099" license="1" longitude="2.320926" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="paris placedelaconcorde obelisquedeluxor obelisk" title="obelisque de luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/99/293995181_21a62836bf_b.jpg" username="MsNina" views="13" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:41:58" description="" id="3970841485" latitude="48.865083" license="4" longitude="2.320944" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="IMG_8742" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3470/3970841485_d8bfeb427f_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:46:12" description="" id="3970850953" latitude="48.865111" license="4" longitude="2.320833" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="IMG_8745" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2585/3970850953_cce3ab897c_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-22 16:00:40" description="Obelisk, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France. Originally from Luxor, Egypt." id="2683052468" latitude="48.865978" license="3" longitude="2.321478" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="obelisk paris france concorde egypt luxor" title="Obelisk, Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3187/2683052468_be27370835_b.jpg" username="john_s_eddie" views="60" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-21 17:19:27" description="" id="3383485352" latitude="48.865872" license="1" longitude="2.320636" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="luxorobelisk monument placedelaconcorde paris france" title="Luxor Obelisk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3659/3383485352_e32350e52e_b.jpg" username="The Wilky Bar Kid" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:45:49" description="" id="3971619256" latitude="48.865027" license="4" longitude="2.320888" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisqueeiffeltowertour" title="IMG_8744" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3460/3971619256_e26518d907_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-06-05 13:35:40" description="In the Place de la Concorde. 8th arrondissement, Paris, France" id="4051465280" latitude="48.866112" license="1" longitude="2.32128" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="paris france hittorf fountain luxor obelisk place de la concorde" title="Hittorf's fountain and Luxor Obelisk" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2518/4051465280_cf46b6e7e4_b.jpg" username="www78" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:44:01" description="" id="3970845159" latitude="48.864944" license="4" longitude="2.320972" nbComments="0" rank="59" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="DSCN1030" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2591/3970845159_e2d3a41d56_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:42:00" description="" id="3970843607" latitude="48.864941" license="4" longitude="2.320961" nbComments="0" rank="60" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="DSCN1028" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2431/3970843607_d816a5a2a7_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:44:27" description="" id="3971616436" latitude="48.86493" license="4" longitude="2.32083" nbComments="0" rank="61" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="DSCN1031" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2580/3971616436_ef3a5de79b_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:38:03" description="" id="3970835753" latitude="48.865383" license="4" longitude="2.321811" nbComments="0" rank="62" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisqueeiffeltowertour" title="DSCN1025" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3476/3970835753_59cc61d17d_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-11-21 14:47:50" description="" id="8270736669" latitude="48.865928" license="2" longitude="2.320432" nbComments="0" rank="63" tags="france paris eurotrip placedelaconcorde concorde moon obélisquedelouxor luxor obelisk" title="Obelisk and moon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8493/8270736669_6d346a7e9d_b.jpg" username="Scott SM" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-11-21 14:50:51" description="The obelisk is from Luxor Temple in Luxor." id="8270735859" latitude="48.865928" license="2" longitude="2.320432" nbComments="0" rank="64" tags="france paris eurotrip placedelaconcorde concorde ferris wheel ferriswheel obélisquedelouxor luxor obelisk" title="Obelisk and wheel" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8073/8270735859_e2e1a74330_b.jpg" username="Scott SM" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-11-08 06:16:24" description="" id="8224883075" latitude="48.86626" license="1" longitude="2.320582" nbComments="0" rank="65" tags="paris placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor" title="Place de la Concorde, Obelisk of Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8062/8224883075_0f3dd2fdb4_b.jpg" username="Talie" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:36:17" description="" id="3971603608" latitude="48.865277" license="4" longitude="2.322027" nbComments="0" rank="66" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisqueeiffeltowertour" title="IMG_8733" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2625/3971603608_ba9fc90506_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="4" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:35:22" description="" id="3971602810" latitude="48.865236" license="4" longitude="2.322119" nbComments="0" rank="67" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcordeobelisque" title="DSCN1024" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2611/3971602810_f2754d94cd_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-05-26 01:18:34" description="This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;time=&amp;amp;date=&amp;amp;ttype=&amp;amp;q=place+de+la+concorde,+Paris,+France&amp;amp;sll=48.034019,3.955078&amp;amp;sspn=3.658673,7.514648&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=48.865463,2.321184&amp;amp;spn=0.003515,0.007339&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=17&amp;amp;om=1&quot;&gt;Place de la Concorde&lt;/a&gt;. During the French Revolution this was called the Place de la Révolution after King Louis XVI was executed here in 1793. The obelisk in the center of the photo is a 3500 year-old structure that came from the entrance of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/baggis/232388463/&quot;&gt;Luxor&lt;/a&gt; Temple. It's counterpart still stands there. Muhammad Ali, the viceroy of Egypt at the time, &amp;quot;offered&amp;quot; the obelisk to France in 1831. King Louis-Philippe had the obelisk placed here in the Place de la Concorde in 1836. The gold cap on the obelisk was still intact. The fountain to the left was constructed in the north end of the square and had recently been a victim of soap vandalism. Suds were everywhere. To the right, not seen in the photo, is the US Embassy. The gold dome seen in the far background is Les Invalides. This is where old French veterans can live after retirement. Napoleon's tomb is also located under this dome." id="2102644210" latitude="48.865836" license="2" longitude="2.322363" nbComments="0" rank="68" tags="europe france paris placedelaconcorde placedelarévolution placedelarevolution luxorobelisque luxorobelisk obelisque obelisk gold cap fountain soap suds lesinvalides invalides dome rueroyale rue street cars" title="Paris" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2342/2102644210_11f6431b05_b.jpg" username="Travis S." views="125" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-14 20:41:26" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:7942671068&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="7942671068" latitude="48.864269" license="1" longitude="2.320712" nbComments="0" rank="69" tags="paris iledefrance place concorde obélisque louxor obelisk luxor monument egyptien egyptian geo:lat=48864269 geo:lon=2320712 geotagged" title="Obélisque de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8300/7942671068_6b2a72feae_b.jpg" username="Sam Nimitz" views="20" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-14 20:41:06" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:7942668754&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="7942668754" latitude="48.864269" license="1" longitude="2.320712" nbComments="0" rank="70" tags="paris iledefrance place concorde monument obélisque louxor obelisk luxor egyptien egyptian geo:lat=4886426912790379 geo:lon=23207121189880127 geotagged" title="Place de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8182/7942668754_61252efd77_b.jpg" username="Sam Nimitz" views="11" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-02 15:33:57" description="" id="3970830387" latitude="48.865063" license="4" longitude="2.322569" nbComments="0" rank="71" tags="parisfranceseptember parisfranceseptemberobeliskluxorplacedelaconcorde" title="DSCN1022" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2464/3970830387_60397795f8_b.jpg" username="marko8904" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-26 03:08:34" description="" id="4609090519" latitude="48.865221" license="5" longitude="2.32272" nbComments="0" rank="72" tags="jardindestuileries phototour luxorobelisk paris afsvrzoomnikkor70200mmf28gifed" title="Paris 2010 Day 2 - 90" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1388/4609090519_fbce1faec6_b.jpg" username="evocateur" views="67" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-03-24 08:22:25" description="In Paris, the Banks of the Seine is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/600&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage site&lt;/a&gt;." id="135373725" latitude="48.865505" license="3" longitude="2.322814" nbComments="0" rank="73" tags="paris france europe iledefrance placedelaconcorde obeliskofluxor luxor obelisk eiffeltower tower eiffel obélisquedeluxor obélisque geo:lat=48865505 geo:lon=2322814 worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Obélisque de Luxor" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/56/135373725_bc7bfff533_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="262" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-03-04 17:07:52" description="L'Obélisque de Luxor et la Tour Eiffel" id="4662692508" latitude="48.865713" license="3" longitude="2.323173" nbComments="0" rank="74" tags="eiffeltower tower toureiffel latoureiffel obelisk obeliskofluxor obélisquedeluxor placedelaconcorde luxorobelisk paris france europe dopplr:explore=yfe1 worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite banksoftheseine" title="Place de La Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4024/4662692508_a6841e915c_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-06-14 20:46:53" description="&lt;a href=&quot;http://loc.alize.us/#/flickr:7942672582&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="7942672582" latitude="48.862575" license="1" longitude="2.319639" nbComments="0" rank="75" tags="paris iledefrance seine fleuve river pont bridge concorde obélisque louxor obelisk luxor monument egyptien egyptian noiretblanc blackandwhite geo:lat=4886257525592859 geo:lon=2319639661376982 geotagged" title="Pont de la Concorde" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8179/7942672582_907ae20e63_b.jpg" username="Sam Nimitz" views="14" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-04-04 12:07:11" description="This is the view looking west-by-north-west along l'Avenue des Champs-Élysées from le Jardin des Tuilleries. L'Obélisque de Louxor and l'Arc de Triomphe de l'Étoile are in the photo, as well as the Champs-Élysées." id="7145105473" latitude="48.862583" license="1" longitude="2.330142" nbComments="0" rank="76" tags="paris france îledefrance jardindestuilleries tuilleries garden champsélysées avenuedeschampsélysées arcdetriomphe arcdetriomphedelétoile obélisquedelouxor luxor obelisk arch fountains gardens tourists parisians cloudy clouds cloud sky" title="Le Jardin des Tuilleries" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7103/7145105473_45b15b4158_b.jpg" username="Dunnock_D" views="18" />
</photos>
