<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Royal Palace of Naples">

<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:38:34" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401323122" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="1" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3464/3401323122_f662e1bdac_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="158" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:26:46" description="Appartamento storico" id="3395345445" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="2" rank="2" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3650/3395345445_ebb3a6438d_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="154" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:54:52" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401366190" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="3" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3580/3401366190_f043af1699_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="282" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:55:04" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401369730" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="2" rank="4" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3645/3401369730_117535ccec_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="163" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:51:36" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400535251" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="5" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3593/3400535251_8c377b4645_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="208" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:01:27" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401391422" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="6" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3583/3401391422_09d157f0aa_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="167" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:56:52" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401373046" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="7" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3426/3401373046_15c0c6172c_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="343" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:07:25" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400609699" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="8" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples barocconapoletano" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3611/3400609699_25a2e82e11_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="217" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:10:14" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400613445" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="9" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3633/3400613445_48e6a2cee1_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="173" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:30:27" description="Appartamento storico" id="3395356493" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="10" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3618/3395356493_38014d1f9f_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="236" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:53:22" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400542743" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="11" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3602/3400542743_32da13b7ef_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="195" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:10:59" description="Appartamento storico" id="3401422936" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="12" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3448/3401422936_8ea9106fdf_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="183" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:33:55" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400506619" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="13" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3585/3400506619_ff3859aeb4_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="213" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:35:25" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400510465" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="14" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3661/3400510465_cce0e157df_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="231" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 12:04:04" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400600719" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="15" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3555/3400600719_28a401ef5b_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="174" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:27:45" description="Appartamento storico" id="3396161860" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="16" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3597/3396161860_aca8f2420f_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="134" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:42:03" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400527145" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="2" rank="17" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3585/3400527145_319e4ac2d9_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="138" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:40:17" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400523439" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="18" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3598/3400523439_a10092fd0f_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="184" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-28 11:58:36" description="Appartamento storico" id="3400569687" latitude="40.836387" license="5" longitude="14.249728" nbComments="1" rank="19" tags="napoli naples campania italia italy armandomancini royalpalaceofnaples" title="Napoli - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3631/3400569687_7194fb8e8a_b.jpg" username="Armando Mancini" views="135" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-12-21 11:52:33" description="" id="4209570380" latitude="40.836188" license="1" longitude="14.249353" nbComments="0" rank="20" tags="" title="Royal Palace of Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2574/4209570380_d93c7326c6_b.jpg" username="Pino Pinto" views="23" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:05" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento." id="7610159660" latitude="40.83693" license="4" longitude="14.249138" nbComments="0" rank="21" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace piazzatriesteetrento roundabout viasancarlo teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8150/7610159660_f887b50286_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="72" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:51:27" description="A quick look around Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples (before we had to get back on our coach). Banners on Teatro di San Carlo as seen in Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatro_di_San_Carlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Teatro di San Carlo&lt;/a&gt;. The Real Teatro di San Carlo (English: Royal Theatre of Saint Charles) is an opera house in Naples, Italy. It is the oldest continuously active such venue in Europe. Founded by the Bourbon Charles VII of Naples (Carlo VII in Italian) of the Spanish branch of the dynasty, the theatre was inaugurated on 4 November 1737 — the king's name day — with a performance of Domenico Sarro's Achille in Sciro, an opera based on the play by the famous poet and dramatist who went by the name of Metastasio. Sarro also conducted the orchestra in two ballets as intermezzi, created by Grossatesta. At the time, it was the largest opera house in the world, seating 3,300. Teatro di San Carlo 1737 Campagna Abbonamenti 2012 - 2013 Prenota il tuo viaggio nella musica Teatro di San Carlo 1737 Ticket campaign 2012 - 2013 Book your trip in music" id="7611090534" latitude="40.837215" license="4" longitude="14.249417" nbComments="0" rank="22" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea piazzatriesteetrento viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace arches teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii viasancarlo operahouse banner banners sign signs campagnaabbonamenti prenotailtuoviaggionellamusica ticketcampaign bookyourtripinmusic unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Teatro di San Carlo - banners - Campagna Abbonamenti" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8162/7611090534_5cd41f4625_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="64" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:51:33" description="A quick look around Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples (before we had to get back on our coach). Banners on Teatro di San Carlo as seen in Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatro_di_San_Carlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Teatro di San Carlo&lt;/a&gt;. The Real Teatro di San Carlo (English: Royal Theatre of Saint Charles) is an opera house in Naples, Italy. It is the oldest continuously active such venue in Europe. Founded by the Bourbon Charles VII of Naples (Carlo VII in Italian) of the Spanish branch of the dynasty, the theatre was inaugurated on 4 November 1737 — the king's name day — with a performance of Domenico Sarro's Achille in Sciro, an opera based on the play by the famous poet and dramatist who went by the name of Metastasio. Sarro also conducted the orchestra in two ballets as intermezzi, created by Grossatesta. At the time, it was the largest opera house in the world, seating 3,300. Teatro di San Carlo 1737 Stagione lirica e di balletto 2011-2012 Venerdi 13 luglio 2012 ore 20.30 (turno A) Pietro Mascagni Cavalleria Rusticana Teatro di San Carlo 1737 Opera and Ballet 2011-2012 Friday 13 July 2012 at 20.30 (session A) Pietro Mascagni Cavalleria Rusticana" id="7611093814" latitude="40.837215" license="4" longitude="14.249417" nbComments="0" rank="23" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea piazzatriesteetrento viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace arches teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii viasancarlo operahouse banner banners sign signs cavalleriarusticana pietromascagni stagioneliricaediballetto operaandballet unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Teatro di San Carlo - banners - Cavalleria Rusticana" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7112/7611093814_851f8b7923_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="63" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:51:34" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. Down here African and Asian men try to sell things like handbags, hats, umbrellas etc (probably counterfit). Next to the palace is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatro_di_San_Carlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Teatro di San Carlo&lt;/a&gt;. The Real Teatro di San Carlo (English: Royal Theatre of Saint Charles) is an opera house in Naples, Italy. It is the oldest continuously active such venue in Europe. Founded by the Bourbon Charles VII of Naples (Carlo VII in Italian) of the Spanish branch of the dynasty, the theatre was inaugurated on 4 November 1737 — the king's name day — with a performance of Domenico Sarro's Achille in Sciro, an opera based on the play by the famous poet and dramatist who went by the name of Metastasio. Sarro also conducted the orchestra in two ballets as intermezzi, created by Grossatesta. At the time, it was the largest opera house in the world, seating 3,300." id="7610155930" latitude="40.83758" license="4" longitude="14.249471" nbComments="0" rank="24" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace arches teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii viasancarlo operahouse unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Teatro di San Carlo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8165/7610155930_b876f0a91c_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="52" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:32" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento). The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city." id="7610173324" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="25" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach gigliotravel piazzatriesteetrento roundabout galleriaumbertoi column columns viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8010/7610173324_69c52a483b_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="57" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:18" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. Fountain in the middle of the piazza." id="7610166678" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="26" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace piazzatriesteetrento fountain roundabout viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - fountain" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8147/7610166678_28423848f9_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="92" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:49" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento). The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento." id="7610183366" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="27" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach gigliotravel piazzatriesteetrento roundabout viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7122/7610183366_b7ef380a34_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="36" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:38" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento). The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. The church is the Chiesa S. Ferdinando. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Ferdinando_(Naples)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;San Ferdinando (Naples)&lt;/a&gt; Shops below these buildings." id="7610176614" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="28" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach gigliotravel piazzatriesteetrento roundabout chiesasferdinando fountain shutter shutters balcony balconies churchofsanferdinando viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Chiesa S. Ferdinando" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7130/7610176614_4b2071c114_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="41" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:12" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. Fountain in the middle of the piazza." id="7610163014" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="29" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach piazzatriesteetrento fountain roundabout viasancarlo piazzadelplebiscito unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - fountain" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8433/7610163014_22441f1275_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="101" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:51:00" description="A quick look around Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples (before we had to get back on our coach). HD Video clip of Piazza Trieste e Trento." id="7611228502" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea piazzatriesteetrento palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace viasancarlo fountain galleriaumbertoi piazzaplebiscito sanfrancescodipaola kingjoachimmuratofnaples ferdinandi dome statue bronze column columns roundabout chiesasferdinando shutter shutters balcony balconies churchofsanferdinando video videoclip hdvideoclip hdvideo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - HD video clip" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7138/7611228502_28f3d2c137_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="102" />
<photo  date_taken="1995-12-20 09:31:28" description="The gates of the Royal Palace near Piazza Plebiscito in Naples, Italy, at sunrise." id="327230265" latitude="40.837815" license="2" longitude="14.24997" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="palazzo reale napoli naples italy italia royal palace statue equestrian silhouette" title="Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/139/327230265_74237cc955_b.jpg" username="thapgood" views="78" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:53:22" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city." id="7610186524" latitude="40.837888" license="4" longitude="14.249213" nbComments="0" rank="32" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii piazzatriesteetrento roundabout galleriaumbertoi column columns viasancarlo operahouse teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7265/7610186524_03a27d5431_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:57:25" description="This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city. HD video clip of Galleria Umberto I, Teatro San Carlo and Palazzo Reale." id="7611408594" latitude="40.837888" license="4" longitude="14.249213" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea viavittorioemanueleiii galleriaumbertoi column columns viasancarlo palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii operahouse video videoclip hdvideo hdvideoclip unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples - HD video clip" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8162/7611408594_e19b03b1cb_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="58" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:53:58" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city." id="7610192938" latitude="40.837888" license="4" longitude="14.249213" nbComments="0" rank="34" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii galleriaumbertoi column columns viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8292/7610192938_bda4b3a80b_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="42" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:54:02" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city." id="7610196172" latitude="40.837888" license="4" longitude="14.249213" nbComments="0" rank="35" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii galleriaumbertoi column columns viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7133/7610196172_0ed8672478_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="42" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:53:42" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. The church is the Chiesa S. Ferdinando. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Ferdinando_(Naples)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;San Ferdinando (Naples)&lt;/a&gt; Shops below these buildings." id="7610189788" latitude="40.837482" license="4" longitude="14.248527" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach piazzatriesteetrento roundabout shutter shutters balcony balconies chiesasferdinando churchofsanferdinando viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Chiesa S. Ferdinando" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8432/7610189788_7e4988a792_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="72" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:54:36" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galleria_Umberto_I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Galleria Umberto I&lt;/a&gt; in Naples. Galleria Umberto I is a public shopping gallery in Naples, southern Italy. It is located directly across from the San Carlo opera house. It was built between 1887–1891, and was the cornerstone in the decades-long rebuilding of Naples — called the risanamento (lit. &amp;quot;making healthy again&amp;quot;) — that lasted until World War I. It was designed by Emanuele Rocco, who employed modern architectural elements reminiscent of the Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II in Milan. The Galleria was named for Umberto I, King of Italy at the time of construction. It was meant to combine businesses, shops, cafes and social life — public space — with private space in the apartments on the third floor. The Galleria is a high and spacious cross-shaped affair surmounted by a glass dome braced by 16 metal ribs. Of the four glass-vaulted wings, one fronts on via Toledo (via Roma), still the main downtown thoroughfare, and another opens onto the San Carlo Theater. It has returned to being an active center of Neapolitan civic life after years of decay. The Galleria Umberto is the setting for The Gallery (1947) by the American writer John Horne Burns (1916–1953) based on his experiences as an American soldier in Naples shortly after the liberation of the city. On the right is Pandorino e Torromacco (a sandwich shop)." id="7610209410" latitude="40.838075" license="4" longitude="14.24975" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii galleriaumbertoi pandorinoetorromacco unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Galleria Umberto I - Naples - Pandorino e Torromacco" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7139/7610209410_c4273cb960_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="58" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:50:06" description="A quick look around Piazza Trieste e Trento in Naples (before we had to get back on our coach). Better shot of Palazzo Reale from Piazza Trieste e Trento. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board." id="7611087526" latitude="40.836736" license="4" longitude="14.249224" nbComments="3" rank="38" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea piazzatriesteetrento palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8023/7611087526_a5568dddd4_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="123" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:51:21" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. Next to the palace is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatro_di_San_Carlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Teatro di San Carlo&lt;/a&gt;. The Real Teatro di San Carlo (English: Royal Theatre of Saint Charles) is an opera house in Naples, Italy. It is the oldest continuously active such venue in Europe. Founded by the Bourbon Charles VII of Naples (Carlo VII in Italian) of the Spanish branch of the dynasty, the theatre was inaugurated on 4 November 1737 — the king's name day — with a performance of Domenico Sarro's Achille in Sciro, an opera based on the play by the famous poet and dramatist who went by the name of Metastasio. Sarro also conducted the orchestra in two ballets as intermezzi, created by Grossatesta. At the time, it was the largest opera house in the world, seating 3,300. Our drop off point would be near here (but first we had to go around the roundabout near the piazza coming up)." id="7610152006" latitude="40.837645" license="4" longitude="14.249761" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii viasancarlo operahouse unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Palazzo Reale and Teatro di San Carlo" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8283/7610152006_b8f1be38eb_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="73" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:23" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento). This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. Next to the palace is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatro_di_San_Carlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Teatro di San Carlo&lt;/a&gt;. The Real Teatro di San Carlo (English: Royal Theatre of Saint Charles) is an opera house in Naples, Italy. It is the oldest continuously active such venue in Europe. Founded by the Bourbon Charles VII of Naples (Carlo VII in Italian) of the Spanish branch of the dynasty, the theatre was inaugurated on 4 November 1737 — the king's name day — with a performance of Domenico Sarro's Achille in Sciro, an opera based on the play by the famous poet and dramatist who went by the name of Metastasio. Sarro also conducted the orchestra in two ballets as intermezzi, created by Grossatesta. At the time, it was the largest opera house in the world, seating 3,300. The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. Fountain in the middle of the piazza." id="7610170220" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach piazzatriesteetrento fountain roundabout gigliotravel palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace viasancarlo teatrodisancarlo realteatrodisancarlo royaltheatreofsaintcharles carlovii operahouse unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples - Teatro di San Carlo - fountain" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8147/7610170220_129b996db5_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="143" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:52:45" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento). The piazza with fountain is the Piazza Trieste e Trento. Shops below these buildings." id="7610179872" latitude="40.837198" license="4" longitude="14.248688" nbComments="1" rank="41" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach gigliotravel piazzatriesteetrento roundabout shutter shutters balcony balconies viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Piazza Trieste e Trento, Naples" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8027/7610179872_be1bdbc902_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="47" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:51:11" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. Going past a wall / metal fence with Italian graffiti on it. Our drop off point would be near here (but first we had to go around the roundabout near the piazza coming up). Other Giglio Travel coaches - we were also on one of them (our tour operators main coach company that they hired in Sorrento)." id="7610148860" latitude="40.837896" license="4" longitude="14.250254" nbComments="0" rank="42" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace graffiti italiangraffiti wall fence gigliotravel viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8145/7610148860_e24c2e6b75_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="91" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 11:51:02" description="Heading on the coach to the centre of Naples. Last leg of the trip on the coach before we got off to have a look around the centre of Naples. Heading past the former Royal Palace and the Galleria Umbero I. On Via Vittorio Emanuele III. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board. Going past a wall / metal fence with Italian graffiti on it." id="7610145112" latitude="40.837896" license="4" longitude="14.250254" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea coach viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace graffiti italiangraffiti wall fence viasancarlo unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Palazzo Reale" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8293/7610145112_95c2f4536c_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="79" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:46:25" description="Statues with horses at the Palazzo Reale in Naples, near the gates / fences on the Piazza Municipio side of the palace. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board." id="7610589856" latitude="40.838286" license="4" longitude="14.251316" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace viasancarlo municipio bronze unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Palazzo Reale - statues" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8155/7610589856_8fb2891dcc_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="115" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-01 13:46:33" description="Statues with horses at the Palazzo Reale in Naples, near the gates / fences on the Piazza Municipio side of the palace. This is Palazzo Reale. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace_of_Naples&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Royal Palace of Naples&lt;/a&gt; The Royal Palace is a palace in Naples, southern Italy. It is one of the four residences used by the Bourbon Kings of Naples during their rule of the Kingdom of Two Sicilies (1730-1860): one is in Caserta, another on the Capodimonte hill overlooking Naples, and the third (now the site of the agricultural department of the University of Naples) is in Portici on the slopes of Vesuvius. The Royal Palace is on the site of an earlier building meant to host King Philip III of Spain, who however never made the trip. The architect chosen for that palace was Domenico Fontana. The building was put up on the site of an even older Spanish viceroyal residence from the early 16th century. The royal residence was moved to Caserta in the 18th century, as that inland town was more defensible from naval assault than Naples. The 17th century palace visible today is, however, the result of numerous additions and changes, including some by Luigi Vanvitelli in the mid-18th century and then by Gaetano Genovese in 1838 after a fire had damaged much of the palace. Additionally, restoration was done after World War II to repair bomb damage. The western façade side of the building (fronting on Piazza del Plebiscito) displays a series of statues of the rulers of dynasties to rule Naples since the foundation of the Kingdom of Naples in the twelfth century. They are: Roger II, Frederick II of Hohenstaufen, Charles of Anjou, Alfonse of Aragon, Emperor Charles V, Charles VII of Naples, Joachim Murat, and Victor Emanuel II of Savoy, the first king of united Italy. Today the palace and adjacent grounds house the famous Teatro San Carlo, the smaller Teatrino di Corte (recently restored), the Biblioteca nazionale Vittorio Emanuele III, a museum, and offices, including those of the regional tourist board." id="7610592874" latitude="40.838286" license="4" longitude="14.251316" nbComments="0" rank="45" tags="naples napoli campania italy italia bayofnaples golfodinapoli gulfofnaples mediterraneansea tyrrheniansea viavittorioemanueleiii palazzoreale royalpalaceofnaples bourbonkingsofnaples kingdomoftwosicilies royalpalace viasancarlo municipio bronze unesco worldheritagesite unescoworldheritagesite" title="Via Vittorio Emanuele III, Naples - Palazzo Reale - statues" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7131/7610592874_6e97de9de0_b.jpg" username="ell brown" views="110" />
</photos>
