<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<photos monument="Tower of Belem">

<photo  date_taken="1995-06-25 01:06:00" description="Torre de Belém (Belém Tower) or the Tower of St Vincent is a fortified tower located in the civil parish of Santa Maria de Belém in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The tower was commissioned by King John II to be part of a defense system at the mouth of the Tagus River and a ceremonial gateway to Lisbon. The tower was built in the early 16th century and is a prominent example of the Portuguese Manueline style, but it also incorporates hints of other architectural styles. The structure was built from lioz limestone and is composed of a bastion and the 30 meter four story tower. (From Wikipedia, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bel%C3%A9m_Tower&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bel%C3%A9m_Tower&lt;/a&gt;)" id="6172322303" latitude="38.691589" license="4" longitude="-9.215986" nbComments="0" rank="1" tags="belem torredebelem portugal torredebelém belémtower belemtower towerofstvincent lisbon" title="Belem, Torre de Belem" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/6161/6172322303_484362b208_b.jpg" username="Arian Zwegers" views="47" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-28 11:15:06" description="Local Name: Torre de Belém, The Torré de Belém is certainly Lisbon's most famous construction and at the same time most well known symbol. It stands surrounded by lawns on the bank of the Tagus to the west of the Hieronymite monastery. At this point the Tagus widens into a large bay. Originally conceived as a lighthouse and simultaneously a defensive fortress for the port of Restelo, Manuel I had the tower built in 1515 on a small island off the river bank. Many old views of the city show the Torré de Belém at a distance from the mainland surrounded by the waters of the Tagus. A former, older tower on the opposite bank and Belém's fortress tower were supposed to afford maximum protection for the harbour. A general shift in the location of the river bank has resulted in the tower now standing on the mainland right on the water's edge: a footbridge leads across an artificial basin to the entrance to the tower. Francisco de Arruda began the construction in 1515. De Arruda came from Alentejo and was one of the most famous architects to use the Manueline style. He had studied with his older brother Diogo de Arruda, had then worked for some time in north Africa and was thus acquainted with the elements of the Arabic style - one of the reasons for the obvious Moorish influences in his work. The Torré de Belém has been the setting for many historical events. These included the onset of Spain's 60 year rule of Portugal after the conquest of the tower in 1580. After Lisbon was taken by Napoleonic troops in 1807 the two upper stories of the tower were destroyed and wooden houses built in their place. In 1845 Minister Terceira had the tower restored to its original state. More Photos At: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glynlowe.com/belem_tower&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.glynlowe.com/belem_tower&lt;/a&gt;" id="8038548360" latitude="38.691572" license="4" longitude="-9.216027" nbComments="33" rank="2" tags="belem belemtower belém photos state stock torré torrédebelém tower buy digital digitaldownload download lisboa lisbon portugal sale stockphoto stockphotos" title="Belem Tower, Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8310/8038548360_57c62c405b_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="265" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-28 10:56:24" description="Local Name: Torre de Belém, The Torré de Belém is certainly Lisbon's most famous construction and at the same time most well known symbol. It stands surrounded by lawns on the bank of the Tagus to the west of the Hieronymite monastery. At this point the Tagus widens into a large bay. Originally conceived as a lighthouse and simultaneously a defensive fortress for the port of Restelo, Manuel I had the tower built in 1515 on a small island off the river bank. Many old views of the city show the Torré de Belém at a distance from the mainland surrounded by the waters of the Tagus. A former, older tower on the opposite bank and Belém's fortress tower were supposed to afford maximum protection for the harbour. A general shift in the location of the river bank has resulted in the tower now standing on the mainland right on the water's edge: a footbridge leads across an artificial basin to the entrance to the tower. Francisco de Arruda began the construction in 1515. De Arruda came from Alentejo and was one of the most famous architects to use the Manueline style. He had studied with his older brother Diogo de Arruda, had then worked for some time in north Africa and was thus acquainted with the elements of the Arabic style - one of the reasons for the obvious Moorish influences in his work. The Torré de Belém has been the setting for many historical events. These included the onset of Spain's 60 year rule of Portugal after the conquest of the tower in 1580. After Lisbon was taken by Napoleonic troops in 1807 the two upper stories of the tower were destroyed and wooden houses built in their place. In 1845 Minister Terceira had the tower restored to its original state." id="8038524164" latitude="38.691606" license="4" longitude="-9.215941" nbComments="15" rank="3" tags="belem belemtower belém photos state stock torré torrédebelém tower buy digital digitaldownload download lisboa lisbon portugal sale stockphoto stockphotos" title="Belem Tower, Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8031/8038524164_81ab4c1d81_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="126" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-28 10:58:58" description="Local Name: Torre de Belém, The Torré de Belém is certainly Lisbon's most famous construction and at the same time most well known symbol. It stands surrounded by lawns on the bank of the Tagus to the west of the Hieronymite monastery. At this point the Tagus widens into a large bay. Originally conceived as a lighthouse and simultaneously a defensive fortress for the port of Restelo, Manuel I had the tower built in 1515 on a small island off the river bank. Many old views of the city show the Torré de Belém at a distance from the mainland surrounded by the waters of the Tagus. A former, older tower on the opposite bank and Belém's fortress tower were supposed to afford maximum protection for the harbour. A general shift in the location of the river bank has resulted in the tower now standing on the mainland right on the water's edge: a footbridge leads across an artificial basin to the entrance to the tower. Francisco de Arruda began the construction in 1515. De Arruda came from Alentejo and was one of the most famous architects to use the Manueline style. He had studied with his older brother Diogo de Arruda, had then worked for some time in north Africa and was thus acquainted with the elements of the Arabic style - one of the reasons for the obvious Moorish influences in his work. The Torré de Belém has been the setting for many historical events. These included the onset of Spain's 60 year rule of Portugal after the conquest of the tower in 1580. After Lisbon was taken by Napoleonic troops in 1807 the two upper stories of the tower were destroyed and wooden houses built in their place. In 1845 Minister Terceira had the tower restored to its original state." id="8038516018" latitude="38.691606" license="4" longitude="-9.215898" nbComments="8" rank="4" tags="belem belemtower belém photos state stock torré torrédebelém tower buy digital digitaldownload download lisboa lisbon portugal sale stockphoto stockphotos" title="Belem Tower, Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8034/8038516018_6048eae527_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="189" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-07-09 16:02:46" description="Some are dreaming, some are drawing. Some are taking pictures. Some are only watching. And some are sailing away. Dreaming of summer. Dreaming of a castle in Portugal. Certains rêvassent, certains dessinent. Certains prennent des photos. Certains admirent en silence. Certains mettent les voiles. Tous rêvent D'un château au Portugal. Belem Tower, Lisbon, Portugal" id="6949768170" latitude="38.691413" license="3" longitude="-9.215962" nbComments="13" rank="5" tags="lisbonne lisbon lisboa portugal belem tower tour castle chateau architecture art sea mer ocean atlantic atlantique port water eau stone pierre people shadow ombre light summer ete vacation trip travel sail sailing voile boat voilier horizon blue bleu panasonic lumix dmctz4 europe torredebelém" title="A Castle in Portugal (Un château au Portugal)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7113/6949768170_bac54200ca_b.jpg" username="Gilderic Photography" views="566" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-09-28 10:52:45" description="Local Name: Torre de Belém, The Torré de Belém is certainly Lisbon's most famous construction and at the same time most well known symbol. It stands surrounded by lawns on the bank of the Tagus to the west of the Hieronymite monastery. At this point the Tagus widens into a large bay. Originally conceived as a lighthouse and simultaneously a defensive fortress for the port of Restelo, Manuel I had the tower built in 1515 on a small island off the river bank. Many old views of the city show the Torré de Belém at a distance from the mainland surrounded by the waters of the Tagus. A former, older tower on the opposite bank and Belém's fortress tower were supposed to afford maximum protection for the harbour. A general shift in the location of the river bank has resulted in the tower now standing on the mainland right on the water's edge: a footbridge leads across an artificial basin to the entrance to the tower. Francisco de Arruda began the construction in 1515. De Arruda came from Alentejo and was one of the most famous architects to use the Manueline style. He had studied with his older brother Diogo de Arruda, had then worked for some time in north Africa and was thus acquainted with the elements of the Arabic style - one of the reasons for the obvious Moorish influences in his work. The Torré de Belém has been the setting for many historical events. These included the onset of Spain's 60 year rule of Portugal after the conquest of the tower in 1580. After Lisbon was taken by Napoleonic troops in 1807 the two upper stories of the tower were destroyed and wooden houses built in their place. In 1845 Minister Terceira had the tower restored to its original state." id="8038507710" latitude="38.691539" license="4" longitude="-9.215812" nbComments="3" rank="6" tags="belem belemtower belém photos state stock torré torrédebelém tower buy digital digitaldownload download lisboa lisbon portugal sale stockphoto stockphotos" title="Belem Tower, Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8456/8038507710_c380f78a2a_b.jpg" username="Glyn Lowe Photoworks" views="102" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-02-14 13:37:44" description="Panoramic view from the top of the tower." id="3384110724" latitude="38.691723" license="6" longitude="-9.21585" nbComments="1" rank="7" tags="rio tejo river water água sky skyline céu lisbon lisboa panorama panorâmica 2009 portugal panoramic view torre belém belem tower" title="LISBON :: Torre de Belém : panorama 180º" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3421/3384110724_ed180ce9d3_b.jpg" username="Crystian Cruz" views="156" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-20 09:21:37" description="The Tower of Belém is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/pg.cfm?cid=31&amp;amp;id_site=263&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/a&gt;." id="97011461" latitude="38.691694" license="3" longitude="-9.215652" nbComments="0" rank="8" tags="europe portugal lisbon lisboa belem tower torre gothic belém tagus river unescoworldheritagesite manueline geo:lat=38691694 geo:lon=9215652 towerofbelém tagusriver water worldheritagesite dopplr:explore=uvf1" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/23/97011461_cf64306e75_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="187" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 15:40:03" description="&lt;b&gt;Watching&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; La torre de Belém, situada en la ciudad de Lisboa, capital de Portugal, es obra de Francisco de Arruda y constituye uno de los ejemplos más representativos de la arquitectura manuelina. En el pasado sirvió como centro de recaudación de impuestos para poder entrar a la ciudad. Su construcción fue iniciada en 1514, bajo el reinado de Manuel I de Portugal (1495-1521), teniendo como arquitecto a Francisco de Arruda. Sus obras quedaron a cargo de Diogo Boitaca, que, en la época, también dirigía las ya adelantadas obras del vecino Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Belém. Las obras finalizaron en 1520. Se encuentra situada en la desembocadura del río Tajo, en el barrio de Santa Maria de Belém de esta ciudad al suroeste de Lisboa. El monumento tiene las influencias islámicas y orientales, que caracterizan el estilo manuelino y marca el fin de la tradición medieval de las torres de homenaje, formando uno de los primeros baluartes para artillería en Portugal. Parte de su belleza reside en la decoración exterior, adornada con cuerdas esculpidas en piedra, galerías abiertas, torres de vigilancia en estilo mozárabe y almenas en forma de escudos decoradas con esferas armilares, la cruz de la Orden de Cristo y elementos naturalistas, como un rinoceronte, alusivos a los descubrimientos en ultramar. El interior gótico, localizado bajo el piso inferior, sirvió como armería y prisión y es muy austero. Su estructura se compone de dos elementos principales: la torre y el baluarte. En los ángulos del piso inferior de la torre y del baluarte, sobresalen garitas cilíndricas coronadas por cúpulas con forma de gajos de naranja, ricamente decoradas en cantería de piedra. La nave del baluarte poligonal, ventilada por un pequeño claustro, tiene dieciséis aberturas para cañoneras de tiro rasante. El terraplén, guarnecido por almenas, constituye una segunda línea de fuego, estando localizado en el Santuario de Nuestra Señora del Buen Suceso, patrona del lugar, también conocida como la &lt;i&gt;Virgem do Restelo&lt;/i&gt;. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torre_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torre_de_Bel%C3%A9m&lt;/a&gt; -------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; Belém Tower or the Tower of St Vincent is a fortified tower located in the civil parish of Santa Maria de Belém in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. It is an UNESCO World Heritage Site (along with the nearby Jerónimos Monastery) because of the significant role it played in the Portuguese maritime discoveries of the era of the Age of Discoveries. The tower was commissioned by King John II to be part of a defense system at the mouth of the Tagus River and a ceremonial gateway to Lisbon. The tower was built in the early 16th century and is a prominent example of the Portuguese Manueline style, but it also incorporates hints of other architectural styles. The structure was built from lioz limestone and is composed of a bastion and the 30 meter (100 foot), four story tower. It has incorrectly been stated that the tower was built in the middle of the Tagus and now sits near the shore because the river was redirected after the 1755 Lisbon earthquake. In fact, the tower was built on a small island in the Tagus River near the Lisbon shore. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bel%c3%a9m_Tower&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bel%C3%A9m_Tower&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/vigilante.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/vigilante.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6765522343" latitude="38.692097" license="3" longitude="-9.216334" nbComments="30" rank="9" tags="tamron 18200 novicecontrast kodakektachrome100vs castillo castle torre tower reflejo reflection río river tajo geo:lat=3869209623 geo:lon=921633303 geotagged cruzquebrada lisboa portugal" title="Vigilante (reedición)" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7015/6765522343_339cfb7a5b_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="465" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-12-24 00:48:01" description="Belem, Lisbon, Portugal From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Monastery of the Hieronymites and Tower of Belém in Lisbon* UNESCO World Heritage Site State Party Portugal TypeCultural Criteriaiii, vi Reference263 Region**Europe and North America Inscription history Inscription1983 (7th Session) * Name as inscribed on World Heritage List. ** Region as classified by UNESCO. Belém Tower (in Portuguese Torre de Belém, pron. IPA: ['toɾ(ɨ) dɨ bɨ'lɐ̃ĩ]) is a fortified tower located in the Belém district of Lisbon, Portugal. It was built in the early 16th century in the Portuguese late Gothic style, the Manueline, to commemorate Vasco da Gama's expedition. This defensive, yet elegant construction has become one of the symbols of the city, a memorial to the Portuguese power during the Age of the Great Discoveries. In 1983 it was classified, together with the nearby Mosteiro dos Jerónimos, as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. [edit]History The Belém Tower was built both as a ceremonial gateway to Lisbon and as part of a defense system of the entrance of the Tagus river and the Jerónimos Monastery, which was necessary to protect Lisbon. The system was initiated by King John II (1455-1495), who built the Fortress of Cascais and the Fortress of São Sebastião of Caparica. The banks of Belém were protected by a ship, the Grande Nau, replaced by the Tower of Belém during the last five years of the reign of King Manuel I. Renaissance loggia on the first floor of Belém Tower. The Tower was constructed between 1515 and 1521 by military architect Francisco de Arruda, who had already built several fortresses in Portuguese possessions in Morocco. The influence of the Moorish decorative art is manifest in delicate decorations of the arched windows and balconies and in the ribbed cupolas of the watch towers. Diogo de Boitaca, first architect of the nearby Monastery of the Jerónimos, probably also participated in decorating the building. The machicolation and the battlements are decorated with the rich sculptural ornamentations of the Manueline style. Originally, the Tower stood on a little island on the right side of the Tagus, surrounded by water. Opposite the beach at Restelo, with the progressive southward creeping of the shore over the years, it is now practically moored to the bank itself. It was dedicated to the patron saint of Lisbon, St Vincent. In 1580, when Lisbon was invaded by Spanish troops in the course of a struggle for the Portuguese throne, the Tower fought and surrendered to the Duke of Alba. In the following centuries the Tower was mainly used as a prison (with the underground cellars regularly flooding) and as a custom house. Indeed, given its height and lack of dissimulation in the landscape, some historians believe the Tower was mostly intended to serve as a customs outpost. In the 1840s, under the impulse of romantic writer Almeida Garrett, the Tower of Belém was restored by King Ferdinand II. At this point many neo-manueline decorative elements were added to the building. It was declared a National Monument in 1910. [edit]Art and architecture Casemate of the bastion of Belém Tower. The Tower of Belém is considered one of the main works of the Portuguese late gothic, the manueline style. Indeed, the tower is decorated with several typical Manueline motifs like the armillary sphere (the symbol of Manuel I), the cross of the Order of Christ (to which Manuel I belonged), twisted ropes, elaborate rib vaulting and other features. However, some of the decoration dates from the renovation of the 1840s, like the shields with the cross of the military Order of Christ, that decorate the crenellations of the walls, and the decoration of the small cloister of the bastion. The part of the tower facing the river displays the richest decorations. The Tower of Belém can be divided into two parts, the bastion, with the shape of an irregular hexagon, and the five-story tower itself, located on the north side of the bastion. The whole ensemble looks like the bow of a caravel. Crenelated tower with Manueline decorations The bastion has a vaulted chamber (the casemate), with openings in the 3.5 m-thick walls for the 17 large-calibre breech-loading cannons. The open centre above the casemate made it easier to dispel the fumes and smokes. The bastion platform could also be used for the emplacement of light-calibre guns. This was the first Portuguese fortification with a two-level gun emplacement and it marks a new development in military architecture. The corners of this platform have delicate turrets (guerites) topped by Moorish-looking cupolas. The base of the turrets have images of beasts, including a rhinoceros, considered to be the first sculpture of such an animal in Western European art. This rhinoceros probably depicts the one that Manuel I sent to the Pope in 1515. On the platform, in front of the tower, stands a statue of the Madonna of Belém with Child and a bunch of grapes in her left hand in a richly carved niche with a baldachin in Manueline style. The same turrets occur on the upper platform of the tower. The entrance to the Tower is done through a portal decorated with many Manueline motifs, including Manuel I's badge of honour (an armillary sphere). The whole tower is also decorated with stone twisted ropes, which even tie a knot at the north façade of the building. Tower lit up at night The upper corners of the tower walls have statues of St Vincent and St Michael, as well as many fine windows with arches. The renaissance-style covered loggia, running the full length of the south side of the first floor of the tower, is particularly delicate. It has a Venetian touch. The many shields that decorate the merlons are neo-manueline. The tower itself, 35 metres high, has four storeys and a terrace that offers wonderful views of the surrounding landscape. The powder magazine is at water level. The next storeys are reached via a narrow spiral staircase. The next storey was the commander's room. The second storey has covered balconies on each side. Of the tower floors, the most interesting is the chapel of the fourth floor, with a magnificent Manueline rib vault decorated with the armillary sphere and the cross of the military Order of Christ, who participated in many Portuguese conquests. The oratory is on the top floor." id="3132267544" latitude="38.692293" license="4" longitude="-9.216156" nbComments="34" rank="10" tags="belem belemstower gothicstyle ilustrarportugal lisbon portugal sixteencentury stone tagusriver thecontinuum unesco unescoworldheritagesite flickrduel" title="Belem's Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3227/3132267544_9b126b95c0_b.jpg" username="pedrosimoes7" views="2780" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-11-10 23:08:30" description="The tower was built in the 16th century (1514-1520) as part of Lisboa's line of defense. Throughout the years it served as customs outpost, prison, telegraph station and lighthouse. Perhaps because it was built in water and somehow resembles a ship, popular tradition say that it was from this tower that Portuguese caravels sailed to Africa, India and Brasil. Although this is not true, it is considered one of the most relevant icons to the Portuguese Discoveries. Today it is listed in UNESCO World Heritage (together with Mosteiro dos Jerónimos)." id="304364937" latitude="38.691761" license="3" longitude="-9.215222" nbComments="20" rank="11" tags="canoneos350d torredebelém belém lisboa portugal descobrimentos white black night monument monumento tejo river tagus nightshot lisbon history bravo canonefs1855mmf3556ii explore lenstagged rio cidade thechromaticorb" title="Torre de Belém by night" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/105/304364937_609cdbb188_b.jpg" username="ChromaticOrb" views="1470" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-12 11:50:51" description="Lisboa, a capital de Portugal. Era para ser uma conexão rápida, mas mudaram o horário do vôo para o Brasil e a gente teve que esperar umas 6 horas no aeroporto. Então resolvemos fazer um city tour. &lt;i&gt;A Torre de Belém é um dos monumentos mais expressivos da cidade de Lisboa. Localiza-se na margem direita do rio Tejo, onde existiu outrora a praia de Belém. Inicialmente cercada pelas águas em todo o seu perímetro, progressivamente foi envolvida pela praia, até se incorporar hoje à terra firme. O monumento se destaca pelo nacionalismo implícito, visto que é todo rodeado por decorações do Brasão de armas de Portugal, incluindo inscrições de cruzes da Ordem de Cristo nas janelas de baluarte; tais características remetem principalmente à arquitetura típica de uma época em que o país era uma potência global (a do início da Idade Moderna). Classificada como Património Mundial pela UNESCO, em 7 de Julho de 2007 foi eleita como uma das Sete maravilhas de Portugal.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torre_de_bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipédia&lt;/a&gt; Lisbon, capital of Portugal. It was supposed to be a quick connection, but the flight back to Brazil changed and we had to wait for about 6 hours. So we decided to have a city tour. &lt;i&gt;Belém Tower (in Portuguese Torre de Belém) or the Tower of St Vincent is a fortified tower located in the Belém district of Lisbon, Portugal. It is an UNESCO World Heritage Site (along with the nearby Jerónimos Monastery) because of the significant role it played in the Portuguese maritime discoveries of the era of the Age of Discoveries. The tower was commissioned by King John II to be both part of a defense system at the mouth of the Tagus River and a ceremonial gateway to Lisbon. The tower was built in the early sixteenth century and is a prominent example of the Portuguese Manueline style, but it also incorporates hints of other architectural styles. The structure was built from lioz limestone and is composed of a bastion and the 30 meter (100 foot), four story tower. It has incorrectly been stated that the tower was built in the middle of the Tagus and now sits near the shore because the river was redirected after the 1755 Lisbon earthquake. In fact, the tower was built on a small island in the Tagus River near the Lisbon shore.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bel%c3%a9m_Tower&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;" id="4463485764" latitude="38.691928" license="3" longitude="-9.214792" nbComments="5" rank="12" tags="lisboa lisbon portugal europa europe citorën 2cv belém torre tower" title="Citroën 2CV na Torre de Belém / Citroën 2CV at Belém Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2766/4463485764_410de7ee9f_b.jpg" username="Marcio Cabral de Moura" views="474" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-02-11 13:50:12" description="The Tower of Belem an amzing fort constructed at the beginning of the 16th century to guard the entrance of the river." id="6923873643" latitude="38.692165" license="1" longitude="-9.214" nbComments="0" rank="13" tags="barge barging canal canals drumsara france huskies lisbon lock locks peniche portugal" title="Lisbon. Portugal - 44" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7207/6923873643_a4e04acd80_b.jpg" username="Drumsara" views="8" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-02-11 13:50:12" description="The Tower of Belem an amzing fort constructed at the beginning of the 16th century to guard the entrance of the river." id="6777567800" latitude="38.692165" license="1" longitude="-9.214" nbComments="0" rank="14" tags="drumsara barge barging canal canals lock locks peniche huskies france" title="Lisbon. Portugal - 44" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7186/6777567800_f791dee78f_b.jpg" username="Drumsara" views="2" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-07-12 11:47:33" description="Avião utilizado por Gago Coutinho e Sacadura Cabral para realizar a primeira travessia aérea do Atlântico Sul, em 1922. Fica localizado numa praça, junto à Torre de Belém. Lisboa, Portugal. Seaplane used by Gago Coutinho and Sacadura Cabral to do the first airplane crossing of the South Atlantic Ocean. It´s located in a square near Belém Tower. Lisboa, Portugal." id="4462708541" latitude="38.692205" license="3" longitude="-9.213934" nbComments="2" rank="15" tags="lisboa lisbon portugal europa europe lusitânia hidroavião seaplane gagocoutinho sacaduracabral" title="Hidroavião Lusitânia / Lusitânia Seaplane" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4067/4462708541_6b697cb7cd_b.jpg" username="Marcio Cabral de Moura" views="680" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-05 12:49:15" description="The Torre de Belém tower seen from the top of the Padrão dos Descobrimentos monument in Belém, Lisbon." id="3905530845" latitude="38.693621" license="4" longitude="-9.205683" nbComments="0" rank="16" tags="portugal lisbon lisboa retriever padrãodosdescobrimentos padraodosdescobrimentos monumenttothediscoveries henrythenavigator belem belém torredebelém torredebelem belémtower belemtower" title="View from Padrão dos Descobrimentos" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2571/3905530845_ce2939dae3_b.jpg" username="Bernt Rostad" views="104" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-04-13 10:15:35" description="Jerónimos, Lisbon, Portugal in Wikipedia The Hieronymites Monastery (Mosteiro dos Jerónimos, pron. IPA: [muʃ'tɐiɾu duʃ ʒɨ'ɾɔnimuʃ]) is located in the Belém district of Lisbon, Portugal. This magnificent monastery can be considered one of the most prominent monuments in Lisbon and is certainly one of the most successful achievements of the Manueline style. In 1983 it was classified by the UNESCO, with nearby Torre de Belém, as a World Heritage Site. The house for the Hieronymite monks was built on the same site of the Ermida do Restelo, a hermitage that was founded by Henry the Navigator at about 1450. It was at this hermitage, that was already in disrepair, that Vasco da Gama and his men spent the night in prayer before departing for India in 1497. Kneeling statue of King Manuel I - main sponsor of the Monastery - on the Western portal. The figure behind the king is St Jerome. The existing structure was started on the orders of Manuel I (1515-1520) to commemorate Vasco da Gama's successful return from India. It was originally meant as a church for the burial of the House of Aviz, but it also became a house of prayer for seamen leaving or entering port. Construction of the monastery began in 1502 and took 50 years to complete. He used pedra lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, for its construction. The building of the monastery was funded by a 5% tax on eastern spices, with the exceptions of pepper, cinnamon and cloves, revenue from which went straight to the Crown. By this influx of riches, the architects had enough financial margin to think big. The enormous amount of funds needed for this monastery, meant abandoning the construction of the Aviz pantheon in the Monastery of Batalha. The monastery was designed in the Manueline style by Diogo de Boitaca (who was probably one of the originators of this style with the Igreja de Jesus in Setúbal). He built the church, the monastery, the sacristy and the refectory. He was succeeded by the Spaniard João de Castilho, who took charge of construction in around 1517. João de Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline style to the Plateresco style, a style with lavish decorations that remind of silver ware (plata = silver). There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with his Renaissance themes. The construction came to a halt when the king Manuel I died in 1520. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir and completing the two storeys of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. His work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. The monastery withstood the Great Earthquake of 1755 without too much damage. But when the building became vacant in 1833 by the abolition of the religious orders in Portugal, it began to deteriorate to the point of almost collapsing. A cupola was later added to the southwestern tower. On December 13, 2007 the Treaty of Lisbon has been signed at the monastery, laying down the basis for the reform of the European Union." id="3495003182" latitude="38.696345" license="4" longitude="-9.206371" nbComments="2" rank="17" tags="ilustrarportugal" title="Jerónimos Monastery" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3643/3495003182_b12d429e7b_b.jpg" username="pedrosimoes7" views="348" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-09-01 18:49:45" description="Para a ana rita, que está quase aí a aparecer e que gosta muito destas coisas. UNESCO World Heritage: &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/263&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Monastery of the Hieronymites and Tower of Belém in Lisbon&lt;/a&gt;" id="2120948174" latitude="38.696178" license="1" longitude="-9.205663" nbComments="1" rank="18" tags="belém praçadoimpério jerónimos mosteirodosjerónimos anna popcorny lisboa rancho lisbon lissabon portugal anarita unescoworldheritage" title="Popcorny" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2127/2120948174_1d17217c04_b.jpg" username="PQz" views="107" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 12:42:26" description="&lt;b&gt;Photo&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. El claustro se encuentra situado junto a la nave norte del templo. Fue diseñado por Juan de Castillo. Fue realizado entre 1517 y 1519 con varias contratas y subcontratas dando lugar a un resultado final de armonía y uniformidad. Todo el claustro está ampliamente decorado con motivos manuelinos (letra M, esfera armilar, cabos marineros, temas religiosos, hornacinas, medallones, etc.). Desde el piso de arriba se puede acceder al coro alto de la iglesia, que fue construido por Torralva en el siglo XVI. En él se halla una importante sillería también del XVI. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Work on the vast square cloister (55 x 55 m) of the monastery was begun by Boitac. He built the groin vaults with wide arches and windows with tracery resting on delicate mullions. Juan de Castilho finished the construction by giving the lower storey a classical overlay and building a more recessed upper-storey. The construction of such a cloister was a novelty at the time. Castilho changed the original round columns of Boitac into rectangular ones, and embellished it with Plateresque-style ornamentation. Each wing consists of six bays with tracery vaults. The four inner bays rest on massive buttresses, forming broad arcades. The corner bays are linked by a diagonal arched construction and show the richly decorated corner pillars. The cloister had a religious function as well as a representative function by its decorative ornamentation and the dynastic symbolic motives, such as the armillarium, coat-of-arms, and the cross from the Order of Christ, showing the growing world power of Portugal. The inside walls of the cloister have a wealth of Manueline motives with nautical elements, in addition to European, Moorish and Eastern motifs. The round arches and the horizontal structure are clearly in line with the Renaissance style, while at the same time there is also a relationship with Spanish architecture. The decorations on the outer walls of the inner courtyard were made in Plateresco style by Castilho: the arcades include traceried arches that give the construction a filigree aspect. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2011/12/foto.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2011/12/foto.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6545192601" latitude="38.6979" license="3" longitude="-9.20592" nbComments="6" rank="19" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos claustro cloister robado stolen novicecontrast fujiastia100f hombre man fotografiando shooting geo:lat=3869789921 geo:lon=920592070 geotagged fav2011" title="Foto" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7022/6545192601_f656bfe654_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="246" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 12:55:49" description="&lt;b&gt;Pose&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. El claustro se encuentra situado junto a la nave norte del templo. Fue diseñado por Juan de Castillo. Fue realizado entre 1517 y 1519 con varias contratas y subcontratas dando lugar a un resultado final de armonía y uniformidad. Todo el claustro está ampliamente decorado con motivos manuelinos (letra M, esfera armilar, cabos marineros, temas religiosos, hornacinas, medallones, etc.). Desde el piso de arriba se puede acceder al coro alto de la iglesia, que fue construido por Torralva en el siglo XVI. En él se halla una importante sillería también del XVI. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Work on the vast square cloister (55 x 55 m) of the monastery was begun by Boitac. He built the groin vaults with wide arches and windows with tracery resting on delicate mullions. Juan de Castilho finished the construction by giving the lower storey a classical overlay and building a more recessed upper-storey. The construction of such a cloister was a novelty at the time. Castilho changed the original round columns of Boitac into rectangular ones, and embellished it with Plateresque-style ornamentation. Each wing consists of six bays with tracery vaults. The four inner bays rest on massive buttresses, forming broad arcades. The corner bays are linked by a diagonal arched construction and show the richly decorated corner pillars. The cloister had a religious function as well as a representative function by its decorative ornamentation and the dynastic symbolic motives, such as the armillarium, coat-of-arms, and the cross from the Order of Christ, showing the growing world power of Portugal. The inside walls of the cloister have a wealth of Manueline motives with nautical elements, in addition to European, Moorish and Eastern motifs. The round arches and the horizontal structure are clearly in line with the Renaissance style, while at the same time there is also a relationship with Spanish architecture. The decorations on the outer walls of the inner courtyard were made in Plateresco style by Castilho: the arcades include traceried arches that give the construction a filigree aspect. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2011/12/pose.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2011/12/pose.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6589643431" latitude="38.69815" license="3" longitude="-9.206075" nbComments="3" rank="20" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos claustro cloister robado stolen adaptativecontrast ml50 bwlayer rf chicas girls mujeres women fotografiando shooting geo:lat=3869815041 geo:lon=920607626 geotagged" title="Pose" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7156/6589643431_e86b7fce25_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="205" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:46:37" description="&lt;b&gt;Hands together&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/manos-juntas.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/manos-juntas.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6700992269" latitude="38.697641" license="3" longitude="-9.205723" nbComments="10" rank="21" tags="tamron 18200 monasterio monastery jerónimos vidriera stainedglass tumba tomb vascodegama kodakroyalgold400milder dof iglesia church geo:lat=3869764173 geo:lon=920572221 geotagged lisboa portugal" title="Manos juntas" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7029/6700992269_ff7b966439_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="271" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:15:24" description="&lt;b&gt;The space&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world. This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/el-espacio.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/el-espacio.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6641115423" latitude="38.697705" license="3" longitude="-9.20575" nbComments="7" rank="22" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos iglesia church columnas columns geo:lat=3869770453 geo:lon=920574903 geotagged prt" title="El espacio" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7016/6641115423_75a5f27317_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="233" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:16:52" description="&lt;b&gt;Filigree in stone&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/filigrana-en-piedra.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/filigrana-en-piedra.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6673080063" latitude="38.697705" license="3" longitude="-9.20575" nbComments="6" rank="23" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos iglesia church columna column geo:lat=3869770453 geo:lon=920574903 geotagged prt" title="Filigrana en piedra" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7030/6673080063_3e53c89883_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="223" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:16:16" description="&lt;b&gt;Details&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/detalles.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/detalles.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6659417235" latitude="38.697705" license="3" longitude="-9.20575" nbComments="6" rank="24" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos iglesia church cristo christ cruz cross geo:lat=3869770453 geo:lon=920574903 geotagged prt mywinners" title="Detalles" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7021/6659417235_7d2081ba91_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="215" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:20:14" description="&lt;b&gt;Lights&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/luces.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/luces.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6684324961" latitude="38.697705" license="3" longitude="-9.20575" nbComments="4" rank="25" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos iglesia church columnas columns vidrieras stainedglasswindows localcontrast kodakektachrome100g geo:lat=3869770453 geo:lon=920574903 geotagged prt" title="Luces" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7015/6684324961_541ca308f2_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="195" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:05:13" description="&lt;b&gt;Chiaroscuro&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. El claustro se encuentra situado junto a la nave norte del templo. Fue diseñado por Juan de Castillo. Fue realizado entre 1517 y 1519 con varias contratas y subcontratas dando lugar a un resultado final de armonía y uniformidad. Todo el claustro está ampliamente decorado con motivos manuelinos (letra M, esfera armilar, cabos marineros, temas religiosos, hornacinas, medallones, etc.). Desde el piso de arriba se puede acceder al coro alto de la iglesia, que fue construido por Torralva en el siglo XVI. En él se halla una importante sillería también del XVI. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Work on the vast square cloister (55 x 55 m) of the monastery was begun by Boitac. He built the groin vaults with wide arches and windows with tracery resting on delicate mullions. Juan de Castilho finished the construction by giving the lower storey a classical overlay and building a more recessed upper-storey. The construction of such a cloister was a novelty at the time. Castilho changed the original round columns of Boitac into rectangular ones, and embellished it with Plateresque-style ornamentation. Each wing consists of six bays with tracery vaults. The four inner bays rest on massive buttresses, forming broad arcades. The corner bays are linked by a diagonal arched construction and show the richly decorated corner pillars. The cloister had a religious function as well as a representative function by its decorative ornamentation and the dynastic symbolic motives, such as the armillarium, coat-of-arms, and the cross from the Order of Christ, showing the growing world power of Portugal. The inside walls of the cloister have a wealth of Manueline motives with nautical elements, in addition to European, Moorish and Eastern motifs. The round arches and the horizontal structure are clearly in line with the Renaissance style, while at the same time there is also a relationship with Spanish architecture. The decorations on the outer walls of the inner courtyard were made in Plateresco style by Castilho: the arcades include traceried arches that give the construction a filigree aspect. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2011/12/claroscuro.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2011/12/claroscuro.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6602168291" latitude="38.698258" license="3" longitude="-9.20605" nbComments="18" rank="26" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos claustro cloister bw bn highcontrast noiseiso800 sombras shadows geo:lat=3869825927 geo:lon=920604944 geotagged prt" title="Claroscuro" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7144/6602168291_34d113c764_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="279" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:47:28" description="&lt;b&gt;Confessions&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. Los críticos de arte consideran este monasterio como la joya del estilo manuelino y uno de los monumentos más importantes de Lisboa y Portugal. El interior es muy amplio y luminoso, con una sola nave de planta salón y una abigarrada decoración manuelina. La bóveda del crucero es grandiosa y cubre una superficie de 29 x 19 metros, sin apoyos centrales y con una compleja red de nervaduras. Fue diseñada por Juan de Castillo en 1522. La bóveda de la nave también fue diseñada por él y fue realizada en 1520. La Capilla mayor fue reformada posteriormente por el maestro Jerónimo Ruão en estilo renacentista avanzado con el mismo estilo que la capilla mayor de la iglesia del Monasterio de El Escorial. En el retablo destaca sobre todo el sagrario, pieza de orfebrería portuguesa del siglo XVIII de gran calidad. Es también de gran importancia el conjunto pictórico compuesto por unas tablas con el tema de la vida de Jesús. En esta capilla se encuentran apoyadas sobre leones las tumbas del rey Manuel I y su esposa María y de Joao III y Catarina de Austria. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Diogo Boitac laid the foundations for this three-aisled church with five bays under a single vault, a clearly marked but only slightly projecting a transept and a raised choir. The hall church layout is composed of aisles and nave that are of equal height. Boitac built the walls of the church as far as the cornices and then started with the construction of the adjoining monastery. Juan de Castilho, a Spanish architect and sculptor, continued the construction in 1517. He completed the retaining walls and the unique single-span ribbed vault, a combination of stellar vaulting and tracery vaults spanning the 19 metre-wide church. Each set of ribs in the vaulting is secured by bosses. The bold design (1522) of the transversal vault of the transept lacks any piers or columns, while Boitac had originally planned three bays in the transept. The transept's unsupported vault gives the visitor the impression that it floats in the air. Castilho also decorated the six 25 metre-high, slender, articulated, octagonal columns with refined grotesque or floral elements typical of the Renaissance style. The construction of this late-Gothic hall is aesthetically and architecturally a masterwork: it augments the spatial effect of this vast building. The northern column closest to the transept there is a medallion that may have been intentionally included as a portrait of Boitac or Juan de Castilho. At the end of the side aisles and on both sides of the choir are altars (also in the Manueline-style) dating from the 16th and the 17th centuries. They are decorated with carved/sculpted wood and plated in golden and green pigment, one of which supports the image of Saint Jerome in multi-coloured enamelled terracotta. This chancel was ordered by Queen Catherine of Austria as the final resting place for the royal family. It is the work of Jerónimo de Ruão (Jean de Rouen) in the Classical style. The royal tombs rest on marble elephants and are set between Ionic pillars, topped by Corinthian pillars. The tombs on the left side of the choir belong to king Manuel I and his wife Maria of Aragon, while the tombs on the right side belong to King João III and his wife Queen Catherine of Austria. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/confesiones.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/confesiones.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6714378765" latitude="38.697802" license="3" longitude="-9.205684" nbComments="16" rank="27" tags="tamron 18200 monasterio monastery jerónimos bw bn mujeres women dynamiccontrast brighten confesionarios confessionals iglesia church robado stolen caminando walking geo:lat=3869780292 geo:lon=920568466 geotagged lisboa portugal anawesomeshot" title="Confesiones" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7022/6714378765_e03994aba5_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="265" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 13:12:40" description="&lt;b&gt;They are coming&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. El claustro se encuentra situado junto a la nave norte del templo. Fue diseñado por Juan de Castillo. Fue realizado entre 1517 y 1519 con varias contratas y subcontratas dando lugar a un resultado final de armonía y uniformidad. Todo el claustro está ampliamente decorado con motivos manuelinos (letra M, esfera armilar, cabos marineros, temas religiosos, hornacinas, medallones, etc.). Desde el piso de arriba se puede acceder al coro alto de la iglesia, que fue construido por Torralva en el siglo XVI. En él se halla una importante sillería también del XVI. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Work on the vast square cloister (55 x 55 m) of the monastery was begun by Boitac. He built the groin vaults with wide arches and windows with tracery resting on delicate mullions. Juan de Castilho finished the construction by giving the lower storey a classical overlay and building a more recessed upper-storey. The construction of such a cloister was a novelty at the time. Castilho changed the original round columns of Boitac into rectangular ones, and embellished it with Plateresque-style ornamentation. Each wing consists of six bays with tracery vaults. The four inner bays rest on massive buttresses, forming broad arcades. The corner bays are linked by a diagonal arched construction and show the richly decorated corner pillars. The cloister had a religious function as well as a representative function by its decorative ornamentation and the dynastic symbolic motives, such as the armillarium, coat-of-arms, and the cross from the Order of Christ, showing the growing world power of Portugal. The inside walls of the cloister have a wealth of Manueline motives with nautical elements, in addition to European, Moorish and Eastern motifs. The round arches and the horizontal structure are clearly in line with the Renaissance style, while at the same time there is also a relationship with Spanish architecture. The decorations on the outer walls of the inner courtyard were made in Plateresco style by Castilho: the arcades include traceried arches that give the construction a filigree aspect. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2012/01/ya-vienen.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2012/01/ya-vienen.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6627949855" latitude="38.697841" license="3" longitude="-9.205662" nbComments="5" rank="28" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos claustro cloister bw bn highcontrast noiseiso3200 escaleras stairs personas people pasadizo passage geo:lat=3869784060 geo:lon=920566052 geotagged prt" title="Ya vienen" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7018/6627949855_47cc371ea9_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="211" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-12-07 12:50:21" description="&lt;b&gt;Cloistered&lt;/b&gt; - Bairro de Belém - Lisboa (Portugal). &lt;b&gt;CASTELLANO&lt;/b&gt; El Monasterio de los Jerónimos de Santa María de Belém, se ubica en el barrio de Belém, Lisboa. Diseñado en estilo manuelino por el arquitecto Juan de Castillo, fue encargado por el rey Manuel I de Portugal para conmemorar el afortunado regreso de la India de Vasco de Gama, se fundó en 1501 en la antigua ermita fundada por el Infante D. Enrique. La primera etapa constructiva de la iglesia nueva comienza en 1514 y fue ampliándose y modificándose hasta el siglo XX. Se financió gracias al 5% de los impuestos obtenidos de las especias orientales, a excepción de los de la pimienta, la canela y el clavo, cuyas rentas iban directamente a la Corona. Este monasterio fue levantado sobre el enclave de la Ermida do Restelo en lo que fue la playa de Restelo, ermita fundada por Enrique el Navegante, y en la cual, Vasco de Gama y sus hombres pasaron la noche en oración antes de partir hacia la India. El estilo manuelino se caracteriza por la mezcla de motivos arquitectónicos y decorativos del gótico tardío y del renacimiento. Destacan los portales principal y lateral, el interior de la iglesia y el magnífico claustro. Las capillas de la iglesia fueron remodeladas en puro estilo renacentista en la segunda mitad del siglo XVI y contienen las arcas funerarias de Manuel I y su familia, además de otros reyes de Portugal. En los Jerónimos se hallan también las tumbas (neomanuelinas) del navegador Vasco da Gama y el poeta Luís de Camões. En una capilla del claustro descansan, desde 1985, los restos del escritor Fernando Pessoa. En un anexo construido en 1850 se ubica el Museo Nacional de Arqueología, el Museu da Marinha se encuentra en el ala oeste. En diciembre de 2007 se firmo en este monasterio el Tratado de Lisboa, un acuerdo de la Unión Europea que sustiyute la Constitución Europea y reforma los tratados que estaban vigentes. Este monasterio, al igual que la cercana Torre de Belém y el Monumento a los Descubrimientos simboliza la Era de las exploraciones portuguesa y se cuenta entre las principales atracciones turísticas de Lisboa. La primera etapa constructiva se encargó al arquitecto de origen francés, el maestro Diogo Boytac (o Boitaca), autor de la primitiva iglesia de Jesús de Setúbal. Su proyecto no fue llevado a cabo pues fue sustituido por el proyecto del siguiente arquitecto, Juan de Castillo. Boytac trabajó en el edificio en los años de 1514 y 1516. Planificó la obra siguiendo las normas imperantes del momento por toda Europa del gótico final. De esta etapa poco queda hoy. En 1516 le sucedió en las obras Juan de Castillo (en Portugal era conocido como João de Castilho). Juan de Castillo era de origen español según acredita un documento en que sus parientes dicen Juan de Castillo era natural de la Merindad de Trasmiera del reino de Castilla… concretamente de Castillo, pequeña localidad de la comarca de Trasmiera en Cantabria. Se sabe que trabajó en España hasta 1505. Con Castillo la obra comienza en su mayor diménsión y se corresponde con las mejores partes del edificio en estilo manuelino conjugándolo con el plateresco y estructuras renacentistas. Bajo su dirección se construyó la iglesia con las más osadas bóvedas, el claustro, la sacristía, la sala capitular y el refectorio. A la muerte del rey Manuel (1521) las obras no se paralizaron y continuarón en tiempos del rey Juan III, hasta que más tarde continuaron con el arquitecto español Diego de Torralva en 1544. La fecha aparece grabada en la piedra. La diferencia de estilo de este arquitecto con respecto al los anteriores se muestra sobre todo en el gran friso alto realizado por Diego de la Zarza y en la introducción de los medallones vueltos de lado. El monasterio fue confiado a los jerónimos, que estuvieron en él hasta 1833 en que fueron expulsados por la autoridad civil. El claustro se encuentra situado junto a la nave norte del templo. Fue diseñado por Juan de Castillo. Fue realizado entre 1517 y 1519 con varias contratas y subcontratas dando lugar a un resultado final de armonía y uniformidad. Todo el claustro está ampliamente decorado con motivos manuelinos (letra M, esfera armilar, cabos marineros, temas religiosos, hornacinas, medallones, etc.). Desde el piso de arriba se puede acceder al coro alto de la iglesia, que fue construido por Torralva en el siglo XVI. En él se halla una importante sillería también del XVI. Más info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%c3%b3nimos_de_Bel%c3%a9m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monasterio_de_los_Jer%C3%B3nimos_de...&lt;/a&gt; --------------------------- &lt;b&gt;ENGLISH&lt;/b&gt; The Hieronymites Monastery (&lt;i&gt;Mosteiro dos Jerónimos&lt;/i&gt;) is located near the shore of the parish of Belém, in the municipality of Lisbon, Portugal. The monastery is one of the most prominent monuments of the Manueline-style architecture (Portuguese late-Gothic) in Lisbon, classified in 1983 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, along with the nearby Tower of Belém. The construction of the monastery and church began on 6 January 1501 (and were completed 100 years later). King Manuel originally funded the project with money obtained from the Vintena da Pimenta, a 5% tax on commerce from Africa and the Orient, equivalent to 70 kilograms (150 lb) of gold per year, with the exception of pepper, cinnamon and cloves (which went directly to the Crown. With the influx of riches, the architects were not limited to small plans, and resources already perscribed for the Monastery of Batalha (including the Aviz pantheon) were redirected to the project in Belém. Manuel I selected the religious order of Hieronymite monks to occupy the monastery, whose role it was to pray for the King's eternal soul and to provide spiritual assistance to navigators and sailors who departed from the beach of Restelo to discover the world.[2][1] This the monks did until 1833 (over four centuries), when the religious orders were dissolved and the monastery was unoccupied. The monastery was designed in a style that later became known as Manueline: a richly ornate architectural design that includes complex sculptural themes incorporating maritime elements and objects discovered during naval expeditions, carved in limestone. Diogo de Boitaca,[1] the architect, pioneered this style in the Monastery of Jesus in Setúbal. On this project Boitaca was responsible for the plans and contracting work on the monastery, the sacristy, and the refectory. He used calcário de lioz, a local gold-coloured limestone, that was quarried from Ajuda, the valley of Alcántara, Laveiras, Rio Seco and Tercena, for its construction. Boitaca was succeeded by the Spaniard Juan de Castilho, who took charge of construction around 1517. Castilho gradually moved from the Manueline to the Spanish Plateresque style, an ornamentation that included lavish decorations that recall silverware (Spanish: plata). The construction came to a halt when the King Manuel I died in 1521. There were several sculptors who made their mark on this building. Nicolau Chanterene added depth with hisRenaissance themes. The architect Diogo de Torralva resumed the construction of the monastery in 1550, adding the main chapel, the choir, and completing the two stories of the monastery, using only Renaissance motifs. Diogo de Torralva's work was continued in 1571 by Jérôme de Rouen (also called Jerónimo de Ruão) who added some Classical elements. The construction stopped in 1580 with the union of Spain and Portugal, because the building of the Escorial in Spain was now draining away all the funds. Work on the vast square cloister (55 x 55 m) of the monastery was begun by Boitac. He built the groin vaults with wide arches and windows with tracery resting on delicate mullions. Juan de Castilho finished the construction by giving the lower storey a classical overlay and building a more recessed upper-storey. The construction of such a cloister was a novelty at the time. Castilho changed the original round columns of Boitac into rectangular ones, and embellished it with Plateresque-style ornamentation. Each wing consists of six bays with tracery vaults. The four inner bays rest on massive buttresses, forming broad arcades. The corner bays are linked by a diagonal arched construction and show the richly decorated corner pillars. The cloister had a religious function as well as a representative function by its decorative ornamentation and the dynastic symbolic motives, such as the armillarium, coat-of-arms, and the cross from the Order of Christ, showing the growing world power of Portugal. The inside walls of the cloister have a wealth of Manueline motives with nautical elements, in addition to European, Moorish and Eastern motifs. The round arches and the horizontal structure are clearly in line with the Renaissance style, while at the same time there is also a relationship with Spanish architecture. The decorations on the outer walls of the inner courtyard were made in Plateresco style by Castilho: the arcades include traceried arches that give the construction a filigree aspect. More info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%c3%b3nimos_Monastery&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jer%C3%B3nimos_Monastery&lt;/a&gt; --- La reflexión: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.santimb.com/2011/12/enclaustrada.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.santimb.com/2011/12/enclaustrada.html&lt;/a&gt;" id="6571246589" latitude="38.698161" license="3" longitude="-9.205798" nbComments="10" rank="29" tags="belém lisboa portugal monasterio monastery jerónimos claustro cloister robado stolen adaptativecontrast eppnccbs mujer woman xprocess geo:lat=3869816088 geo:lon=920579731 geotagged" title="Enclaustrada" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7032/6571246589_0760e1a796_b.jpg" username=". SantiMB ." views="265" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-10 15:22:54" description="Part of the defensive battery. Tower of Belém" id="4344336372" latitude="38.69161" license="3" longitude="-9.21599" nbComments="0" rank="30" tags="belem cannon lisboa lisbon portugal portugal2009 tower weapon window pedrouços" title="Cannon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4072/4344336372_a0b0d765eb_b.jpg" username="mbac" views="12" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-02-16 03:44:29" description="upper floor at Torre de Belém -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com?q=38.691539366352586,-9.215984344482421(Top of the Tower)&amp;amp;t=h&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="43333336" latitude="38.691539" license="5" longitude="-9.215984" nbComments="0" rank="31" tags="lisbon lisboa portugal belem hunda geo:lat=38691539 geo:lon=9215984 geotagged" title="Top of the Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/25/43333336_4fefd3c69c_b.jpg" username="Hunda" views="108" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-01-10 06:54:47" description="Took on the same day of Torres de Belem and Padrão dos Descobrimentos series... Straighten, Croping, Brightness &amp;amp; Contrast and Border &lt;a href=&quot;http://wHaTeVeR-.deviantart.com/art/Torre-de-Belem-28353580&quot;&gt;wHaTeVeR-.deviantart.com/art/Torre-de-Belem-28353580&lt;/a&gt;" id="2182503399" latitude="38.691539" license="1" longitude="-9.215925" nbComments="1" rank="32" tags="deviantart dafeature tosite torredebelém belém lisbon portugal monument tower belemtower lisboa sonycybershotw5 europe" title="Torre de Belem" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2400/2182503399_cb71db7d4f_b.jpg" username="wHaTEvEr-" views="141" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-20 09:36:31" description="The Tower of Belém is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/pg.cfm?cid=31&amp;amp;id_site=263&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/a&gt;." id="97028026" latitude="38.691673" license="3" longitude="-9.215931" nbComments="0" rank="33" tags="europe portugal lisbon lisboa belem tower torre gothic belém tagus river unescoworldheritagesite manueline geo:lat=38691673 geo:lon=9215931 towerofbelém tagusriver water worldheritagesite dopplr:explore=uvf1" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/39/97028026_0675240d75_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="297" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-20 09:35:34" description="The Tower of Belém is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/pg.cfm?cid=31&amp;amp;id_site=263&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/a&gt;." id="97020234" latitude="38.691673" license="3" longitude="-9.215931" nbComments="1" rank="34" tags="europe portugal lisbon lisboa belem tower torre gothic belém tagus river unescoworldheritagesite manueline geo:lat=38691673 geo:lon=9215931 towerofbelém tagusriver water worldheritagesite dopplr:explore=uvf1" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/33/97020234_04b2df19e2_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="276" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-04-01 15:23:30" description="The Tower of Belém The tower was opened in 1521 and put under the protection of Lisbon's saint, São Vicente. Along with the fort São Sebastião, Torre de Belém was part of a group of forts built to protect the river. After the sea receded, the Tower no longer stands in the water." id="2388200448" latitude="38.69161" license="3" longitude="-9.215887" nbComments="13" rank="35" tags="santa maria de belem portugal lisbon tower" title="Torre de Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2104/2388200448_db8f56250c_b.jpg" username="Charalampos Konstantinidis" views="310" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-22 15:23:22" description="Originally, the Tower was in the middle of the river and was the last thing that sailors would see as they left and the first thing they would see when they return." id="2313694699" latitude="38.691476" license="1" longitude="-9.215989" nbComments="0" rank="36" tags="portugal" title="From within the Belem Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2043/2313694699_5ef032b223_b.jpg" username="wfbakker2" views="3" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-22 15:35:06" description="" id="2314514110" latitude="38.691476" license="1" longitude="-9.215989" nbComments="0" rank="37" tags="portugal belem" title="View of Belem, from Belem Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2339/2314514110_52f87a6734_b.jpg" username="wfbakker2" views="7" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-20 09:41:54" description="The Tower of Belém is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/pg.cfm?cid=31&amp;amp;id_site=263&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/a&gt;." id="97149923" latitude="38.691481" license="3" longitude="-9.215947" nbComments="0" rank="38" tags="europe portugal lisbon lisboa belem tower torre gothic belém tagus river unescoworldheritagesite manueline geo:lat=38691481 geo:lon=9215947 towerofbelém worldheritagesite dopplr:explore=uvf1" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/27/97149923_f5b69c024f_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="214" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-04-29 17:43:25" description="Tower of Belem, Lisbon (Portugal)." id="2990578610" latitude="38.691501" license="2" longitude="-9.215898" nbComments="0" rank="39" tags="lisbon portugal belem" title="Out the window" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3213/2990578610_d4701b10fa_b.jpg" username="Héctor de Pereda" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-02-16 03:40:42" description="surviving tower (other was located in center of today's Tagus river channel) that was 15th century sailors last view of city as the set out to corss the Atlantic -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com?q=38.69147237351829,-9.215898513793945(Torre de Belém)&amp;amp;t=h&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="43323731" latitude="38.691472" license="5" longitude="-9.215899" nbComments="0" rank="40" tags="lisbon lisboa portugal belem torredebelem hunda geo:lat=38691472 geo:lon=9215899 geotagged" title="Torre de Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/29/43323731_4e6f2a4ddf_b.jpg" username="Hunda" views="138" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-02-07 11:38:15" description="On top of the tower of Belém" id="563867326" latitude="38.691489" license="3" longitude="-9.215823" nbComments="6" rank="41" tags="battlement belém bridge brug fille girl kantelen lisbõa lisbon lisbonne lissabon meisje pont portugal taag tague tagus tejo torredebelém" title="Watching" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/1420/563867326_254cdc0cb3_b.jpg" username="Amaury Henderick" views="152" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-23 19:38:03" description="The Torre de Belém (Tower of Bethlehem) is one of Lisbon's most charismatic landmarks and one of its symbols. Located by the river shore, this former fortress of the early XVI th century, later to be prison and light house, saw it's construction initiated in 1514 and accomplished six years latter, under a different ruler. It was classified by UNESCO as World Heritage in 1983 and as one of Portugal's 7 wonders in 2007. This photo was taken on an urban expedition with fellow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/castilho15/&quot;&gt;Fotógrafos da Castilho&lt;/a&gt; group members. &lt;b&gt;Tech specs&lt;/b&gt;, for the technical minded... 10mm 2&amp;quot; f/4 -2EV ISO:100 Sigma 10-20mm F4-5.6 EX DC HSM Camera: Canon EOS 400D Geotagged with Gisteq PhotoTracker" id="3391183282" latitude="38.691777" license="3" longitude="-9.216084" nbComments="1" rank="42" tags="pedrotavaressilva fotografosdacastilho canon 400d canon400d castilho17h9" title="Torre de Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3574/3391183282_11ac6a4a45_b.jpg" username="Pedro Tavares Silva" views="303" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-06-06 14:06:05" description="" id="2700035933" latitude="38.69184" license="1" longitude="-9.215887" nbComments="0" rank="43" tags="nikond70s70300 lisbon santamariadebelém sculpture stone torredebelém belémtower tower fortress castle angel wall" title="The face of sorrow" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3287/2700035933_691c4a5b71_b.jpg" username="JF Sebastian" views="16" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-03-23 19:39:15" description="The Torre de Belém (Tower of Bethlehem) is one of Lisbon's most charismatic landmarks and one of its symbols. Located by the river shore, this former fortress of the early XVI th century, later to be prison and light house, saw it's construction initiated in 1514 and accomplished six years latter, under a different ruler. It was classified by UNESCO as World Heritage in 1983 and as one of Portugal's 7 wonders in 2007. This photo was taken on an urban expedition with fellow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/castilho15/&quot;&gt;Fotógrafos da Castilho&lt;/a&gt; group members. Tech specs, for the technical minded... 10mm 3.2&amp;quot; f/4 -2EV ISO:100 Lens: Sigma 28-300mm F3.5-6.3 DG Macro Camera: Canon EOS 400D Geotagged with Gisteq PhotoTracker" id="3390371281" latitude="38.691722" license="3" longitude="-9.216362" nbComments="0" rank="44" tags="pedrotavaressilva fotografosdacastilho canon 400d canon400d castilho17h9" title="Torre de Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3606/3390371281_8c6494e2c0_b.jpg" username="Pedro Tavares Silva" views="273" />
<photo  date_taken="2006-01-20 09:14:58" description="Built 1515-1521, the tower was originally further out in the river (before landfill brought it close to shore). It was constructed where an artillery ship had previously been moored for defensive purposes. The tower is built in the Manueline style, combining Gothic architecture with elements of Spanish, Italian, and Flemish renaissance work and Moorish influences. The work also incldues many maritime themes in the form of carvings of barnacles, seaweed, algae, anchors, and navigation tools, echoing Portugal's concurrent period of discovery. The Tower of Belém is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://whc.unesco.org/pg.cfm?cid=31&amp;amp;id_site=263&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage Site&lt;/a&gt;." id="96992514" latitude="38.692126" license="3" longitude="-9.216253" nbComments="10" rank="45" tags="europe portugal lisbon lisboa belem tower torre gothic tagus unescoworldheritagesite river beautiful i500 explore7feb06 manueline interestingness2 architecture fort belém geo:lat=38692126 geo:lon=9216253 towerofbelém tagusriver worldheritagesite dopplr:explore=uvf1" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/32/96992514_3f67bed329_b.jpg" username="Sean Munson" views="1544" />
<photo  date_taken="2012-07-03 12:13:03" description="Belém, whose name is derived from the Portuguese word for Bethlehem, is a civil parish of the municipality of Lisbon, in central Portugal. At the mouth of the Tagus River it is located six kilometres west of the city centre." id="7555592664" latitude="38.692019" license="3" longitude="-9.215434" nbComments="9" rank="46" tags="hdr sony sigma lisboa lisbon lissabon portugal belém belem tower photomatix colorefex lucisart" title="Lissabon, Belém Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/7248/7555592664_7152a32ae8_b.jpg" username="HDR-newaddict" views="321" />
<photo  date_taken="2009-09-10 15:15:24" description="Detail of a sentry post. In the background, the cereal docks of Tafaria." id="4343598435" latitude="38.69179" license="3" longitude="-9.21528" nbComments="0" rank="47" tags="belem hdr lisboa lisbon portugal portugal2009 tower pedrouços" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4041/4343598435_e4e80d3088_b.jpg" username="mbac" views="39" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-22 15:04:51" description="A representation of a tower and its representation, as observed by Anita. Is there a semiotician in the house?" id="2313681301" latitude="38.691941" license="1" longitude="-9.215227" nbComments="0" rank="48" tags="portugal belem tower" title="Belem Tower and Its Representation" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3006/2313681301_26079363e2_b.jpg" username="wfbakker2" views="5" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-24 18:10:29" description="" id="4585323690" latitude="38.691966" license="1" longitude="-9.215233" nbComments="0" rank="49" tags="belem ilustrarportugal lisboa monument monumento portugal postcards" title="The 2 Towers of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4010/4585323690_2e7ef6d9fa_b.jpg" username="Hugo M Pereira" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-24 18:09:44" description="" id="4584696931" latitude="38.691966" license="1" longitude="-9.215233" nbComments="3" rank="50" tags="portugal postcards ilustrarportugal lisboa belem monumento monument bw blackwhite pretobranco" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/4042/4584696931_5ce0cf7aa4_b.jpg" username="Hugo M Pereira" views="17" />
<photo  date_taken="2010-04-24 18:09:12" description="" id="4585322230" latitude="38.691966" license="1" longitude="-9.215233" nbComments="1" rank="51" tags="belem ilustrarportugal lisboa monument monumento portugal postcards" title="Tower of Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3318/4585322230_d2593bd57d_b.jpg" username="Hugo M Pereira" views="10" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-05-26 00:37:44" description="The Torre (Tower) de Belém was started construction in 1515 in honor of recent ocean voyages. It later became a monument to the power of the Portuguese empire during the &amp;quot;Age of Great Discoveries&amp;quot;. This was built in a Gothic style with some Moor influence." id="2088810154" latitude="38.691882" license="2" longitude="-9.214997" nbComments="0" rank="52" tags="europe portugal lisbon torredebelém belémtower tower belém belem tagusriver tagus tejo megan" title="Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2391/2088810154_f870acbb37_b.jpg" username="Travis S." views="33" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-02-16 03:47:06" description="view of the Monumento Padräo dos Descobrimentos (monument to the history of discoveries) from the top of the Tower of Belém, on the north shore of the Rio Tejo -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com?q=38.691539366352586,-9.214954376220703(Lisbon waterfront at Belém)&amp;amp;t=h&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="43323732" latitude="38.691539" license="5" longitude="-9.214954" nbComments="0" rank="53" tags="lisbon lisboa portugal belem riotejo tagus hunda geo:lat=38691539 geo:lon=9214954 geotagged" title="Lisbon waterfront at Belém" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/29/43323732_29d6dab762_b.jpg" username="Hunda" views="791" />
<photo  date_taken="2005-08-06 17:55:40" description="The plane is a replica of the first to cross the Atlantic from Portugal to Brazil." id="2713845348" latitude="38.692226" license="4" longitude="-9.213795" nbComments="0" rank="54" tags="lisbon portugal belem plane biplane belemtower" title="Belem Tower and aeroplane" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3071/2713845348_fcf4e3639d_b.jpg" username="Matt From London" views="132" />
<photo  date_taken="2011-05-22 05:31:42" description="A bit before the sunrise, with Padrão dos Descobrimentos and 25 de Abril bridge over Tejo. (yes, after seeing Pedro Pinheiro's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pedromourapinheiro/5789156919&quot;&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt;, my other one sucked… so I went back to my library and found this brighter one, but has that tower in front of Padrão… but still, has much better colors) Thanks Pedro for planning this great LXPW's!" id="5789232803" latitude="38.69233" license="1" longitude="-9.212154" nbComments="0" rank="55" tags="201105belémbaixa belém lisboa lxpw nascerdosol padrãodosdescobrimentos photowalk portugal sunrise" title="First Colors" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/3618/5789232803_d4e474b391_b.jpg" username="wHaTEvEr-" views="78" />
<photo  date_taken="2008-02-22 14:29:51" description="We got our first view of our next stop, Belem Tower, while we were at the top of the monument." id="2313654755" latitude="38.692615" license="1" longitude="-9.210904" nbComments="0" rank="56" tags="portugal" title="Belem Tower" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/2241/2313654755_b9cfc7f630_b.jpg" username="wfbakker2" views="9" />
<photo  date_taken="2003-02-16 03:39:00" description="Monument to first Portugal-Brazil transatlantic flight, with Tower of Belém in background -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com?q=38.69361611309868,-9.206328392028808(Heavy Biplane)&amp;amp;t=h&quot;&gt;See where this picture was taken.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/groups/geotagging/discuss/72157594165549916/&quot;&gt;[?]&lt;/a&gt;" id="43323730" latitude="38.693616" license="5" longitude="-9.206328" nbComments="0" rank="57" tags="lisbon lisboa portugal belem hunda geo:lat=38693616 geo:lon=9206328 geotagged" title="Heavy Biplane" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/32/43323730_0da32cf9dd_b.jpg" username="Hunda" views="183" />
<photo  date_taken="2007-06-11 10:51:06" description="Statue in Belem looking towards Statue of Christ and suspension bridge" id="8050536724" latitude="38.69344" license="1" longitude="-9.205802" nbComments="0" rank="58" tags="lisbon belem tagus monumenttothediscoveries statueofchrist bridge tower" title="Monument to the Discoveries in Belem, Lisbon" url_b="http://static.flickr.com/8029/8050536724_22f2054c15_b.jpg" username="A M H 2012" views="9" />
</photos>
